<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Juha-Matti Santala - Community Builder. Dreamer. Adventurer.</title>
  <subtitle></subtitle>
  <link href="" rel="self" />
  <link href="https://hamatti.org" />
  <updated>2026-01-28T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <id></id>
  <author>
    <name>Juha-Matti Santala</name>
    <email>juhamattisantala@gmail.com</email>
  </author> 
  <entry>
    <title>Taskmaster UK Series 7 is peak entertainment</title>
    <link href="https://hamatti.org/posts/taskmaster-uk-series-7-is-peak-entertainment/" />
    <updated>2026-01-28T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://hamatti.org/posts/taskmaster-uk-series-7-is-peak-entertainment/</id>
    <content type="html">
      &lt;p&gt;
  For years, I’ve been working on an ultimate
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.taskmaster.tv/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Taskmaster&lt;/a&gt;
  Tier List. But they keep making more of them all around the world and I
  haven’t quite gotten to the finish line of writing about all of them yet. I
  think I’ve seen them all — not just the UK ones but all 13 different countries
  and a bunch of really well done fan editions as well. Hundreds of hours of
  peak fun.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  If you’re not familiar with the show, Taskmaster is a masterpiece TV comedy
  game show that originated from the UK and has spread around the globe in
  various qualities. In the show, 5 comedians, actors or generally public
  figures complete tasks set to them by the Taskmaster and get judged by their
  performance.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;notion-heading_2 notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
  I shouldn’t find Taskmaster so fun
&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Before I talk about why I love series 7 so freaking much, I need to talk about
  why I’m baffled by this format. On paper, it’s antithetical to what I find
  interesting. I’m a stickler to the rules and I hate any type of games or
  competitions that participants don’t take seriously or where the rules and
  scoring is not transparent and consistent.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Taskmaster is none of that. It’s completely arbitrary in scoring and pretty
  much every task has some kind of a carefully designed loophole solution and
  part of the fun of the show is trying to figure out how you would have
  completed them and seeing if any of the contestants find those loopholes.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Despite all of this being something I generally find uninteresting, this show
  has kept me audibly laughing for over a decade — even on multiple rewatches.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Alex Horne, the Taskmaster’s assistant and the mastermind behind the tasks for
  UK (and some other shows) is simply amazing. Greg Davies, the UK Taskmaster is
  so funny and has great chemistry with most of the guests throughout its
  already 20 seasons and many specials.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;notion-heading_2 notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
  Series 7 of the UK show is the best
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://hamatti.org/assets/img/posts/taskmaster-uk-series-7-is-peak-entertainment/1.png.webp&quot; alt=&quot; &quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  While I’ve been rewatching different series and writing my tier list, I keep
  bouncing between a couple of different series to nominate the best. New
  Zealand has 6 stellar seasons and gun to my head, I’m not sure I can decide
  whether I enjoy their second season or UK’s 7th the most.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Today, I’m calling UK Series 7 the best because I just rewatched it for the
  umpteenth time and want to talk about it.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cast of the 7th series is&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;notion-bulleted_list&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;notion-bulleted_list_item notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jamesacaster.com/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;James Acaster&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li class=&quot;notion-bulleted_list_item notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jessknappett.com/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Jessica Knappett&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li class=&quot;notion-bulleted_list_item notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://kerrygodliman.com/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Kerry Godliman&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li class=&quot;notion-bulleted_list_item notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.philwang.co.uk/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Phil Wang&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li class=&quot;notion-bulleted_list_item notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://rhodgilbertcomedian.com/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Rhod Gilbert&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  All five of them are funny as heck and as is so important in this show, their
  chemistry with each other is brilliant. It’s only rivaled by the wonderful
  five of the aforementioned NZ season 2’s cast.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  James, Jessica, Kerry and Phil are the wild young kids and Rhod is the weird
  uncle and Greg is the disappointed dad. It’s even more funny because Rhod and
  Greg are real-life friends which comes up all the time as Rhod is sparing no
  shots as he heckles Greg throughout the series.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Each of the 10 episodes is pure fire. There are not a lot of comedy TV shows
  that I actually laugh at out loud when watching but with this series, I’m
  constantly laughing.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Episode 7 is also home to the best individual moment in all hundreds of
  episodes across all Taskmaster shows. It’s so monumental that the stage where
  final task of each episode takes place is called The Knappett these days and
  why I always come back to this series when I need a good feel moment. I won’t
  spoil it for you.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  The outcome of a Taskmaster series is a result of multiple factors: the cast
  and their chemistry, the tasks, the team compositions (they have team tasks
  throughout the series and split teams to two and three people) and of course,
  how the contestants perform (+ the amazing editing that goes into the show).
  Sometimes even a strong group in paper can fall flat and sometimes another
  group surprises.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  This one gets all of it so right. There’s a ton of interaction between the
  participants in the studio sections which really ties it together. You can see
  that they truly enjoyed being there together.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  If you’re new to the show or haven’t seen the 7th yet, find it and take a
  look!
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    </content>
  </entry> 
  <entry>
    <title>I made a board game zine</title>
    <link href="https://hamatti.org/posts/i-made-a-board-game-zine/" />
    <updated>2026-01-21T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://hamatti.org/posts/i-made-a-board-game-zine/</id>
    <content type="html">
      &lt;p&gt;
  Say hello to
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://zine.hamatti.org/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Roll the Zine&lt;/a&gt;, a board and card game focused 8-page zine.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I really like the idea of
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Zine&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;zines&lt;/a&gt;
  and for a few years, I’ve been reading other people’s zines and spent time
  reading zine forums, dreaming of making one myself. I’ve always felt zines are
  beyond my skills as I can’t draw or illustrate or write poems or anything like
  that.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  After a couple of sleepless nights sick in my bed to start off 2026, I decided
  it’s time to make one to get something going. I have some ideas for zines that
  have been living rent free in my head but decided to start practicing the art
  of making them with something with smaller stakes.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Hence, Roll the Zine. It’s an 8-page zine with words about games I enjoy. In
  the first issue, I wrote about Wingspan, Print and Play games, Dandân,
  Tinderblox and Hive. I wanted to challenge myself and my need to write
  comprehensive and structured things. Some of the text is slightly tilted,
  paragraphs don’t align perfectly and some pages have less text and bigger
  pictures. I was definitely way outside my comfort zone with some of the layout
  decisions.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I’m so used to publishing in the web (this blog and
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://notes.hamatti.org/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;my digital garden&lt;/a&gt;) where I can link to other things that I found it difficult to adjust to a
  print medium. I’m publishing the zine as a PDF as well but I wanted it to be
  first and foremost a printed paper zine and to operate within that constraint.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s an example page about Wingspan:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://hamatti.org/assets/img/posts/i-made-a-board-game-zine/1.png.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Zine page about Wingspan board game with five paragraphs of text and a black-and-write illustration of a bird sitting on top of a post. &quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m quite happy about how it turned out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  With this zine, the process was definitely the most important bit: I learned a
  lot about technical stuff (like how to lay out pages so they print correctly)
  and about the constraints of page space (as in the web there’s always a lot of
  space and ability to link to more stuff).
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  If you’re into board games or zines, give it a look! I’d love to hear your
  opinions about it.
&lt;/p&gt;

    </content>
  </entry> 
  <entry>
    <title>Gaming for busy people</title>
    <link href="https://hamatti.org/posts/gaming-for-busy-people/" />
    <updated>2026-01-14T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://hamatti.org/posts/gaming-for-busy-people/</id>
    <content type="html">
      &lt;p&gt;
  I enjoy playing games, both video games and board games a lot. One of my many
  joys in life is to spend an entire day either diving deep into a long story of
  a video game or get together with friends to move tokens around boards on a
  table while having a great time.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  As an adult in modern life, these full gaming days are few and far between so
  my gaming has shifted a lot lately to play more games that can be enjoyed in
  shorter sessions while still enjoying them equal amounts.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  A big shift for me started with
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nintendo_Switch&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Nintendo Switch&lt;/a&gt;
  and later continued with
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Steam_Deck&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Steam Deck&lt;/a&gt;
  as both of them are mobile and crucially, they both provided a sleep mode
  where you could suspend the device mid-game without having to save and exit.
  That combination meant I can pick up a device, immediately jump into the game,
  play a 10 minute session during a break and then put it back to sleep and
  continue my day.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  For both devices, I have a dock in my living room connected to my projector
  and full AV setup but I also have secondary docks at my desk connected to my
  display and in the case of Steam Deck, my keyboard and mouse.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Once I started getting into this mindset, I ended up buying and playing more
  games that didn&#39;t require me to remember where I was the last time I left off.
  Heavier story-based or base-building games also take a while to immerse myself
  into the world so they are not great for short sessions.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Natural genre for this kind of gaming is
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Roguelike&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;roguelikes&lt;/a&gt;
  and
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Roguelike#Rogue-lites_and_procedural_death_labyrinths&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;roguelites&lt;/a&gt;. You start each run from scratch and in many games the individual runs are
  short, anywhere from a few minutes to an hour. Other great genre that is
  perfect for short sessions is sports games where individual games usually last
  less than half an hour.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;notion-heading_2 notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
  Short-session game recommendations
&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I recently returned to
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://notes.hamatti.org/gaming/video-games/reviews/lonely-mountains&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Lonely Mountains&lt;/a&gt;
  to do mountain biking and downhill skiing. Each run is only a couple of
  minutes long so it&#39;s really easy to adjust based on how much time you have to
  play. In Lonely Mountains: Downhill, you&#39;re descending mountain trails with
  your bike, finding new routes, enjoying nature and trying to beat your
  previous personal bests. In the sequel Lonely Mountains: Snow Riders you
  switch the bike to skiis and enjoy the snowy mountains.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Slay_the_Spire&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Slay the Spire&lt;/a&gt;
  is a deckbuilding roguelike where your goal is to use your cards to beat
  monsters in three, increasingly difficult act and gather new cards and relics
  to improve your deck. A single, completed run lasts around an hour but most of
  the runs don&#39;t finish successfully so in reality a single run is way less than
  that.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Into_the_Breach&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Into the Breach&lt;/a&gt;
  is a turn-based strategy game where you are controlling mechs in an 8 by 8
  grid, trying to defend the world from alien attacks. You control three to five
  war machines and alternate taking turns with the opponent. Each run has five
  different areas, each split to smaller sections for individual fights with
  individual goals. After each area, you get to improve your mechs based on how
  well you performed.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  The 2025 hit game
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Blue_Prince&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Blue Prince&lt;/a&gt;
  operates on day cycle where the mansion resets each night. Every time you walk
  through an unopened door, you get to draft a new room from a small selection
  of randomly selected rooms and your goal is to figure out the mysteries the
  mansion hides.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://pokerogue.net/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;PokéRogue&lt;/a&gt; is a
  fan-game set in the Pokémon universe that focuses solely on battling. Each
  run, you select a starting party and go through a battle after battle against
  wild Pokémon and fellow trainers. You catch new Pokémon, level up and evolve
  your party members and purchase items from the shop to keep your party going.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shogun_Showdown&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Shogun Showdown&lt;/a&gt;
  is a turn-based, puzzle-esque roguelike fighting game. You are a samurai
  equipped with a few starting weapons and you battle opponents in small, tight
  2D-space moving left and right and queueing attacks you unleash to your
  opponents. It&#39;s a really neat game: the mechanics are simple but have enough
  depth to be interesting. Compared to many other games on the list, there&#39;s
  less variation between individual runs, especially in the early sections but
  it&#39;s still a fun game that I haven&#39;t ran out of replay value yet.
&lt;/p&gt;

    </content>
  </entry> 
  <entry>
    <title>I added BookLore to my homelab</title>
    <link href="https://hamatti.org/posts/i-added-booklore-to-my-homelab/" />
    <updated>2026-01-07T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://hamatti.org/posts/i-added-booklore-to-my-homelab/</id>
    <content type="html">
      &lt;p&gt;Happy 2026!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  First of my holiday projects was to set up
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/booklore-app/booklore&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;BookLore&lt;/a&gt;
  to my homelab to manage my e-books. It’s a pretty nice full system that allows
  you to manage your collection but also provides an interface to read the books
  and an OPDS server that can be used for example with KOReader to sync your
  reading progress across different systems.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I don’t yet use KOReader on any of my devices and I don’t intend to read my
  books in browser so at this point, it’s mainly to gather all my e-books from
  various sources like my NAS, iPad, Kindle and laptops to a single location.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://hamatti.org/assets/img/posts/i-added-booklore-to-my-homelab/1.png.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot of Booklore web app with 12 Martha Wells’ books shown out of 113 books total in library. &quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  For example, I recently purchased Martha Wells’ Murderbot series from Humble
  Bundle and I’m planning to read through them next year, maybe taking a head
  start already during the holidays. BookLore allows me to easily check what
  book’s coming next, keep track of my notes and reviews and so on, even if I
  still manually download the books to my devices for reading.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I’m willing to be that some time next year, having access to this system will
  motivate me to maybe get a Kobo reader to make it easier to read from my own
  collection.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  The best part of BookLore is that it’s running in my bedroom so I own my data
  and it’s open source so I can add things to it if I find a need for something
  it doesn’t provide out of the box.
&lt;/p&gt;

    </content>
  </entry> 
  <entry>
    <title>Year in Review 2025</title>
    <link href="https://hamatti.org/posts/year-in-review-2025/" />
    <updated>2025-12-31T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://hamatti.org/posts/year-in-review-2025/</id>
    <content type="html">
      &lt;h2 class=&quot;notion-heading_2 notion-color-default&quot;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  In
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Big_Fat_Quiz_of_the_Year&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Big Fat Quiz of The Year&lt;/a&gt;
  2016, Mel Giedroyc described her year as:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;notion-quote notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
  It was absolutely cracking. Marvellous. Every month rolled by better than the
  last. May, May was really good. May was a cracker. August, even better than
  May. September, it was so brilliant.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to have even 10% of her positivity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  It’s time for another end-of-year reflection post. I started writing these in
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://hamatti.org/posts/year-in-review-2016/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;2016&lt;/a&gt; after
  a friend of mine had started doing the same and they’ve become not only a nice
  habit to wrap up a year but also a nice time capsule for me. Years go by and
  over time they meld together and it’s hard to remember what life has brought
  to me.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  So here’s my review of 2025, a year that finally brought some positive hope
  into life after a few ones I’d rather wish had gone differently.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Sprinkled in are some pictures from throughout the year from important
  moments.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://hamatti.org/assets/img/posts/year-in-review-2025/1.png.webp&quot; alt=&quot;A rainbow coloured massive Slinky in the darkness of Finnish winter in January. &quot; /&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;notion-heading_2 notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
  What I hoped for 2025 last year?
&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Rather than set up new year’s resolutions, I like to set a few hopes or goals
  for the year — some of them I complete and others not so much.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;notion-quote notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
  &lt;b class=&quot;notion-text-bold&quot;&gt;I want to become a better writer.&lt;/b&gt; I haven’t
  quite figured out the metrics for that yet though. It’s hard to know if my
  output improves in quality. Over a lunch with a friend, we brainstormed this a
  bit and one outcome we came up with was to write more long-form stuff this
  year. Something akin to a book - but probably not an actual book.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  My writing goal for this year was not one to be easily measured. The previous
  year, I set my goal to publishing 100 posts and reached that but I didn’t feel
  it would be meaningful to raise it from there as that wouldn’t really benefit
  me.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, I wanted to become better at writing, whatever that would mean.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Recently, over the last couple of years, I’ve noticed more and more that I
  actual enjoy my own writing and feel proud of my pieces. And I don’t seem to
  be the only one.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I’ve gotten a lot of positive feedback on my writing too. During the year, my
  readership has more than doubled: the monthly views have gone from around 150k
  to 300k and visitors from roughly 20k to 45k per month. What I love more than
  those numbers going up is meeting people in events and even in the pub every
  now and then who come talk to me and telling me they enjoy my writing.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;notion-quote notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
  And sure,
  &lt;b class=&quot;notion-text-bold&quot;&gt;the main goal of 2025 is to find a job&lt;/b&gt;. But I
  hate setting up goals where the outcomes are not in my hands. I can do things
  to increase the odds but eventually, getting hired is in someone else’s hands
  and if those hands are not kind, I cannot reach the goal. I don’t have
  particularly high hopes about 2025 either since the market hasn’t shown much
  improvement towards the end of this year.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I managed to find a job — or more accurately, a job found me — this year. I
  was reached out by a recruiter, we talked for a bit, I went through a couple
  of rounds of interviews and in the end of April, I joined
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reaktor.com/en-fi&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Reaktor&lt;/a&gt;
  as a full-stack developer. I got to join an office with a lot of fantastic
  people that I knew from before and have been having a great time so far.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  In a society where having a job is how people’s worth is measured, it sure is
  nice to have one.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;notion-quote notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
  If I think about the &lt;b class=&quot;notion-text-bold&quot;&gt;communities I run&lt;/b&gt;, they
  are pretty much in good shape and I’ll keep running them for years to come but
  they are also reaching the limits of what makes sense in terms of growth or
  doing more. They need to be at a capacity where they can be run whilst doing
  everything else in life so I can’t go overboard with them just because I now
  have more time. I also don’t want them to end up in a situation where nobody
  else would continue after me because the amount of free labour is too much.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  We had really a good year with both
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://turkufrontend.fi/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Turku ❤️ Frontend&lt;/a&gt;
  (with which we celebrated
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://turkufrontend.fi/10-years&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;10 year anniversary&lt;/a&gt;
  in December) and
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://archipylago.dev/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;archipylago&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;notion-quote notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
  I also want to have
  &lt;b class=&quot;notion-text-bold&quot;&gt;more good discussions with people&lt;/b&gt;. To
  experiment with that, I’ve crafted and designed a year-long project. I want to
  keep the details still secret but if I succeed in sticking to it, I’ll write
  about it in-depth towards the end of 2025.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I started the year with a project I called “One email every day” where I
  wanted to start more discussions with wonderful people. I emailed replies to
  blog posts, said thanks to people who maintain movements, communities or
  software that I enjoy. Even though that project didn’t last very long, the
  spirit of it stayed with me the whole year. I started a ton of great
  discussions via blogs, emails, social media and in person and I’m so glad I
  did. I also added a box at the end of each blog posts that reads:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;notion-quote notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
  If something above resonated with you, let&#39;s start a discussion about it!
  Email me at juhamattisantala at gmail dot com and share your thoughts. In
  2025, I want to have more deeper discussions with people from around the world
  and I&#39;d love if you&#39;d be part of that.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  That got me quite a few good emails as well which started nice discussions.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, I’m really glad with all the four goals for the year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;notion-heading_2 notion-color-default&quot;&gt;General thoughts of 2025&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Looking back, 2025 was a better year than many of the few previous ones but
  still at the back of my head, I feel I’m nowhere near where I’d like to be in
  life. I feel like I’m still not in a driver’s seat of my own life but rather
  trying to hang on.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Doing this reflection exercise helps notice all the good stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;notion-heading_2 notion-color-default&quot;&gt;Writing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://hamatti.org/assets/img/posts/year-in-review-2025/2.png.webp&quot; alt=&quot;A calendar chart showing every day of 2025 with colored dots here and there denoting a day when a blog post was published. Other than one Wednesday in early October, they are all filled with squares. Most of the other posts are published on Saturdays. In August, there’s a big blob of almost daily publishing. &quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I published something every week — a streak I’ve managed to keep going since
  July 2023. Like last year, all but one Wednesday got a blog post.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  This year, I started two new main writing projects to accompany my blog:
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://buttondown.com/juhis/archive/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;From Juhis with Love&lt;/a&gt;
  newsletter that, once a month, gathers together what I’ve been up to and has
  links to wonderful, joyful things I’ve come across in the Internet that month
  and
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://notes.hamatti.org/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Garden of Learning&lt;/a&gt;, my digital garden where I publish my notes.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  In this blog, I published 107 blog posts. I wrote and published 12 newsletter
  issues and published one guest post. I published a bit over 350 notes in the
  digital garden, 12 of them being my
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://notes.hamatti.org/technology/advent-of-code/2025/advent-of-code-2025-landing-page&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Advent of Code solution explanations&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  In August, I took part in
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://hamatti.org/blog/blaugust-2025&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Blaugust&lt;/a&gt; and
  despite not having a plan to write that much, ended up with 31 posts in 31
  days once again and had a blast. Made a bunch of new writing friends this year
  again.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of my favourite blog posts from the year:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;notion-bulleted_list&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;notion-bulleted_list_item notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://hamatti.org/posts/human-curation-over-algorithmic-recommendations/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Human curation over algorithmic recommendations&lt;/a&gt;
    (Jan 2025)
  &lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li class=&quot;notion-bulleted_list_item notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://hamatti.org/posts/be-careful-with-introducing-ai-into-your-notes/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Be careful with introducing AI into your notes&lt;/a&gt;
    (Jan 2025)
  &lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li class=&quot;notion-bulleted_list_item notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://hamatti.org/posts/explaining-it-helps-you-learn-it/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Explaining it helps you learn it&lt;/a&gt;
    (Feb 2025)
  &lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li class=&quot;notion-bulleted_list_item notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://hamatti.org/posts/redesign-and-rewrite-of-playtest-printer/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Redesign and rewrite of playtest printer&lt;/a&gt;
    (Mar 2025)
  &lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li class=&quot;notion-bulleted_list_item notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://hamatti.org/posts/shrink-designing-board-games/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;“Shrink designing” board games&lt;/a&gt;
    (Mar 2025)
  &lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li class=&quot;notion-bulleted_list_item notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://hamatti.org/posts/how-i-write-and-publish-blog-posts-in-april-2025/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;How I write and publish blog posts in April 2025 &lt;/a&gt;(Apr 2025)
  &lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li class=&quot;notion-bulleted_list_item notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://hamatti.org/posts/notifications-about-almost-anything-with-ntfy-sh/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Notifications about (almost) anything with ntfy.sh&lt;/a&gt;
    (May 2025)
  &lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li class=&quot;notion-bulleted_list_item notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://hamatti.org/posts/as-a-developer-my-most-important-tools-are-a-pen-and-a-notebook/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;As a developer, my most important tools are a pen and a notebook&lt;/a&gt;
    (May 2025)
  &lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li class=&quot;notion-bulleted_list_item notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://hamatti.org/posts/indieweb-principles-and-i/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;IndieWeb principles and I&lt;/a&gt;
    (Jul 2025)
  &lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li class=&quot;notion-bulleted_list_item notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://hamatti.org/posts/build-the-forum-you-want-to-see-in-the-web/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Build the forum you want to see in the web&lt;/a&gt;
    (Aug 2025)
  &lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li class=&quot;notion-bulleted_list_item notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://hamatti.org/posts/static-sites-enable-a-good-time-travel-experience/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Static sites enable a good time travel experience&lt;/a&gt;
    (Aug 2025)
  &lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li class=&quot;notion-bulleted_list_item notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://hamatti.org/posts/my-favourite-bird-pokemon-tcg-card-arts/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;My favourite bird Pokémon TCG card arts&lt;/a&gt;
    (Sep 2025)
  &lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li class=&quot;notion-bulleted_list_item notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://hamatti.org/posts/pycon-finland-2025-recap/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;PyCon Finland 2025 recap&lt;/a&gt;
    (Oct 2025)
  &lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li class=&quot;notion-bulleted_list_item notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://hamatti.org/posts/improve-your-programming-skills-with-advent-of-code/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Improve your programming skills with Advent of Code&lt;/a&gt;
    (Nov 2025)
  &lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li class=&quot;notion-bulleted_list_item notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://hamatti.org/posts/i-built-a-tiny-rss-generator-for-my-advent-of-code-solutions/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;I built a tiny RSS generator for my Advent of Code solutions&lt;/a&gt;
    (Dec 2025)
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I also had writing projects that got scrapped or postponed: in the spring I
  had plans to write a small book but then I got a job and that got sidetracked.
  I started writing a technical guide that is still on my holiday backlog, maybe
  I’ll get to start the new year with it. About 50 blog post drafts didn’t see
  the light of day but they live in my notes and might resurface.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I’ve learned to let go of old projects that never became anything. I used to
  stress about them and see them as failures but now I’m just happy I have a lot
  of ideas and that the best ones come through and the rest can be let go.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;notion-heading_2 notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
  Communities, events and speaking
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://hamatti.org/assets/img/posts/year-in-review-2025/3.png.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Juhis is speaking in front of a small audience in an office space. &quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  This year was a great one for communities I was involved with. With
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://turkufrontend.fi/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Turku ❤️ Frontend&lt;/a&gt;
  we organised 8 meetups and one official afterwork and with
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://archipylago.dev/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;archipylago&lt;/a&gt; we
  ran 5 meetups and 3 sprints. I stepped down from admin position at
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://koodiklinikka.fi/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Koodiklinikka&lt;/a&gt;
  but remained active and ran some community projects like our annual
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://kk-bracket.netlify.app/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;NHL Bracket Challenge&lt;/a&gt;
  where I finished 3rd. In May, we organised another
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://futurefrontend.com/2025/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Future Frontend conference&lt;/a&gt;
  which was a blast.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I got on stage 18 times this year to talk about debugging, Django,
  documentation, blogging, prototyping, building developer portfolios and
  building communities. And I hosted a pub quiz in our company winter party
  which was fun.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Due to early year unemployment and then starting a new job, I didn’t have the
  opportunity to visit any conferences abroad but my highlight of the year was
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://hamatti.org/posts/pycon-finland-2025-recap/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;speaking in PyCon Finland in Jyväskylä&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://hamatti.org/assets/img/posts/year-in-review-2025/4.png.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Juhis is speaking, waving his hands up in the air with a slide titled Rubber duck debugging on the screen. &quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Seth Larson launched
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://sethmlarson.dev/fedi-donut-friday&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Fedi Donut Friday&lt;/a&gt;
  initiative and I ate donuts and pastries every other Friday and invited others
  in Mastodon to join me to celebrate their weekly wins. I made a couple of new
  online friends through that.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I played more Pokémon TCG in person this year, participating in leagues and
  retro nights but also ran
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://notes.hamatti.org/gaming/board-games/pokemon/scarlet--and--violet-progression-series&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;a Progression Series&lt;/a&gt;
  for our group playing through all sets of Scarlet &amp; Violet block. In 4.5
  months, we opened 16 sets, built 15 decks each and battled against each other
  after each set.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;notion-heading_2 notion-color-default&quot;&gt;Projects&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Garden of Learning&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  As I mentioned in writing section, in January I started publishing my notes in
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://notes.hamatti.org/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Garden of Learning&lt;/a&gt;, my digital garden. It took a bit of time to figure out some of the
  technical bits but I managed to end up with a flow that works really nice.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I’ve really enjoyed having a place for writing that is not quite blog-like.
  Notes like
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://notes.hamatti.org/sources/music/1001-albums-you-must-hear-before-you-die&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;1001 Albums You Must Hear Before You Die&lt;/a&gt;,
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://notes.hamatti.org/gaming/board-games/pokemon/scarlet--and--violet-progression-series&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Scarlet &amp; Violet Progression Series&lt;/a&gt;
  and
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://notes.hamatti.org/sources/shows-and-movies/2025-christmas-movie-tracking&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;2025 Christmas Movie tracking&lt;/a&gt;
  are good examples of notes that I’ve updated over time.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  There has been a lot of moments when I’ve considered building my own tool for
  building websites from Obsidian. So far, I’ve managed to get by with
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Quartz&lt;/a&gt; but
  there are a few things I would wish to customise and maybe clean up some of
  the output code.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  It’s one of those projects where it feels like a “quick weekend project” in my
  head but I’ve been around the neighbourhood enough to know that they never are
  such. Let’s file that into the “one day” part of the backlog.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Progression Series website&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  In September, our local Pokémon TCG play group started
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://notes.hamatti.org/gaming/board-games/pokemon/scarlet--and--violet-progression-series&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;a Progression Series&lt;/a&gt;
  and to keep track of matchups and scores, I built
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://progression-series.hamatti.org/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;a website for us&lt;/a&gt;.
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://hamatti.org/posts/leveraging-eleventys-custom-data-file-format-feature-for-simpler-game-scoring-format/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Using Eleventy’s custom data file format&lt;/a&gt;, I managed to build a nice scores website that I was able to update directly
  via GitHub. Once people reported their match scores, I could open the
  repository on GitHub’s mobile app, add a line to the data file and the site
  would recalculate scores and update it.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  At one point, I started adding deck images (for the future, I need to figure
  out a better way to provide them in accessible way by asking players to submit
  decklists and not just images) for each set.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Advent of Code&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  My usual December joy is to solve
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://adventofcode.com/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Advent of Code puzzles&lt;/a&gt;
  and
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://notes.hamatti.org/technology/advent-of-code/2025/advent-of-code-2025-landing-page&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;write explanations of my Python solutions&lt;/a&gt;
  to help people learn programming. This year had 24 puzzles in 12 days and the
  new shorter calendar was a great thing. I was able to get all the stars for
  the first time and didn’t have to make difficult decisions about how to spend
  the few last days leading into Christmas.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I wrote
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://hamatti.org/posts/advent-of-code-2025-retrospective/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;a retrospective&lt;/a&gt;
  of the month and the wonderful new people who I discovered through their
  solutions.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Playtest printer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  One of my beloved hobbies is playing TCGs and prototyping board games and I
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://hamatti.org/posts/redesign-and-rewrite-of-playtest-printer/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;redesigned my playtest card printer&lt;/a&gt;
  to finally give it some polish and new features.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  It’s one of those small apps I enjoy to use and occasionally work on. Over the
  years, I used it to also print a lot of card sized info cards. I printed a
  double-sided reminder card for chess board starting assembly and
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.chess.com/openings/The-Cow&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;the Cow opening&lt;/a&gt;
  and a couple of rule-reminder / custom player aid cards for other games I own
  but don’t want to carry manuals with me.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://hamatti.org/assets/img/posts/year-in-review-2025/5.png.webp&quot; alt=&quot;A chess board with pieces in their starting positions &quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I play chess rarely enough to remember whether A1 is black or white and in
  which order the Queen and King are placed at the start.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Pokémon Toolkit&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Over the year, multiple things led me to start building a self-hosted Pokémon
  TCG toolkit: a collection of tools that enable me to do all sorts of things.
  It’s running in my bedroom for local access only because I don’t want Pokémon
  Company’s lawyers knocking on my door.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://pokemontcg.io/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;PokemonTCG.io API&lt;/a&gt;
  started having problems early on and I had to figure out a backup plan so I
  started building a custom API to power up my hobby projects. It’s still
  missing some key features like a really good search but it’s good enough that
  I was able to start building the other bits.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I used to have my collection inventory in
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pkmn.gg/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;pkmn.gg&lt;/a&gt; but they
  started to have more and more features behind a paywall and their focused
  seemed to move to a direction I don’t want to follow. The final trigger for
  building my own was when I realised they didn’t have a way for me to export my
  data. I knew I needed to start building my own sooner than later, otherwise it
  would be a massive undertaking to rebuild the collection later. With that, I’m
  in a stage that has all the features I needed from the site but has some added
  features like a trade feature and changelog.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  As we started playing the Progression Series, I realised the amount of cards
  grew really fast and I needed a better way to manage my card pool than having
  an evergrowing list of cards. I built a script that takes an export from the
  virtual booster opening simulator and stored the cards in a database. I then
  built a UI that shows the cards I have, sorted by card type (Pokémon, Items,
  Stadiums, Supporters and so on) and displayed by evolution lines.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Finally, I started building a tool to manage future Progression Series. It’s
  still a work in progress but it allows league admins to create a series,
  select which sets are part of it, invite players by email and track scores and
  card pools.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  In the future, once everything else moves forward a bit, I’ll integrate my
  earlier deck builder project into the toolkit.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Building this has been some of the most fun I’ve had writing software in ages.
  I’ve built it with Django and htmx which has turned out to be an excellent
  tech stack for a project like this.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Homelab&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I have two Raspberry Pis and a NAS running in my bedroom that I’ve configured
  with a few self-hosted homelab projects:
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.home-assistant.io/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Home Assistant&lt;/a&gt;
  to run my
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://notes.hamatti.org/my-projects/smart-home/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;smart home&lt;/a&gt;,
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.paperless-ngx.com/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;paperless-ngx&lt;/a&gt;
  to keep my digital documents in order,
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://jellyfin.org/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Jellyfin&lt;/a&gt; for my
  personal media collection, a
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/coder/code-server&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;VS Code Server&lt;/a&gt;
  for editing my projects on the Raspberry Pi and the aforementioned Pokémon
  Toolkit.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I also have a couple of RSS proxies running there. Either to
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://hamatti.org/posts/i-built-custom-rss-hydrator-for-better-github-and-youtube-feeds/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;take an existing RSS and modify it before it reaches my reader&lt;/a&gt;
  or to run custom RSS builders for sites that don’t provide RSS themselves.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I also have some scripts there that I can trigger from my iPad with a
  Shortcut: for example, I can choose an action from the iOS’s Share menu to
  send the current page URL to my homelab and depending on where that link
  points to, the bash script does different things.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  It’s a growing collection as I discover new services. One of those is
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/booklore-app/BookLore&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;BookLore&lt;/a&gt;, an ebook manager that I had been looking at for a while. I installed it and
  added most of my collection over the Christmas holidays.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;notion-heading_2 notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
  Games, books, podcasts and so on
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Games&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://hamatti.org/assets/img/posts/year-in-review-2025/6.png.webp&quot; alt=&quot;A dozen or so deckboxes and two playmats on a kitchen table with dice and tokens spread around. &quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I wrote
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://hamatti.org/posts/i-played-some-games-this-year/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;a separate review post&lt;/a&gt;
  about some of my favourite games I played this year.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Books, podcast and other media&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://hamatti.org/assets/img/posts/year-in-review-2025/7.png.webp&quot; alt=&quot;A book with Finnish title Veisu luonnonkoneille by Becky Chambers &quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Most of my recommendations are scifi or solarpunk adventures. I finally read
  Becky Chambers’
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://us.macmillan.com/series/monkrobot&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Monk and Robot&lt;/a&gt;
  duology and it was brilliant. I loved both books: I read the one in English
  and the other translated to Finnish as it was translated by my favourite
  translator and both were excellent.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Nnedi Okorafor’s
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Binti_(novella)&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Binti&lt;/a&gt;
  was another excellent scifi story.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/This_Is_How_You_Lose_the_Time_War&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;This Is How You Lose the Time War&lt;/a&gt;
  had a lot of good in it but it was bit too abstract and dragged along a tid
  bit too much to find a permanent spot in my bookshelf but it had its moments.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sarjakuvakauppa.fi/ankkalinna-portti-kahden-maailman-valilla.html&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Katja Kontturi’s Ankkalinna - Portti kahden maailman välillä&lt;/a&gt;
  is a Finnish book about Don Rosa’s comics. It’s a casual reader’s version of
  Kontturi’s PhD thesis and I got to meet the author in October and got my book
  signed as well. As a comic book geek, it was really nice to peek into the more
  analytical side of how Rosa crafted his stories.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  My #1 podcast of the year was once again
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://lateralcast.com/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Tom Scott’s Lateralcast&lt;/a&gt;
  because it’s just that good. Some new, interesting ones were
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sleepbaseball.com/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Northwoods Baseball Sleep Radio&lt;/a&gt;
  which is a fictional sportscast of baseball games spoken in slow soft tones,
  perfect for falling asleep.
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.atypicalartists.co/breaker-about&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Breaker Whiskey&lt;/a&gt;
  is a lovely daily microfiction audio drama / podcast that I enjoyed in the
  fall. Individual episodes are only a couple of minutes long and they follow a
  story of a woman in a post-apocalyptic USA.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  To my Finnish speaking nerd audience, find Lohikäärmeradio wherever you find
  your podcasts. It’s a monthly podcast about fantasy and scifi books.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Towards the end of the year, I discovered
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://pagedout.institute/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;PagedOut! magazine&lt;/a&gt;. It’s a experimental one page == one topic technical magazine and I’ve
  enjoyed reading through the archives and have started drafting an article to
  submit there as well.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;notion-heading_2 notion-color-default&quot;&gt;What’s up with 2026?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Over the past years, I’ve enjoyed setting up goals for myself, just to give
  some structure. This year, I don’t feel like having any. I don’t believe that
  goals are really needed for good things to happen. Especially in personal
  life: I’ll work on things that I enjoy and believe will lead to good things,
  goals or no goals.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there’s one major thing I want to do next year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;b class=&quot;notion-text-bold&quot;&gt;I want to decide it’s gonna be a good year.&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Ever since the pandemic started, I’ve been struggling with how life has turned
  out. The pandemic and what followed kind of destroyed my career, took a huge
  toll on my mental and physical health and social life.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m tired of waiting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Maybe it’s not up to some external factors to change but rather my look on
  life.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  It’s time to take action and decide it’s good and focus on the positive
  aspects of life and make the most out of them.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    </content>
  </entry> 
  <entry>
    <title>From Juhis with Love #012 - For a happy new year</title>
    <link href="https://hamatti.org/posts/external-from-juhis-with-love-012-for-a-happy-new-year/" />
    <updated>2025-12-31T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://hamatti.org/posts/external-from-juhis-with-love-012-for-a-happy-new-year/</id>
    <content type="html">
      
&lt;p&gt;
  In December issue of &lt;strong&gt;From Juhis with Love&lt;/strong&gt;, I share updates of my
  projects and lovely bits from the internet.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://buttondown.com/juhis/archive/012-for-a-happy-new-year/&quot;&gt;Read #012 - For a happy new year&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;

    </content>
  </entry> 
  <entry>
    <title>We played a full Scarlet &amp; Violet Progression Series</title>
    <link href="https://hamatti.org/posts/we-played-a-full-scarlet-and-violet-progression-series/" />
    <updated>2025-12-27T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://hamatti.org/posts/we-played-a-full-scarlet-and-violet-progression-series/</id>
    <content type="html">
      &lt;p&gt;
  I’m a big fan of
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://progression-series.hamatti.org/about/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Pokémon TCG Progression Series&lt;/a&gt;
  (or Evolution Series as some call them). In such series, players open booster
  boxes of consecutive sets and after each box, build a deck with cards they’ve
  pulled so far and play games.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Azul GG Garcia and Chip Richey are currently in the middle of
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLtaquYSiDejMLtVX90ByBMe1h1IKcIoa7&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;their Scarlet and Violet series&lt;/a&gt;
  in Youtube, some years back GamingLair
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PL7rAiabAkA9R6OMRSd4VsQ-Yy0CObwtj5&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;started from the very Base Set&lt;/a&gt;
  and what got me originally excited in the format was
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLr_LAOrEVAtwrH2J-N6GVrhUBIGICfQsL&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Omnipoke’s Sun and Moon series&lt;/a&gt;
  that unfortunately never finished.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I’ve always wanted to play one but with physical cards, it’s so freaking
  expensive especially these days to purchase a booster box for each set that it
  never seemed doable. Last summer, I started putting together an idea where
  we’d open virtual packs using
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://pokemoncard.io/pack-sim/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;PokemonCard.io’s Pack Opening Simulator&lt;/a&gt;
  and
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://tcg.pokemon.com/en-us/tcgl/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Pokémon TCG Live&lt;/a&gt;. Scarlet and Violet block had just finished and it was relatively cheap to
  craft missing cards in Live so for the first time it felt doable.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I sent a message to our local game group’s Discord and in total, five people
  were interested in starting such series and in September, we opened the first
  packs starting with Scarlet and Violet base set.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  This week, just before Christmas, we finished our 15th round and thus
  completed the series. It was so much fun!
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Everyone seemed to enjoy the series enough that we’ll be playing a different
  block early next year. My hopes are with HeartGold &amp; SoulSilver block but
  let’s see what we decide as a group. If you’re interested in seeing how that
  goes, keep an eye on the
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://notes.hamatti.org/tags/pokemon&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Pokémon tag page on my notes&lt;/a&gt;
  as I’m going to keep track of it there.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;notion-heading_2 notion-color-default&quot;&gt;Deckbuilding challenge&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I consider deckbuilding to be the biggest weakness of mine when it comes to
  TCG. There’s so many options and building a balanced, focused and consistent
  deck is hard. That’s why I welcomed this challenge with open arms as I wanted
  to get better at building decks.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did I? Probably not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I had a great start to the series, finishing with strong 3-1, 3-1 and 2-2
  records in the first three sets. I’m used to playing jank rogue decks rather
  than meta decks so I think I had a bit of an advantage over the others in the
  early phases.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Once others started pulling better cards, especially ones with energy
  acceleration, I fell to the bottom tables. 1-3, 1-2, 0-3, 1-2 in four
  consecutive sets. Cards like
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://pkmncards.com/card/baxcalibur-scarlet-violet-promos-svp-019/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Baxcalibur&lt;/a&gt;,
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://pkmncards.com/card/gardevoir-ex-scarlet-violet-svi-086/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Gardevoir ex&lt;/a&gt;
  and
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://pkmncards.com/card/electric-generator-scarlet-violet-svi-170/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Electric Generator&lt;/a&gt;
  started to dominate the field and I had not pulled anything with proper energy
  acceleration to keep up with these new decks.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Midway our series, I managed to get a set of Electric Generators from
  compensation packs (after each set, you’d get to open extra packs from
  previous set based on your ranking) and got my hands on
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://pkmncards.com/card/iron-hands-ex-paradox-rift-par-070/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Iron Hands ex&lt;/a&gt;
  and got a 3-0 sweep.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I had another clean sweep victory in Stellar Crown with a
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://pkmncards.com/card/terapagos-ex-prismatic-evolutions-pre-092/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Terapagos ex&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&quot;https://pkmncards.com/card/pidgeot-ex-obsidian-flames-obf-164/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Pidgeot ex&lt;/a&gt;
  deck that was really strong thanks to
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://pkmncards.com/card/crispin-stellar-crown-scr-133/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Crispin&lt;/a&gt;. After a nice streak of positive records, I made the biggest blunder in
  Journey Together set where I tried to put together a
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://pkmncards.com/card/raging-bolt-ex-temporal-forces-tef-123/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Raging Bolt ex&lt;/a&gt;
  deck despite only having one
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://pkmncards.com/card/professor-sadas-vitality-paradox-rift-par-170/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Professor Sada’s Vitality&lt;/a&gt;. My deck played one draw supporter and bricked completely in all three
  matches.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  In Destined Rivals, my
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://pkmncards.com/card/ethans-ho-oh-ex-destined-rivals-dri-039/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Ethan’s Ho-oh ex&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&quot;https://pkmncards.com/card/crustle-destined-rivals-dri-012/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Crustle&lt;/a&gt;
  deck was massively dominant picking up easy 3-0. I got so excited about the
  deck that I made a commemorative Tag Team GX card out of it
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://hamatti.org/assets/img/posts/we-played-a-full-scarlet-and-violet-progression-series/1.png.webp&quot; alt=&quot;A haphazardly photoshopped Pokemon card where I&#39;ve slapped Ho-oh and Crustle arts on top of a Pikachu and Zekrom Tag Team GX card and changed its name to Ho-oh &amp; Crustle &quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  In the final combined set of Black Bolt and White Flare, my
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://pkmncards.com/card/cinccino-black-bolt-blk-153/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Cinccino&lt;/a&gt;
  deck fell short after 3 excellent and most fun matches in the entire series.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I had a lot of fun playing a wide variety of decks and always trying to come
  up with something new, especially after sets when I had won 3-0. I decided
  early on that I’d retire decks that do too well because otherwise the format
  can have a tendency of staying with just a couple of decks and new sets having
  little to no impact.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I finished with a positive 25-24 record and 2nd place which was a big surprise
  for me, especially given how good the other players in our group are.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  If you’re into Pokémon TCG and have accumulated some recent cards in Live, I
  recommend finding some friends to play this format. It’s super fun!
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;notion-heading_2 notion-color-default&quot;&gt;Software&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I kept notes of my own progress with remarks on pulls, decks and matchups in
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://notes.hamatti.org/gaming/board-games/pokemon/scarlet--and--violet-progression-series&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Scarlet &amp; Violet Progression Series&lt;/a&gt;
  and built
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://progression-series.hamatti.org/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;a website&lt;/a&gt;
  to keep track of series scores, decks and matchups. A lot of these ideas
  evolved throughout the series as we learned what was fun.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Originally, my idea for keeping track of what we’ve pulled was to print the
  page to PDF (and I believe that’s what most others kept doing throughout the
  series) but I quickly came to the conclusion that it was gonna get out of hand
  real fast.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  So first I built
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Hamatti/export-pack-sim&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;export-pack-sim&lt;/a&gt;, a bookmarklet that extracts the card pool information for each set into
  plaintext and then started building my own selfhosted homelab solution for
  being able to add the cards to database and view them on a website. This
  turned out to be a great solution because it helped me brew new decks and
  think about my growing collection of cards even when I wasn’t logged in to
  Live.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://hamatti.org/assets/img/posts/we-played-a-full-scarlet-and-violet-progression-series/2.png.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot of a web page displaying three lines of Pokemon TCG cards: Abra, Absol and Aipom with varied counts of different cards. &quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  It’s still in its infancy as software as I just had to get something up and
  running while we were playing. It’s tightly connected to my own toolkit
  software that has its own card API, personal collection info and bunch of
  other helpful Pokémon TCG tools. I’ll try to see if I can find a way to open
  source them eventually but due to the fear of Pokémon Company lawyers, I’ll
  likely never be able to publish it as a web app.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  One of its strengths is that it shows Pokémon by their evolution lines
  regardless of which set they came from. And it separates trainer cards by
  their subtype (Item/Tool/Supporter/Stadium), making it easier to find what
  you’re looking for.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I did start building a management tool for a Progression Series however. In
  it, you can invite players, select which sets to include in a series and how
  many boosters to open per set. Players could then open the boosters, have
  cards automatically added to their pool and in the best case scenario, even
  build the decks directly in the app. The goal with the deck builder portion
  especially is that it could use your pulled cards pool as the source from
  where to search and pick cards so you wouldn’t accidentally add cards you
  don’t have.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  And then submit and confirm match scores so everything could be done within
  the app. Some parts of it I have working but it’s not quite ready yet for our
  next series. Maybe for the one after that.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    </content>
  </entry> 
  <entry>
    <title>Merry Christmas!</title>
    <link href="https://hamatti.org/posts/merry-christmas-2025/" />
    <updated>2025-12-24T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://hamatti.org/posts/merry-christmas-2025/</id>
    <content type="html">
      &lt;p&gt;
  It’s Christmas Eve today and that’s when we in Finland celebrate Christmas. If
  you’re reading this when it comes out, I’m likely sitting at the Christmas
  table, feasting on wonderful food that our family has set up and enjoying
  watching my siblings’ children enjoy the wonders of Christmas season.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Thus, I reserve this week in the blog to wish you all merry Christmas and
  happy holidays.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  2025 has been a year full of wonderful people and encounters. If our paths
  crossed this year, whether in personal life, through communities, at work or
  online, I’m thankful for that and I’m happy you’ve been part of my life this
  year ❤️.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  While the last few years since the pandemic haven’t been exactly smooth
  sailing, I’ve been blessed to have so many great people in my life through all
  that and in the grand scheme of things, that’s really what I’ll remember from
  these times and what really matters.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I will take a deeper dive into my year next Wednesday with my annual Year in
  Review post but for now, it’s time to enjoy good food and company and rest and
  relax.
&lt;/p&gt;

    </content>
  </entry> 
  <entry>
    <title>I played some games this year</title>
    <link href="https://hamatti.org/posts/i-played-some-games-this-year/" />
    <updated>2025-12-20T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://hamatti.org/posts/i-played-some-games-this-year/</id>
    <content type="html">
      &lt;p&gt;
  It’s been another year of gaming and I wanted to highlight some of my
  favourites from this year. Games I &lt;b class=&quot;notion-text-bold&quot;&gt;played&lt;/b&gt; this
  year, not necessarily games &lt;b class=&quot;notion-text-bold&quot;&gt;published&lt;/b&gt; this
  year. These are not in any kind of order really.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I’m sharing these in the spirit of
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://hamatti.org/posts/human-curation-over-algorithmic-recommendations/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;more human curation over algorithmic recommendations&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;notion-heading_2 notion-color-default&quot;&gt;NHL 21&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://hamatti.org/assets/img/posts/i-played-some-games-this-year/1.png.webp&quot; alt=&quot;EA Sports NHL 21 &quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  The list may start with a bit of a surprise. I’ve been playing hockey games
  ever since I learned how to hold a controller or smash a keyboard. Since the
  early 1990s. It all started with the
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://hamatti.org/2c70733fbc61800883e4e8c6c2efcc9a&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Face Off!&lt;/a&gt;, then with EA’s
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/NHLPA_Hockey_%2793&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;NHLPA Hockey &#39;93&lt;/a&gt;
  and
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/NHL_%2794&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;NHL ‘94&lt;/a&gt;
  on Super Nintendo, then
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/NHL_97&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;NHL 97&lt;/a&gt;
  on PC that I played for years. At the same time, I played
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Olympic_Hockey_%2798&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Olympic Hockey ‘98&lt;/a&gt;
  on Nintendo 64 and my mind was blown when
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/NHL_2003&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;NHL 2003&lt;/a&gt;
  on Xbox came out.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Around 2006, I switched to
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/NHL_2K&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;2K series&lt;/a&gt;
  for a while until in 2010, I got the demo of NHL 2010 and the skill stick
  experience changed the way of playing virtual hockey forever.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  People always talk about these sports games as just annual roster updates and
  that’s why I’ve usually been updating around 3 years as there usually is
  enough small incremental changes that accumulate in a few years so that the
  new ones feel fresh and usually better.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I’ve been sticking with NHL 21 for over 5 years already and I’m still enjoying
  it.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  “Enjoying it” might be an understatement. Every year since its release, it’s
  been my most played game on Playstation by quite a distance. In 2023, I played
  134 hours of it. In 2024, I played 124 hours. This year? 168 hours.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I’ve been thinking about maybe updating next year to get some of the newer
  teams and rosters but I’m in year 12 or something of a very nice GM run and it
  would be a shame to stop that now.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  If I were made to choose only one game I could play from here on, I’d pick
  this one. I’ll never get bored of it.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;notion-heading_2 notion-color-default&quot;&gt;Stardew Valley&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://hamatti.org/assets/img/posts/i-played-some-games-this-year/2.png.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Stardew Valley &quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  ConcernedApe’s masterpiece
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.stardewvalley.net/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Stardew Valley&lt;/a&gt;
  isn’t a new game either. I purchased it for my birthday in 2017, a year after
  its launch and have racked way over 1000 hours in Steam — and that’s only
  counting the hours I’ve played when online so the real number is even higher.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  In the world of microtransactions, shutting down servers, DLCs and all the
  other crap, Stardew Valley is what I wish more games would aspire to be. It’s
  been almost 10 years since the launch and it still receives updates. Not just
  bug fixes and stuff but actual story content. The team is working on the
  seventh update, 1.7., that’s been rumored to maybe arrive for the 10 year
  anniversary.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  It’s not just the official updates either. The modding community is wonderful
  and there are so many great, very deep content mods that brings new fresh life
  to the game just when you thought you’re getting bored of it.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  If you’re not familiar with it, Stardew Valley is a cozy farming game with
  elements of relationships with villagers, mining, fishing, combat and making a
  shit ton of money by selling wine in a town with 20 or so adults. Who’s buying
  and drinking all this wine? Millions worth of it, every month.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;notion-heading_2 notion-color-default&quot;&gt;Blue Prince&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://hamatti.org/assets/img/posts/i-played-some-games-this-year/3.png.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Blue Prince &quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I have a love-hate relationship with puzzle games. I mean, I love them and if
  it was up to me, I could spend hours every day solving puzzles. But I’m also
  very bad at them and they mess up my sleep with horrible nightmares really
  easily so I need to ration my intake.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  This year, I gave
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.blueprincegame.com/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Blue Prince&lt;/a&gt;
  two opportunities.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Blue Prince is a mansion drafting puzzle rogue-lite. Every day, you wake up in
  the courtyard of a mansion and try to make your way through it to solve its
  mysteries. Whenever you open a door to a new room, you get to draft a new room
  from a selection of (usually) 3 different rooms. There are a lot of mysteries
  and I have barely scratched the surface so I don’t know what they are yet.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I first got it in the spring when it came out and internet was raving about
  it. Most likely after watching this
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9K7zYN6_-2I&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Game Maker’s Toolkit video on the game&lt;/a&gt;. I played it and after a ton of attempts, I finally got through to one of
  the mysteries of the game — around day 70 or so. Only to find out, it was not
  a permanent upgrade but something that had to be solved EVERY TIME. That broke
  me and I abandoned the game.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  In November, I got back to it and equipped with better understanding of the
  game, started a new fresh run and made quite a lot of progress in just a
  fraction of the days spent. I still haven’t gotten back to the point where I
  was in the spring but I have a bit more permanent upgrades and goodies
  unlocked so I’ve been enjoying it a bit more this time.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;notion-heading_2 notion-color-default&quot;&gt;Cyberpunk 2077&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://hamatti.org/assets/img/posts/i-played-some-games-this-year/4.png.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Cyberpunk 2077 &quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Thanks to this summer’s
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cdprojekt.com/en/media/news/cyberpunk-2077-ultimate-edition-is-available-now-on-mac/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Mac release&lt;/a&gt;, I finally got to experience
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cyberpunk.net/fi/en/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Cyberpunk 2077&lt;/a&gt;
  properly. I had borrowed it from the library for PS4 before but at the first
  fight scene, it turned into a slideshow and I couldn’t ever get through that
  forced moment.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I’ve been wanting to play this game for so long and it’s been great. I’m a big
  fan of cyberpunk genre and I feel the game has captured many aspects of it
  brilliantly. I love roaming the city, interacting with the characters and
  hacking away.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  At the same time, I feel like it’s not gonna be a game that I’ll return over
  and over again in the future. It’s more of a one-off (or two, or three off)
  experience and that’s fine too.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;notion-heading_2 notion-color-default&quot;&gt;Marvel’s Spider-Man&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://hamatti.org/assets/img/posts/i-played-some-games-this-year/5.png.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Marvel’s Spider-Man &quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I might be a bit late to the party with this one but I finally played
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Marvel%27s_Spider-Man_(video_game)&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Marvel’s Spider-Man&lt;/a&gt;
  that’s been highly praised especially for its web-slinging movement mechanics.
  And yes, they are fun. But also, there’s a lot of it — too much to my taste.
  The first few hours it’s so much fun. After 12 hours, it gets boring because
  all the missions are spread out in a way that you need to cross half of New
  York to get to the location.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Despite that criticism, the game is great. Definitely worth all the praise
  it’s gotten. The story is your run of the mill Spider-Man story but it does
  its job well. Occasionally, you get to play as MJ and while usually these
  types of gimmicks are poorly done in games, I actually enjoyed these as well.
  While Spider-Man flies around the city and kicks and punches his way through
  the bad guys, MJ takes a more stealthy approach as a good journalist does.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;notion-heading_2 notion-color-default&quot;&gt;Hoop Land&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://hamatti.org/assets/img/posts/i-played-some-games-this-year/6.png.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Hoop land &quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I don’t play a lot of games on mobile but there are a couple of games I’ve
  been enjoying on my iPad that I want to share. After years of enjoying
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Retro_Bowl&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Retro Bowl&lt;/a&gt;, the game became bit too repetitive and I was looking for something new. I
  ran into
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.koalitygame.com/hoop-land&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Hoop Land&lt;/a&gt;, a basketball game with surprising depth.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Retro Bowl’s simple controls and mechanics made it a perfect game to play on a
  tiny breaks but Hoop Land essentially requires a controller so it has filled a
  different type of void. But when you sit down to play, oh boy is it fun. It
  has a bit of a learning curve and in the beginning, I got smacked in the head
  every game but eventually started to get the ball into the basket.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  For those moments when all I have with me is the iPad and a controller, it’s
  real good entertainment where I can put hours into.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;notion-heading_2 notion-color-default&quot;&gt;Tatami&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://hamatti.org/assets/img/posts/i-played-some-games-this-year/7.png.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Tatami &quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://kaylees.site/tatami.html&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Tatami&lt;/a&gt;
  is a lovely puzzle game by Kaylee Calderolla. The mechanics are simple: you
  need to group tiles on a grid into rectangles based on the rules imposed by
  each level. The levels get more difficult as time goes on.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  As it’s a puzzle game that I need to ration to maintain a healthy-ish sleep
  cycle, I’m limiting myself to maximum couple of levels a day and early in the
  morning. I’m currently at level 231 and the puzzles are starting to get real
  difficult here.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  The first 200 levels are free but it’s a single purchase game that’s built
  with such care for the users that I recommend purchasing it right away.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;notion-heading_2 notion-color-default&quot;&gt;Pokémon TCG&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://hamatti.org/assets/img/posts/i-played-some-games-this-year/8.png.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Pokemon TCG &quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Moving (partly) away from the digital realm, my number one game this year was
  Pokémon TCG. I played a ton both in-person as well as digitally. One of the
  highlights of the year was running a
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://notes.hamatti.org/gaming/board-games/pokemon/scarlet--and--violet-progression-series&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Scarlet &amp; Violet Progression Series&lt;/a&gt;
  that we started in September and finished just before Christmas.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I played in a bunch of Leagues and Prereleases, even won a tiny GLC tournament
  and continued growing my collection of Eeveelutions whenever I could pick up
  new cards I’m still missing.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I also spent a good chunk of timing building my own tools to manage my card
  collection (moved away from a service that provided no export and started to
  paywall and enshittify aggressively), built my own card API (when one I had
  used for years started to have issues), built a bunch of tooling to manage the
  progression series (a public website, a card pool viewer and I’m mid-way
  building a platform where one could manage a complete progression series with
  opening packs, building decks and recording scores. None of that will likely
  ever be publicly available because I don’t want their lawyers on my ass but
  I’m self-hosting for myself and the growing toolkit has been wonderful so far.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;notion-heading_2 notion-color-default&quot;&gt;Magic the Gathering&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://hamatti.org/assets/img/posts/i-played-some-games-this-year/9.png.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Magic the Gathering &quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I have been following Magic the Gathering for years but never really got into
  it to play. Mainly because my money already goes to Pokémon TCG and can’t
  afford two TCG hobbies simultaneously.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Then last year, they published
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://mtg.wiki/page/Bloomburrow&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Bloomburrow&lt;/a&gt;
  and I was sold. This year, I actually started playing. Not a ton but more and
  more as the year progressed. I built my own
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://notes.hamatti.org/gaming/board-games/mtg-battle-box&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Battle Box&lt;/a&gt;
  for easy pick-and-play at the pub, I built a
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://notes.hamatti.org/gaming/board-games/forgetful-fish&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Dandân, Forgetful Fish&lt;/a&gt;
  deck for similar type of game play.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  And when a friend asked if I’d like to join their group of casual Commander, I
  purchased my first Commander pre-con deck
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://moxfield.com/decks/PzY-rAZ3SEiLi_fuR2XBhQ&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Family Matters&lt;/a&gt;
  and we started playing regularly.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;notion-heading_2 notion-color-default&quot;&gt;Parks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://hamatti.org/assets/img/posts/i-played-some-games-this-year/10.png.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Parks &quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I didn’t get to play as much
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/266524/parks&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Parks&lt;/a&gt;
  as I would have wanted this year but it has slowly climbed up the ranks of my
  favourite board games. It has such nice aesthetics, great gameplay and it’s
  the type of game that provides depth but is still kind to beginners and as
  such, can be a great gateway
  &lt;s class=&quot;notion-text-strikethrough&quot;&gt;drug&lt;/s&gt; game to get new people into the
  hobby.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  In Parks, you and your friends are hiking at national parks, gathering
  resources, taking photos and experiencing the great wild nature.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;notion-heading_2 notion-color-default&quot;&gt;NHL 94/25 romhack&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://hamatti.org/assets/img/posts/i-played-some-games-this-year/11.png.webp&quot; alt=&quot;NHL 25 Romhack &quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  While NHL 21 has been my main way of enjoying virtual hockey, Adam Catalyst’s
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://forum.nhl94.com/index.php?%2Ftopic%2F34793-nhl-94-2025-edition-by-adam-catalyst%2F=&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;NHL25 romhack for NHL ‘94&lt;/a&gt;
  has been a delight. NHL ‘94 is one of the most iconic hockey games ever and
  one I played a lot as a kid. So whenever there’s a way to return to that
  iconic experience with something new and fresh, I’m all for it.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  This romhack brings modern teams and rosters, alongside with gameplay tweaks
  and graphics refinements. It’s a perfect nostalgia trip while still getting to
  enjoy all the benefits of the most recent roster updates.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  It’s funny that if I want to play with Seattle Kraken or Utah Mammoth, I need
  to abandon my modern PS4 experience and play the game from over 30 years ago.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;notion-heading_2 notion-color-default&quot;&gt;PokeRogue&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://hamatti.org/assets/img/posts/i-played-some-games-this-year/12.png.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Pokerogue &quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://pokerogue.net/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;PokéRogue&lt;/a&gt;, a
  fan-made rogue-lite Pokémon game continues to entertain me. I have an
  offline-version on my Steam Deck that I haven’t updated since I created it (I
  should check if my documented workflow still works).
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  PokéRogue is a game where you have 10 points to use to pick your starting
  party: the better the Pokémon, more expensive it is to add. Then you fight
  randomly generated opponents, catch wild monsters to add them to your party
  and as new starting Pokémon and try to get through the game.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a lot of fun!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;notion-heading_2 notion-color-default&quot;&gt;Factorio&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://hamatti.org/assets/img/posts/i-played-some-games-this-year/13.png.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Factorio &quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.factorio.com/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Factorio&lt;/a&gt; is
  one of those games that I had to put on a shelf in April when I got a job. I
  couldn’t afford booting it up, blinking my eyes and noticing it’s 5 in the
  morning. I’m kind of looking forward to the Christmas holidays and dedicating
  a few days to just getting lost in the world of Factorio.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Every time we talk about video games with friends, Factorio comes up. It has a
  devious lack of cycles, if that makes any sense. There’s never a “now is a
  good moment to stop playing” moment. You just keep on going and going and
  going, solving the next optimisation puzzle. Until you notice you haven’t
  eaten or slept in ages.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I always play it on a safe mode, ie. turn off the aggressive creatures. The
  game is complicated enough to try to solve without the constant worry of
  someone wrecking my base.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  In Factorio, you’re stranded on a strange planet and need to make the best out
  of the bad situation. You start by collecting some copper and iron ore and
  coal by hand and little by little build a massive automated factory with the
  aim to conquer space.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I’d love to recommend the game to everyone. If you care about your sleep
  though, maybe give it a pass 😅.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    </content>
  </entry> 
  <entry>
    <title>Advent of Code 2025 retrospective</title>
    <link href="https://hamatti.org/posts/advent-of-code-2025-retrospective/" />
    <updated>2025-12-17T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://hamatti.org/posts/advent-of-code-2025-retrospective/</id>
    <content type="html">
      
&lt;p&gt;
  It feels weird to write an Advent of Code retrospective a week before
  Christmas. For years, it’s either been one of the last or first posts of the
  year. This year, the creator of Advent of Code, Eric, decided to limit the
  amount of puzzles to 12 days instead of the previous 25 and I really liked
  that.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  This year, for the first time I reached the end credits. I got all 24 stars in
  12 days.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I had a wonderful time as usual. I solved all puzzles with Python, using
  nothing but standard library for everything except day 10, part 2. My
  favourite part is
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://notes.hamatti.org/technology/advent-of-code/2025/advent-of-code-2025-landing-page&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;writing about my solutions&lt;/a&gt;, explaining my thinking process and teaching how wonderful language Python
  is.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Over the past weekend and change, I’ve been thinking about this a lot. I’d
  like my explanations to be helpful in learning puzzle solving, iteratively
  building solutions step-by-step, debugging and Python.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Sometimes I feel though that my refactoring and cleaning up process polishes
  the solutions too much and I reach too eagerly to what is available in
  Python’s standard library, especially itertools and collections modules. They
  are very good things to learn about if you want to write good Python code but
  many of them are “if you know to reach for them” level of things rather than
  something you might organically figure out.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Hence, I’m not anymore sure who the audience for them is. Maybe next year I’ll
  really focus on writing beginner-level step-by-step guides rather than just
  beautiful Pythonic solutions. I especially felt this when I organised an
  in-person jam on the 11th and went through one of the puzzles with a student.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I did make new friends and reconnected with old ones through the writing and
  it was a highlight of the year for me.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  This year, I learned a lot from the following people who shared their
  solutions in a lovely variety of programming and human languages:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;notion-bulleted_list&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;notion-bulleted_list_item notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.minaspace.org/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Mina&lt;/a&gt;
    (Perl)
  &lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li class=&quot;notion-bulleted_list_item notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.godeveloper.co.uk/advent-of-code/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Paul&lt;/a&gt;
    (Go)
  &lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li class=&quot;notion-bulleted_list_item notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://work.njae.me.uk/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Dr. Neil&lt;/a&gt;
    (Haskell)
  &lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li class=&quot;notion-bulleted_list_item notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://notes.adfoucart.be/aocode25/index.html&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Adrien&lt;/a&gt;
    (Python, in French)
  &lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li class=&quot;notion-bulleted_list_item notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ohjelmointiputka.net/keskustelu/32619-sql-advent-of-code-2025-sqlite&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Antti&lt;/a&gt;
    (SQL, in Finnish)
  &lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li class=&quot;notion-bulleted_list_item notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://brassnet.biz/blog&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Dan&lt;/a&gt;
    (Python)
  &lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li class=&quot;notion-bulleted_list_item notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://christopherhimes.com/blog/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Christopher&lt;/a&gt;
    (Python)
  &lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li class=&quot;notion-bulleted_list_item notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://marcoshuerta.com/posts/aoc/2025/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Marcos&lt;/a&gt;
    (Python)
  &lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li class=&quot;notion-bulleted_list_item notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://abhinavsarkar.net/notes/tags/advent-of-code/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Abhinav&lt;/a&gt;
    (Janet)
  &lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li class=&quot;notion-bulleted_list_item notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://scerruti.github.io/AoC2025/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Stephen&lt;/a&gt;
    (Java)
  &lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li class=&quot;notion-bulleted_list_item notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://nocto.weblog.lol/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Kirsty&lt;/a&gt;
    (Python)
  &lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li class=&quot;notion-bulleted_list_item notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://hamberg.no/erlend/tags/aoc.html&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Erlend&lt;/a&gt;
    (Lean 4)
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Big thanks to Eric for once again building these puzzles for us to solve and
  to Koodiklinikka, TurkuDev, Asteriski and Reaktor communities for solving
  these with me and discussing the solutions.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


    </content>
  </entry> 
  <entry>
    <title>I’m a tool builder at heart</title>
    <link href="https://hamatti.org/posts/im-a-tool-builder-at-heart/" />
    <updated>2025-12-13T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://hamatti.org/posts/im-a-tool-builder-at-heart/</id>
    <content type="html">
      
&lt;p&gt;
  Two things in the past week made me think about tools and how I enjoy building
  them — often more than doing the things those tools enable us to do.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;notion-heading_2 notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
  A follow up on my latest IndieWeb post
&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Earlier this week, I published
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://hamatti.org/posts/where-are-we-going-indieweb/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;my submission to IndieWeb Carnival&lt;/a&gt;
  and as part of discussion that sparked in Fediverse,
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://cyberplace.social/@khleedril/115696354441842911&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Khleedril commented&lt;/a&gt;:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;notion-quote notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
  I would argue that we don&#39;t need to talk about tools at all. They are a
  concrete implementation detail completely hidden by abstraction.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  This was a great comment as it touched on something I discussed in the
  original post: to me, IndieWeb as a community is primarily a community of tool
  builders. At least that’s who I want to find there and that’s what I want to
  geek out about with them.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Somebody needs to build the tools we use. The only way we can ignore them as
  implementation details is to let others — often corporates whose incentives
  don’t align with ours — to decide what tools we have and how we can use them.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  That’s a core value in IndieWeb community for me. It’s difficult to take
  ownership of data and content and the control of them if we don’t build tools
  that allow that.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Often when I talk about the non-corporate, non-commercial web, I prefer to
  talk about personal or small web instead of indie web (or IndieWeb) for this
  particular reason. I’m a strong believer in that side of things too. To me,
  those are communities or approaches that cover much wider group of people:
  users, creators (as in, artists, writers, etc) and builders (as in,
  technology).
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I’m especially excited about building those small indie tools: things that
  would never be commercially viable but that can solve problems of individuals
  or small groups.
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://notes.hamatti.org/technology/hobbit-software&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Hobbit software&lt;/a&gt;, if you will, or
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://hamatti.org/posts/home-cooked-situated-software/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;home-cooked, situated software&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;notion-heading_2 notion-color-default&quot;&gt;A wild tool idea appeared&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few days later the question popped into my head again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I was rewatching
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MCzAXR9LsUs&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Chrism360’s and Shenanagans’ old Pokemon Randomizer blind bingo race&lt;/a&gt;
  from 2018. In it, the players compete in achieving certain goals while playing
  randomized Pokémon Red. The catch is, they don’t know what those goals are and
  there’s a third person keeping track of the bingo card.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  As I was watching it, I realised many of the goals can be quite challenging to
  keep in mind and make sure the person keeping score catches them all.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Immediately, my mind went into a “what kind of software could be built to help
  make it easier” rabbit hole. I started thinking about how those goals could
  have data attached that define Pokémon, moves or items that satisfy the
  criteria.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Then, the scorekeeper could just keep a log of actions and events (like
  catching a new Pokémon, learning new moves, etc) and the system would take
  care of all the difficult parts: matching the actions and events with the
  goals and would update the score as things happen.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I’m much more interested in building those kinds of tools than I am of
  participating in such races as a player.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;notion-heading_2 notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
  I’ve always been like this
&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I became a community organiser because I realised at one point that I’m almost
  always more interested in the organising and being behind the scenes making
  stuff happen than I am with doing the thing itself.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Organising shares so many same traits as tool building. Both are about
  creating structure into chaos and making it easier for people to enjoy the
  thing they enjoy. Being able to tame that chaos into something easier to
  understand and deal with is what makes me tick in life.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  On the first day of my current job, I introduced myself to sales people as
  someone who likes to build tools for professionals.
&lt;/p&gt;


    </content>
  </entry> 
  <entry>
    <title>Where are we going, IndieWeb?</title>
    <link href="https://hamatti.org/posts/where-are-we-going-indieweb/" />
    <updated>2025-12-10T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://hamatti.org/posts/where-are-we-going-indieweb/</id>
    <content type="html">
      
&lt;p&gt;
  My dear internet friend and intellectual sparring partner V.H. Belvadi is
  hosting things month’s IndieWeb Carnival and is asking us:
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://vhbelvadi.com/indieweb-carnival-future&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;where do you see the IndieWeb in 2030&lt;/a&gt;:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;notion-quote notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
  Welcome to the last IndieWeb Carnival of 2025. Having been a part of this
  wonderful community for years now and having thought about the IndieWeb from
  various perspectives, I have plenty of ideas about where I hope we are headed
  in the near future. And I am sure you do too. So tell us,
  &lt;b class=&quot;notion-text-bold&quot;&gt;where do you see the IndieWeb in 2030,&lt;/b&gt; just
  five short years from now?
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  My relationship with the IndieWeb community has been rocky and ever-evolving
  and it was pretty much this IndieWeb Carnival thing that finally brought me
  into the community and got more excited about it. Even then, I think “indie
  web” as an alternative to building your online presence outside from
  commercial platforms is more important than “IndieWeb”, the specific
  community.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  One of the related key questions that I’ve been pondering a ton lately is
  &lt;b class=&quot;notion-text-bold&quot;&gt;what does the categorisation of “IndieWeb” mean &lt;/b&gt;so let’s start there.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;notion-heading_2 notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
  Category through belonging or focus
&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Whenever we build a community (or one forms accidentally by likeminded people
  gathering together), there are some sort of borders around the community.
  There are people who are part of it and people who are not. This definition
  then often influences what actions are taken, who is accepted into the
  community and where the community wants to go.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  A lot of the discussion related to IndieWeb happens around this definition
  too.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I see two ways of defining a community’s boundaries: 1) who gets to be part of
  it and 2) what the community’s focus is on. In public discussions, these two
  ways unfortunately mush together.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Belonging: who gets to be part of IndieWeb&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I want IndieWeb to be a community that’s welcoming everyone who wants to be
  part of it — regardless of their current situation. It’s really difficult to
  draw the line between “Indie” and “non-Indie” for example in case of a
  personal website.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  For example, where would you draw the line in this spectrum of options with
  blogs as an example:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;notion-bulleted_list&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;notion-bulleted_list_item notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
    Writing a blog in LinkedIn or Medium
  &lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li class=&quot;notion-bulleted_list_item notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
    Writing a blog in hosted WordPress, Pika, Bear or other
  &lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li class=&quot;notion-bulleted_list_item notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
    Writing a blog in self-hosted WordPress
  &lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li class=&quot;notion-bulleted_list_item notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
    Writing a blog in hosted service but with your own domain
  &lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li class=&quot;notion-bulleted_list_item notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
    Writing a blog with static site generator and hosting it on Netlify
  &lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li class=&quot;notion-bulleted_list_item notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
    Writing a blog with static site generator and self-hosting it on a VPS
  &lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li class=&quot;notion-bulleted_list_item notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
    Building your own blog engine and self-hosting it on a VPS
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IndieWeb wiki defines itself as&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;notion-quote notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
  We are a community of independent and personal websites based on the
  principles of: owning your domain and using it as your primary online
  identity, publishing on your own site first (optionally elsewhere), and owning
  your content.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I like those principles (and have written
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://hamatti.org/posts/indieweb-principles-and-i/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;my thoughts on all 12 principles&lt;/a&gt;) but even then, they are more aspirational than gatekeeping. You don’t have
  to own your own domain to get started with the community, you don’t need to
  implement Webmentions or microformats or many of the other technical wonders
  us IndieWeb folks rave about.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I want IndieWeb to be and to remain an open community where people can decide
  to be part of, regardless of how their website is built or hosted. I want the
  community to be inspiring and aspirational with its ideas and technical
  possibilities rather than limiting or gatekeeping.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Focus: what is the community about&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Focus and belonging can sometimes be at odds with each other on a face value.
  The tighter the focus on a single topic is, less open it would have to be to
  new people.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I often hear opinions that “IndieWeb is too technical” and that it’s keeping
  non-developer folks out.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;b class=&quot;notion-text-bold&quot;&gt;I think that’s okay.&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, IndieWeb is not the one and only option to corporate web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I’ve been thinking a lot whether we can have the “Indie” part without the “you
  need to make it yourself” part. At what point, does it turn from indie to
  commercial when we build tools and services that reduces or removes the
  technical portion.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I don’t mean this as a gatekeepy “you need to be this technical to get in” or
  “only real developers can be part of indie web”. Not at all.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I see two main technical challenges one needs to overcome to build and host
  their own website: they need to build the site and they need to deploy it
  somewhere. It’s really difficult to reduce these to a minimum without turning
  the entire thing into a commercial-ish service — and we have a lot of those
  ones already.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  If you just want a website and not worry about the technical bits, you could
  buy WordPress hosting from someone who sets WP up and start writing.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I don’t consider that any less indie in the terms of beloging (as I discussed
  in previous section) but there seems to be a big desire to have some options
  that would be “more indie” without being any more technical.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;notion-heading_2 notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
  I like the technical parts of IndieWeb
&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I’m a technical person and I love building my own tools and tinkering with
  stuff on Saturday evenings. For me, IndieWeb is a community that encourages
  that and helps me find other people who care about the same things.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;b class=&quot;notion-text-bold&quot;&gt;It’s more of a mindset than a skill check.&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I hope to invite new people into the community who want to learn how to build
  websites, to learn programming through building the websites and tools to run
  them and have an interest towards learning new things in general — and to
  share what they have learned.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  The best outcome is when the people involved in the community build better
  tools for everyone to use to make it easier to build and run their own sites.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;notion-heading_2 notion-color-default&quot;&gt;5 years from now?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I don’t know what we’ll be specifically in five years as Belvadi is asking. My
  “membership” of it is so loose that I don’t have strong opinions on anything
  practical.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope that the community stays open and welcoming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I hope it continues to encourage and inspire people to learn how to build the
  tools they need.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I hope it doesn’t take itself too seriously as the only or best option to
  commercial web.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  And I hope I’m still as excited (if not more) about building websites in five
  years.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr class=&quot;notion-divider&quot; /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks V.H. for hosting this month’s Carnival!&lt;/p&gt;


    </content>
  </entry> 
  <entry>
    <title>About writing and audience</title>
    <link href="https://hamatti.org/posts/about-writing-and-audience/" />
    <updated>2025-12-03T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://hamatti.org/posts/about-writing-and-audience/</id>
    <content type="html">
      &lt;blockquote class=&quot;notion-quote notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
  Would you still write if you had a single reader? And do you appreciate the
  readers you &lt;i class=&quot;notion-text-italic&quot;&gt;do&lt;/i&gt; have?
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Richard Griffiths asked these questions in his post
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://writingslowly.com/2025/11/16/why-niche-blogs-and-small.html&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Why niche blogs and Small Rooms still win - even in the age of
    technofeudalism&lt;/a&gt;. I read the post when it came out as it appeared in my RSS feed and was
  reminded about it again when Daniel Miller responded to it in
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://daniel.industries/2025/11/22/why-write-online/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Why Write Online?&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I love having discussions about the audience we write for. Because I think we
  &lt;b class=&quot;notion-text-bold&quot;&gt;worry too much about it.&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  To answer Richard’s original question: 100%. For most of the time I’ve had a
  blog, I’ve written to a basically non-existent audience. These days, my
  readership is way bigger than I can comprehend. I even have a second blog out
  there that I haven’t shared with anyone yet but I still enjoy using it as a
  creative outlet.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  The readers of this blog are people who like to read my stuff. Plain and
  simple. I don’t have a prescribed audience that I analyse and write what I
  think they want to read. I write what I have to share and people who like
  those things, join to read.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;notion-heading_2 notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
  Writing about professional topics
&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Earlier in my blogging journey, I did worry about it a bit. I knew that if I
  had written for a specific niche, I would have had a higher chance of
  attracting a larger audience, faster. A couple of articles that helped me
  realise it was a silly worry are
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://rachsmith.com/to-be-whole-is-the-goal/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Rach Smith’s To be whole is the goal&lt;/a&gt;
  and
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nateliason.com/blog/be-yourself&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Nat Eliason’s Be Yourself, Not a Niche&lt;/a&gt;. More recently, I’ve been introduced to
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://roytang.net/2023/06/write-anything/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Roy Tang’s You Can Write About Anything&lt;/a&gt;
  that discusses similar topics.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I have recently been talking about blogging to developer audiences in a bunch
  of events and I often get questions about my thoughts on the audience. One of
  my key messages is that you don’t necessarily need an audience for your blog
  posts to be powerful. If you document what you’ve learned and share what you
  know, you’ll have access to those posts when you need them.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  You can share a link to such post when someone asks for help or when you apply
  to a job. Building such body of work can be very powerful in building
  credibility and trust as an expert, if you blog about your professional
  interests. I have expanded these thoughts in
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://notes.hamatti.org/writing/why-developers-should-blog&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Why developers should blog?&lt;/a&gt;
  with links and quotes to other’s thoughts.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;notion-heading_2 notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
  Writing for yourself first
&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  In
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://hamatti.org/posts/notes-are-a-tool-for/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Notes are a tool for …&lt;/a&gt;, I wrote about different ways writing notes help me in daily life.
  Similarly, writing itself is a powerful tool to process and communicate ideas.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Even if nobody reads your posts, your writing improves your skills as a
  writer.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  You don’t have to dream about becoming an author to benefit from writing
  skills. In this day and age, communication is one of the key skills in many
  industries. Not only will you spend a larger share of your work day
  communicating when the higher up you are on the career ladder but becoming a
  great communicator can help you ascend the ladder faster, if that’s something
  you’d like to do.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  As a software developer, most of my technical posts are written for myself. I
  document what I learn so that I can find it later — sharing it with the world
  is a nice bonus benefit. If one person reads a post of mine and gets inspired
  by it or learns something new from it, it’s a massive upside. It makes me
  genuinely happy.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    </content>
  </entry> 
  <entry>
    <title>I built a tiny RSS generator for my Advent of Code solutions</title>
    <link href="https://hamatti.org/posts/i-built-a-tiny-rss-generator-for-my-advent-of-code-solutions/" />
    <updated>2025-12-02T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://hamatti.org/posts/i-built-a-tiny-rss-generator-for-my-advent-of-code-solutions/</id>
    <content type="html">
      &lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://hamatti.org/posts/your-blog-should-have-an-rss-feed/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;RSS/Atom feeds are one of the great technologies in the open web&lt;/a&gt;. They allow me to follow other people and them to follow me.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  This week, I started solving Advent of Code problems and this time I’m
  publishing my explanations as part of
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://notes.hamatti.org/technology/advent-of-code/2025/advent-of-code-2025-landing-page&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;my Digital Garden&lt;/a&gt;
  and that doesn’t support separated RSS feeds for a subset of notes.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Two IndieWeb principles that I love are
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://indieweb.org/make_what_you_need&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Make what you need&lt;/a&gt;
  and
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://indieweb.org/use_what_you_make&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Use what you make&lt;/a&gt;. In that spirit, I built a tiny tool today afterwork to enable people to
  follow my Advent of Code explanations via RSS.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  A bit of background: my personal website at
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://hamatti.org/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;https://hamatti.org&lt;/a&gt;
  is built with Eleventy (and a bunch of custom scripts) and my digital garden
  at
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://notes.hamatti.org/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;https://notes.hamatti.org&lt;/a&gt;
  is powered by notes in Obsidian and
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://quartz.jzhao.xyz/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Quartz&lt;/a&gt; that
  turns them to a website.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  To build this tiny RSS generator, I combined a Node.js script with Eleventy’s
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.11ty.dev/docs/data-global/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Global Data Files&lt;/a&gt;
  and
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.11ty.dev/docs/data/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;templating&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre class=&quot;language-javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-javascript&quot;&gt;const fs = require(&quot;fs&quot;);

function addEntry(entryUrl) {
  // Read existing JSON in
  const data = JSON.parse(fs.readFileSync(&quot;_data/aoc2025.json&quot;, &quot;utf-8&quot;));

  // Extract Advent of Code puzzle day from URL
  // URL looks like this:
  // https://notes.hamatti.org/technology/advent-of-code/2025/day-1
  // so capture the number from `day-1` part.
  const day = entryUrl.match(/day-(&#92;d+)/)[1];

  const today = new Date();

  // Add new feed entry
  data.entries.push({
    url: entryUrl,
    title: `Advent of Code 2025, day ${day}, explanation and solution.`,
    created: today,
  });

  // Update metadata
  data.updated = today;

  // Write new data to JSON file
  fs.writeFileSync(&quot;_data/aoc2025.json&quot;, JSON.stringify(data));
}

if (process.argv.length &amp;#60; 3) {
  console.log(&quot;Usage: npm run aocfeed [url-to-note]&quot;);
  process.exit(1);
}

addEntry(process.argv[2]);
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  It’s a tiny script that reads existing JSON, adds a new entry and writes it
  back.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Unfortunately I don’t yet have an easy way to add the full content since it’s
  not tied to my digital garden publishing pipeline but that can be an exercise
  for a day when I have more time.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  The data it writes looks like this, at
  &lt;code class=&quot;notion-text-code&quot;&gt;_data/aoc2025.json&lt;/code&gt; :
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre class=&quot;language-json&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-json&quot;&gt;{
  &quot;entries&quot;: [
    {
      &quot;url&quot;: &quot;https://notes.hamatti.org/technology/advent-of-code/2025/day-1&quot;,
      &quot;title&quot;: &quot;Advent of Code 2025, day 1, explanation and solution.&quot;,
      &quot;created&quot;: &quot;2025-12-02T15:17:43.981Z&quot;
    },
    {
      &quot;url&quot;: &quot;https://notes.hamatti.org/technology/advent-of-code/2025/day-2&quot;,
      &quot;title&quot;: &quot;Advent of Code 2025, day 2, explanation and solution.&quot;,
      &quot;created&quot;: &quot;2025-12-02T15:17:58.315Z&quot;
    }
  ],
  &quot;updated&quot;: &quot;2025-12-02T15:17:58.315Z&quot;
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and I have a feed template like this&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre class=&quot;language-html&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-html&quot;&gt;---
permalink: feed/aoc2025.xml
excludeFromSitemap: true
---
&amp;#60;?xml version=&quot;1.0&quot; encoding=&quot;utf-8&quot;?&amp;#62;
&amp;#60;feed xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom&quot;&amp;#62;
  &amp;#60;title&amp;#62;Advent of Code 2025 - Solutions and explanations by Juhis&amp;#60;/title&amp;#62;
  &amp;#60;link href=&quot;https://hamatti.org/feed/aoc2025.xml&quot; rel=&quot;self&quot; /&amp;#62;
  &amp;#60;link href=&quot;https://notes.hamatti.org/technology/advent-of-code/2025/advent-of-code-2025-landing-page&quot; /&amp;#62;
  &amp;#60;updated&amp;#62;{{aoc2025.updated}}&amp;#60;/updated&amp;#62;
  &amp;#60;id&amp;#62;https://hamatti.org/feed/aoc2025.xml&amp;#60;/id&amp;#62;
  &amp;#60;author&amp;#62;
    &amp;#60;name&amp;#62;{{ metadata.author.name }}&amp;#60;/name&amp;#62;
    &amp;#60;email&amp;#62;{{ metadata.author.email }}&amp;#60;/email&amp;#62;
  &amp;#60;/author&amp;#62;
  {%- for entry in aoc2025.entries | reverse | limit(30) %}
  &amp;#60;entry&amp;#62;
    &amp;#60;title&amp;#62;{{entry.title}}&amp;#60;/title&amp;#62;
    &amp;#60;link href=&quot;{{ entry.url }}&quot; /&amp;#62;
    &amp;#60;updated&amp;#62;{{ entry.created }}&amp;#60;/updated&amp;#62;
    &amp;#60;id&amp;#62;{{entry.url}}&amp;#60;/id&amp;#62;
    &amp;#60;content type=&quot;html&quot;&amp;#62;
      {{entry.title}}
    &amp;#60;/content&amp;#62;
  &amp;#60;/entry&amp;#62;
  {%- endfor %}
&amp;#60;/feed&amp;#62;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Which reads data from the
  &lt;code class=&quot;notion-text-code&quot;&gt;aoc2025.json&lt;/code&gt; file and populates a feed
  whenever I call Eleventy to create a new build.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I’ve published a new note, I run&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre class=&quot;language-shell&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-shell&quot;&gt;node _scripts/updateAdventOfCodeFeed.js [url-to-note]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and push changes to my website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Once that deploy is done, users can follow my Advent of Code via
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://hamatti.org/feed/aoc2025.xml&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;https://hamatti.org/feed/aoc2025.xml&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;

    </content>
  </entry> 
  <entry>
    <title>From Juhis with Love #011 - November of learning</title>
    <link href="https://hamatti.org/posts/external-from-juhis-with-love-011-november-of-learning/" />
    <updated>2025-11-30T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://hamatti.org/posts/external-from-juhis-with-love-011-november-of-learning/</id>
    <content type="html">
      
&lt;p&gt;
  In November issue of &lt;strong&gt;From Juhis with Love&lt;/strong&gt;, I share updates of my
  projects and lovely bits from the internet.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://buttondown.com/juhis/archive/011-november-of-learning/&quot;&gt;Read #011 - November of learning&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;

    </content>
  </entry> 
  <entry>
    <title>One thing I’d like to change about Pokémon TCG</title>
    <link href="https://hamatti.org/posts/one-thing-id-like-to-change-about-pokemon-tcg/" />
    <updated>2025-11-29T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://hamatti.org/posts/one-thing-id-like-to-change-about-pokemon-tcg/</id>
    <content type="html">
      &lt;p&gt;
  Youtube channel
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/post/UgkxncbEjzh153fyjf55hIG0xxVvyAX52vGE&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Control Players Unite posted a poll&lt;/a&gt;
  with a question and four options
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://hamatti.org/assets/img/posts/one-thing-id-like-to-change-about-pokemon-tcg/1.png.webp&quot; alt=&quot;A Youtube poll from Control Players Unite. The question and answer options are described below. &quot; /&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;notion-quote notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
  Of the following, if you could change ONE thing about the Pokémon TCG, it
  would be…
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;with the options of&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;notion-bulleted_list&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;notion-bulleted_list_item notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
    The prize check rule — let us look at them already!
  &lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li class=&quot;notion-bulleted_list_item notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
    The power creep — why on earth am I hitting 230 for 1 energy?
  &lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li class=&quot;notion-bulleted_list_item notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
    Best of 1 rules (especially relevant for control play)
  &lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li class=&quot;notion-bulleted_list_item notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
    Something to fix slow play
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  All four make sense so let’s go through all options and why or how they should
  be fixed.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;notion-heading_2 notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
  Eliminating prize checking
&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  In Pokémon TCG, at the start of each game, you put aside 6 random cards as
  “prize cards”. You are not allowed to look at them and each time you knock out
  opponent’s Pokémon, you get to pick some prizes (usually at least…).
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prize cards create an extra level of randomness and require you to&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;notion-bulleted_list&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;notion-bulleted_list_item notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
    build your deck in a way where prizing something important doesn’t
    completely ruin your game plan and
  &lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li class=&quot;notion-bulleted_list_item notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
    adapt your gameplay based on your prizes
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Still, the current system creates a problem. Players, especially in higher
  competitive play, want to know what their prizes are so they spend (and are
  allowed to spend) quite a lot of time during their first deck search going
  through their remaining cards to deduce which 6 cards they don’t have access
  to.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  A tournament game of Pokémon is played as best of three wins with a time limit
  of usually 50 minutes.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I mostly play casual so this isn’t really a problem for me. I don’t prize
  check a lot myself — I usually make sure I know how many energies I have
  available and check a couple of the most important cards. In casual play, we
  also don’t generally play with time limits so I’m only exposed to this when
  watching official streams.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I really like what
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/@ComebackMechs&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Comeback Mechanics&lt;/a&gt;
  group do in their Gym Leader Challenge matches. They have a custom houserule
  (that they call Matty’s Map) that allows the player to look at their prizes
  when they search their deck for the first time.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://hamatti.org/assets/img/posts/one-thing-id-like-to-change-about-pokemon-tcg/2.png.webp&quot; alt=&quot;A custom Pokemon TCG Item card named Matty’s Map that reads: You can only use this card during your first deck search. Look at your face-down prize cards. Then, shuffle your face-down prize cards. &quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  This gives the player same knowledge than rigorously going through their deck
  but in fraction of time.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Some people argue that efficiently checking your prizes is a skill and they
  don’t want that skill requirement reduced from the game. I can understand
  where they come from but I do disagree. Especially in a game where the game
  clock is shared and there’s no individual clocks like in chess.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  In a game that goes to full 3 matches, if both players spend a couple of
  minutes checking for prizes, that’s easily over 10 minutes out of the general
  play time just to check for prizes. For example, the first deck search in a
  recent Latin America International Championship’s 2nd day stream lasted 3.5
  minutes.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Being able to check your prizes and make notes would cut these early game
  searches short and would speed up the game. I think it would be a good
  tradeoff for the game.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;notion-heading_2 notion-color-default&quot;&gt;The power creep&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I chose the power creep as my answer in the poll. Even though I think prize
  checking would be beneficial for the game, I really wish the game’s balance
  would change.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I’ve been lately enjoying my share of retro Pokémon — especially
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://jklaczpokemon.com/ex/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;RS-PK format&lt;/a&gt;
  from early 2000s. It’s a format I never played when it was the active format
  but I highly prefer it over the current standard format.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  The biggest thing is that there’s very few one hit KO options. The game is
  slower, requires better board management and you need to make — in my opinion
  — more interesting decisions constantly because it’s hard to get rid of all of
  your opponent’s threats in one turn. So you have to think about how you
  balance between building your board and being aggressive to chase knockouts.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  It’s no wonder why that format has grown to be probably the most played retro
  format. It doesn’t have quite as broken trainers as the early years and it’s
  not full of 3-prize Pokémon and one hit KOs like modern standard format.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I really wished that Pokémon Company had learned their lesson after the
  previous 3-prize cards like Tag Team and VMAX Pokémon but somehow they managed
  to bring the concept back with the newest iteration of Mega evolutions.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  This is also why I like casual
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://gymleaderchallenge.com/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Gym Leader Challenge&lt;/a&gt;. While some people play the format similarly to modern standard — going full
  meta and trying to find the best deck in the format — there’s a lot of
  opportunities to play the format in a slower pace, utilising cards you
  wouldn’t otherwise play.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I’ve also been enjoying playing
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://notes.hamatti.org/gaming/board-games/pokemon/scarlet--and--violet-progression-series&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Progression Series&lt;/a&gt;
  with our local game group. Your card pool in it is limited so you can’t put 4
  copies of the best card and 4 of each card that supports it to build super
  consistent decks. You need to make do with what you have and that slows down
  the game a lot.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;notion-heading_2 notion-color-default&quot;&gt;Best of 1 rules&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I’m not sure what the author of the poll means with the better best of 1 rules
  but I think this game doesn’t lend to the format that well, especially in a
  competitive format. The game is too prone for donking (winning the game in
  turn 1 or 2 by knocking out all your opponent’s Pokémon before they manage to
  set up) that it feels it would create a very volatile format with luck playing
  even bigger role.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Maybe that could be solved by some of the better rules but especially right
  now (see previous section), the game is so fast that I’m worried it would lead
  to even less varied meta game. W consistent early game setup (likely with big
  basics) becomes a crucial part of not getting donked, the game loses a lot of
  it charm.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;notion-heading_2 notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
  Something to fix slow play
&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Game is played in best of 3 format but finishing 3 games in 50 minutes is a
  lot to ask. In the recent
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://labs.limitlesstcg.com/0046/pairings&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Latin America Internationals&lt;/a&gt;, each round, 15-21% of the games finished in a draw. That’s a lot. And I
  couldn’t find data on how many games ended 1-0 with even the second game not
  having time to finish but it’s a non-zero amount.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Prize checking is one part of the problem but even without it, it’s too easy
  for the games to run long.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I don’t have good solutions though. It’s not something that really affects me
  because we don’t really have sanctioned tournaments here and when playing
  casually over a couple of beers, slow play is usually a result of chatting
  about life and it’s always worth it.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  For competitive play at the highest level, I think chess clocks could be an
  option. Give each player their own time budget. It’s very easy in Pokémon TCG,
  within its rules, to manipulate the clock and speed up or slow down the game.
  A clock could help with that as it would deincentivize slow play. Everytime
  someone brings it up though, the community gets up and arms so I’m not gonna
  champion the idea any further.
&lt;/p&gt;

    </content>
  </entry> 
  <entry>
    <title>Improve your programming skills with Advent of Code</title>
    <link href="https://hamatti.org/posts/improve-your-programming-skills-with-advent-of-code/" />
    <updated>2025-11-26T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://hamatti.org/posts/improve-your-programming-skills-with-advent-of-code/</id>
    <content type="html">
      &lt;p&gt;
  Next Monday we turn our calendars to December and for us software developers
  it means Advent of Code starts again, for the 11th year. This year, there are
  some new changes though that will hopefully make it more approachable to many
  people.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;notion-heading_2 notion-color-default&quot;&gt;What is Advent of Code?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Advent of Code is an annual Christmas calendar of programming puzzles that you
  can solve anyway you wish, created by Eric Wastl. You can choose your tools,
  programming languages and approaches: some people try to solve them as quickly
  or as efficiently as possible; others use the time to learn a new programming
  language or challenge them to solve them in ways that restrict what is
  available to them. One of the best parts of Advent of Code is that you get to
  choose how to do it.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Each day, you’ll receive a puzzle and an input. For example, let’s take a look
  at the first day of last year’s calendar,
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://adventofcode.com/2024/day/1&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;day 1 of 2024&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  There’s a bit of lore to get you into the right Christmas mood — usually Santa
  has disappeared or something important has gone missing or broken and it is
  our job to help the elves through solving puzzles to save Christmas.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For that puzzle, you receive an input that looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre class=&quot;language-plain text&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plain text&quot;&gt;3   4
4   3
2   5
1   3
3   9
3   3&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and a task:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;notion-quote notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
  Pair up the
  &lt;i class=&quot;notion-text-italic&quot;&gt;smallest number in the left list&lt;/i&gt; with the
  &lt;i class=&quot;notion-text-italic&quot;&gt;smallest number in the right list&lt;/i&gt;, then the
  &lt;i class=&quot;notion-text-italic&quot;&gt;second-smallest left number&lt;/i&gt; with the
  &lt;i class=&quot;notion-text-italic&quot;&gt;second-smallest right number&lt;/i&gt;, and so on.
  Within each pair, figure out
  &lt;i class=&quot;notion-text-italic&quot;&gt;how far apart&lt;/i&gt; the two numbers are; you&#39;ll
  need to &lt;i class=&quot;notion-text-italic&quot;&gt;add up all of those distances&lt;/i&gt;.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  You then write code that takes the provided input, solves it and outputs a
  single number. Everyone gets their own custom generated input so you can’t
  just copy an answer from a friend but need to generate it by yourself using
  your input.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Once you solve a puzzle successfully, a second part is revealed. It usually
  introduces &lt;i class=&quot;notion-text-italic&quot;&gt;a twist&lt;/i&gt; — maybe you need to
  calculate something more complex or some parameters of the puzzle change,
  challenging you to solve a similar but slightly different puzzle.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  For the first decade, we got 50 of these puzzles: 2 for every day from
  December 1st to December 25th, often increasing in complexity or difficulty.
  This year,
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://adventofcode.com/2025/about#faq_num_days&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Eric decided to only have 12 days of puzzles&lt;/a&gt;, making the entire ordeal a bit easier to chew:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;notion-quote notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
  &lt;i class=&quot;notion-text-italic&quot;&gt;Why did the number of days per event change?&lt;/i&gt;
  It takes a ton of my free time every year to run Advent of Code, and building
  the puzzles accounts for the majority of that time. After keeping a consistent
  schedule for ten years(!), I needed a change. The puzzles still start on
  December 1st so that the day numbers make sense (Day 1 = Dec 1), and puzzles
  come out every day (ending mid-December).
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I welcome this change with open arms. Quite often, around 18th or 19th, real
  life Christmas preparations start to take up the time from the calendar and as
  the complexity of the puzzles grow, I’ve found it has become more and more
  challenging to find time to solve the last problems.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;You can solve them as you wish&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  You don’t have to solve the days in order: the next day will be available even
  if you haven’t solved the previous ones. You also don’t have to solve all of
  them or do one each day. I often see people drop out because they missed a day
  and feel like the backlog starts to grow unmanageable.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I understand where that sentiment comes from but I want to encourage everyone
  to participate, skip the days that are too hard or too busy and continue from
  the next day. There are rarely part 1 puzzles that have any connection to
  previous ones and never any that cannot be solved if you haven’t solved the
  previous.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;notion-heading_2 notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
  Best part is the community
&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Solving puzzles is fun and all but the real treat is the friends we make along
  the way. Every year, I come back to Advent of Code because it’s so nice to do
  together. In pretty much every developer community I’m part of, we have a
  forum/Slack/Discord threads for each day, asking for help, sharing our
  solutions and generally getting excited about the puzzles.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  We also organise in person gatherings where we solve puzzles and have a good
  time.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  The flexibility of Advent of Code fits this kind of community approach so
  well. One person can solve puzzles in Java, another in Rust and third in
  Python and they can share ideas and solutions and learn together even when
  they don’t share a single programming language.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  It’s also fun to see how different programming languages fit different types
  of puzzles.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;notion-heading_2 notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
  I use Advent of Code to teach programming
&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  My approach for the past few years has been to solve the puzzles using Python
  and then write about my solutions and tools I use with the intention of
  teaching programming and Python to new audiences and to inspire new people to
  participate.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I think Advent of Code can be a brilliant way for new developers to get a lot
  of practice. The puzzles are well written and don’t require any specific tools
  or libraries. Basic programming language constructs can get you there. And
  since all previous years’ puzzles are always open, there’s a decade’s worth of
  puzzles to practice on if you get excited about AoC this year.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  You can find my previous solutions from
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://hamatti.org/adventofcode&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;/adventofcode&lt;/a&gt;,
  categorised by year.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  You can also
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://hamatti.org/blog/advent-of-code/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;read more blog posts about Advent of Code&lt;/a&gt;
  if you want to pick up my general tips and tricks for making Advent of Code a
  great experience.
&lt;/p&gt;

    </content>
  </entry> 
  <entry>
    <title>My Debugging Python talk from PyCon Finland published</title>
    <link href="https://hamatti.org/posts/my-debugging-python-talk-from-pycon-finland-published/" />
    <updated>2025-11-21T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://hamatti.org/posts/my-debugging-python-talk-from-pycon-finland-published/</id>
    <content type="html">
      
&lt;img src=&quot;https://hamatti.org/assets/img/posts/my-debugging-python-talk-from-pycon-finland-published/1.png.webp&quot; alt=&quot;A cityscape behind a lake with a massive illustrated yellow rubber duck floating in it and text Debugging Python - what to do when computer says no written on the sky&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This past October, I spoke in PyCon Finland about debugging Python.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Kep3kN2Ay04&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Video of the talk&lt;/a&gt;
  has now been released in Plone’s Youtube channel.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I also have the talk in
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://hamatti.org/posts/debugging-python/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;blog post format as Debugging Python&lt;/a&gt;
  and I wrote about my experience in the event in
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://hamatti.org/posts/pycon-finland-2025-recap&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;PyCon Finland 2025 recap&lt;/a&gt;
  if you want a peek into the event as a whole.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  You can find
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLGN9BI-OAQkR3wuMu0ZepeEwyI88ber22&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;other PyCon Finland talks from the playlist&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;

    </content>
  </entry> 
  <entry>
    <title>Eulogy to my old laptop</title>
    <link href="https://hamatti.org/posts/eulogy-to-my-old-laptop/" />
    <updated>2025-11-19T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://hamatti.org/posts/eulogy-to-my-old-laptop/</id>
    <content type="html">
      &lt;p&gt;
  I recently purchased a new laptop and it’s been a joy. This means I’m letting
  my old laptop retire after 7.5 years — out of which the last 4 years or so it
  was already broken af.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  My previous laptop was a late-2017 Macbook Pro. We started our shared journey
  at my job and after it was time to update the work laptop, I was able to
  purchase the old laptop for personal use, replacing my then ~7 year old
  laptop.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  There’s this push in tech to be constantly replacing your devices. We are to
  think that after 3 years or so, an old device is useless and you should
  upgrade to a newer version. I think that’s absurd. While my devices haven’t
  quite survived to celebrate a 10 year anniversary, I’m rather happy I’ve
  managed to use both of them for over 7 years.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  At the moment of retirement, my laptop was in a rough condition. I had lost
  many keys from the keyboard and even many of those still hanging on had
  started to have issues where they’d register multiple presses so it was
  completely unusable. The touch bar (remember those, thank heavens they decided
  to stop adding them) was in perpetual disco mode: it keeps flashing like a
  strobe light at a rave and I wasn’t able to find a way to turn it off. The
  battery lasted around 10 seconds at best. And it had gotten really slow.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  It essentially spent its last years as a docked laptop at my desk and I was
  forced to use
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://notes.hamatti.org/technology/ipad-and-raspberry-pi-setup&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;my iPad with a Raspberry Pi as my mobile workstation&lt;/a&gt;. It wasn’t the optimal thing but it was the financially responsible one.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  But despite its rough last moments, we had a lot of great moments together. We
  traveled across Europe to speak in developer conferences and meetups. We
  traveled in Finland, to Sweden, Denmark, Estonia, Germany, The Netherlands and
  Czechia to show my presentations to many lovely software developers.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I wrote hundreds of blog posts and built dozens of hobby projects on this
  laptop.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://hamatti.org/assets/img/posts/eulogy-to-my-old-laptop/1.png.webp&quot; alt=&quot;A Macbook cover with a ton of stickers &quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I love laptop stickers and looking back at my old laptops, they remind me of
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://hamatti.org/posts/stickers-tell-stories/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;so many stories and memories&lt;/a&gt;. Most of my stickers are from events, communities and organisations that
  matter to me. Some I’ve worked on and others I’ve been either speaking in or
  participating and enjoying.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    </content>
  </entry> 
  <entry>
    <title>I designed a 3D printed photo caddy insert for Tiny Epic Galaxies</title>
    <link href="https://hamatti.org/posts/i-designed-a-3d-printed-photo-caddy-insert-for-tiny-epic-galaxies/" />
    <updated>2025-11-12T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://hamatti.org/posts/i-designed-a-3d-printed-photo-caddy-insert-for-tiny-epic-galaxies/</id>
    <content type="html">
      
&lt;p&gt;
  Last week, I added
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/163967/tiny-epic-galaxies&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Tiny Epic Galaxies&lt;/a&gt;
  to
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://hamatti.org/tabletop/collection&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;my tabletop games collection&lt;/a&gt;. I’ve been enjoying the game for a long time but never owned a copy until
  now.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  The game comes in a nice small box but as is usual for retail board games, the
  boxes are just a bottom and a cover and my experience with those is that they
  tend to open on their own in the bag, spilling all of the pieces around in my
  bag.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;notion-heading_2 notion-color-default&quot;&gt;Starting point&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  First, I printed
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.printables.com/model/534518-tiny-epic-galaxies-insert-v2-now&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;an insert that fits the original box&lt;/a&gt;
  as I found a nice looking one. However, after the first evening of carrying
  the game, I noticed the tokens had flown all around inside the box.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://hamatti.org/assets/img/posts/i-designed-a-3d-printed-photo-caddy-insert-for-tiny-epic-galaxies/1.png&quot; alt=&quot;A Tiny Epic Galaxies board game box with a custom white 3D printed insert that has individual space for cards, dice and tokens. The tokens are bit all over the place and have been mixed up instead of staying in their crevices. &quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  It wasn’t very easy to get tokens in and out of the tight spaces without
  turning the entire box upside down. I think it’s still a nice insert
  especially if you want to use the original box.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;notion-heading_2 notion-color-default&quot;&gt;My own insert&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  When I got home, I decided to design my own insert that would fit a photo
  caddy box. I purchased a carrying case with 16 such boxes a while back and
  have been putting my small games in them to build a collection where it’s easy
  to pick them up and go.
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://hamatti.org/posts/shrink-designing-board-games/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Some examples are in an earlier blog post&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I took a lot of inspiration from aforementioned insert by The Cyberpunk Raven,
  splitting the insert into cards holder, dice section and space for tokens.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I made two options for holding the tokens:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://hamatti.org/assets/img/posts/i-designed-a-3d-printed-photo-caddy-insert-for-tiny-epic-galaxies/2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Two narrow white 3D printed containers, filled with small blue and red wooden tokens. &quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  In the first option, you can print 5 smaller containers, one per each player.
  These slot into the token space, can be taken out to distribute to players
  (easier to empty by turning upside down) and then put back after finishing
  games.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://hamatti.org/assets/img/posts/i-designed-a-3d-printed-photo-caddy-insert-for-tiny-epic-galaxies/3.png&quot; alt=&quot;An orange 3D printed insert for Tiny Epic Galaxies inside a transparent plastic photo caddy box. On the left side area of the insert, there’s a smaller, grey box. &quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  The other option uses
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.printables.com/model/1218292-mini-pocket-slide-box-5cm-7cm-9cm-h15cm&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;TuTu’s Mini Pocket Slide Boxes&lt;/a&gt;
  (9cm x 5cm version) if you don’t want to have individual containers for
  pieces.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I actually started with the latter solution but then decided to also make
  individual containers when I decided to post my model into Printables.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;notion-heading_2 notion-color-default&quot;&gt;The model&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://hamatti.org/assets/img/posts/i-designed-a-3d-printed-photo-caddy-insert-for-tiny-epic-galaxies/4.png&quot; alt=&quot;An orange 3D printed insert for Tiny Epic Galaxies inside a transparent plastic photo caddy box. On the left side area of the insert, there’s are 5 narrow white containers with tokens separated into them by five colours: green, yellow, red, blue and black. &quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I’ve
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.printables.com/model/1474154-tiny-epic-galaxies-insert-for-photo-caddy&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;posted the model into Printables&lt;/a&gt;
  if you want to print one for yourself. I’m happy to receive feedback but can’t
  make any promises for improvements as my modeling skills are rather limited.
  It’s published with
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;a permissive license&lt;/a&gt;
  (CC BY-SA 4.0) though so if you’re able to make your own changes, I encourage
  remixing and sharing. The only requirements in the license are to attribute to
  the original model and to maintain the same license with remixes.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;notion-heading_2 notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
  Putting the original case into good use
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://hamatti.org/assets/img/posts/i-designed-a-3d-printed-photo-caddy-insert-for-tiny-epic-galaxies/5.png&quot; alt=&quot;A 3D printed Tiny Epic Galaxies player mat overlay on a playmat with green tokens and spaceships on top. &quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Since the original case is still good and valid, I use it to store these
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.printables.com/model/78555-tiny-epic-galaxies-board-game-player-mat-overlay&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;player mat overlays&lt;/a&gt;
  by Sherri. I won’t take them with me as I travel but they are a nice premium
  when playing at home to avoid the pieces from moving around on the playmat.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The original designer explains the need very well:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;notion-quote notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
  I created this print because the popular board game, “Tiny Epic Galaxies”
  player mat/playing pieces have a very low friction coefficient. During game
  play it is common for the pieces to slide from their proper position into an
  adjacent space requiring the player&#39;s constant attention and detracting from
  the game play experience. In order to prevent this accidental movement I
  created an overly that the player mat is inserted into without destroying the
  card or harming the mat in any way.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They are quite thick: 5 overlays take up the entire original box.&lt;/p&gt;


    </content>
  </entry> 
  <entry>
    <title>What’s the story my front page tells?</title>
    <link href="https://hamatti.org/posts/whats-the-story-my-front-page-tells/" />
    <updated>2025-11-08T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://hamatti.org/posts/whats-the-story-my-front-page-tells/</id>
    <content type="html">
      &lt;p&gt;
  Last week,
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://vhbelvadi.com/the-homepage-quandary&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;V.H. Belvadi wrote about the homepage quandary&lt;/a&gt;, stating
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;notion-quote notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
  In my humble opinion the single most difficult part of a personal website to
  design properly is the homepage. This is especially true when your website is
  not limited to a single showcase. Programmers writing about code might simply
  list their latest work; artists and photographers might provide a grid of
  their projects straightaway; people who rarely update their website might
  treat it as a business card. These come with their own challenges but one
  challenge they do not face is what to put on their home page: quite simply
  their content dictates this.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I totally agree with his statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a generalist like me, it’s definitely a difficult task.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  General wisdom is that you want to have tight focus and preferably one “call
  to action”, i.e what you want the reader to do. But that’s all
  business-jargony and as much as I am a generalist with multiple interests, the
  visitors to my site come from a wide variety of people, interested in
  different things.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Some might say that’s a problematic situation and I worried about it for my
  fair share in the past but then I embraced the fact that I don’t have to write
  and build for a niche (I’ll link to
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://rachsmith.com/to-be-whole-is-the-goal/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Rach Smith’s great To be whole is the goal&lt;/a&gt;
  and recommend also reading
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nateliason.com/blog/be-yourself&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Nat Eliason’s Be yourself, not a niche&lt;/a&gt;
  on the topic).
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  So I split my front page into “cards”, all sharing one aspect, sub page or
  project.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the time of writing, this includes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;notion-bulleted_list&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;notion-bulleted_list_item notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
    “hero section” with a short introduction to who I am and links to my social
    accounts
  &lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li class=&quot;notion-bulleted_list_item notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
    a testimonial video I hired a video production company to do where they
    interviewed 6 wonderful human beings I’ve had the pleasure to work with
  &lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li class=&quot;notion-bulleted_list_item notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
    my latest blog post
  &lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li class=&quot;notion-bulleted_list_item notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
    my digital garden
  &lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li class=&quot;notion-bulleted_list_item notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
    my From Juhis with Love newsletter
  &lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li class=&quot;notion-bulleted_list_item notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
    most recent Advent of Code solutions
  &lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li class=&quot;notion-bulleted_list_item notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
    my older Syntax Error newsletter
  &lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li class=&quot;notion-bulleted_list_item notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
    my Potluck playing cards design project
  &lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li class=&quot;notion-bulleted_list_item notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
    my now mostly outdated Weeklies
  &lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li class=&quot;notion-bulleted_list_item notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
    Turku ❤️ Frontend community
  &lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li class=&quot;notion-bulleted_list_item notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
    archipylago Python community
  &lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li class=&quot;notion-bulleted_list_item notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
    developer community show Codebase
  &lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li class=&quot;notion-bulleted_list_item notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
    Pokemon TCG digital toolkit
  &lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li class=&quot;notion-bulleted_list_item notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
    conference/meetup speaker stuff
  &lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li class=&quot;notion-bulleted_list_item notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
    Helsinki Dev Lunch that I used to run
  &lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li class=&quot;notion-bulleted_list_item notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
    Dev Breakfast Newsletter I used to run
  &lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li class=&quot;notion-bulleted_list_item notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
    a talk about communities in marketing
  &lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li class=&quot;notion-bulleted_list_item notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
    more testimonials
  &lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li class=&quot;notion-bulleted_list_item notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
    let’s get in touch section
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  The common thread is that they are things
  &lt;b class=&quot;notion-text-bold&quot;&gt;I’m most proud of.&lt;/b&gt; My website is one part
  portfolio, one part digital home, one part a platform for my creativity. It’s
  as complex and multifaceted as I am.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Every now and then I go through and remove sections that I think are not
  relevant anymore and add new ones.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I wish that if someone early on in their career lands on my site after a
  workshop, a lecture or a talk, they’ll find inspiring and educational stuff
  that will lead them forward in their path.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  If someone who’s looking to hire great people lands on my site, they’ll get a
  strong sense of my skills as a technology generalist and be impressed by it
  and reach out.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  If someone who’s looking for a speaker to their event lands on my site,
  they’ll see what I’ve done before and how I communicate and it will lead to
  them choosing me to give a talk or host a workshop.
&lt;/p&gt;

    </content>
  </entry> 
  <entry>
    <title>My writing inspiration lives through cycles</title>
    <link href="https://hamatti.org/posts/my-writing-inspiration-lives-through-cycles/" />
    <updated>2025-11-05T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://hamatti.org/posts/my-writing-inspiration-lives-through-cycles/</id>
    <content type="html">
      &lt;p&gt;
  Alex is hosting this month’s
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://indieweb.org/IndieWeb_Carnival&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;IndieWeb Carnival&lt;/a&gt;
  with
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://alexsirac.com/indieweb-carnival-%e2%88%92-cycles-and-fluctuations/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;a theme of cycles and fluctuations&lt;/a&gt;:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;notion-quote notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
  There’s one more cycle I need to talk about today: the monthly IndieWeb
  Carnival cycle. Because here we are: it’s my turn to host! Let’s talk about
  cycles and fluctuations and give our world just a little more grace.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I’m currently in a really tough creative rut when it comes to writing. For the
  past couple of months, I’ve been struggling to work on any of the writing
  projects I want to work on. I have ideas and I’ve worked on those ideas to
  make it easier to start. Then I sit down and start writing and I barely manage
  to write a paragraph and I hate even that lone paragraph.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  My writing inspiration fluctuates a lot: sometimes I can write for days and
  sometimes even getting through a short note makes me agonise about everything.
  Back in my university days, whenever I sat down to work on my bachelor’s
  thesis (which I never finished), I felt the same despair. It felt like writing
  a single paragraph took everything out of me and still the end result wasn’t
  satisfactory.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Over the years, thanks to writing in this blog and participating in writing
  festivals like
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://hamatti.org/blog/blaugust&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Blaugust&lt;/a&gt; has really
  helped me transition from inspiration-driven writing to
  sit-down-and-just-write type of workflow. I’ve gotten quite good at it and
  it’s been a massive factor in the fact that I rather casually publish way over
  100 pieces a year (for the second year in a row!) without sacrificing the
  quality.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I have a couple of bigger writing projects that I’ve been trying to get
  started this fall but so far I have less than 1000 words on each and I don’t
  know if it’s due to a lack of direction and clarity or due to my struggles
  with writing in general right now.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Despite years of ups and downs, forward movement and time standing still, I
  still haven’t quite figured out how to get out of the rut. I don’t know if
  time will fix it on its own or if I need to do something to get my creative
  juices flowing and rekindle the joy of writing.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Sometimes the smart thing to do is to take a break. Doing something completely
  different usually helps get tangled mind untangled, to get some distance
  between yourself and the problem and to see things from new perspectives. But
  it’s hard to do when I still &lt;b class=&quot;notion-text-bold&quot;&gt;want&lt;/b&gt; to write.
  And I’ve gotten quite attached to my weekly blogging streak — which probably
  is the sign that it needs to break because streaks can become obsessions and
  obsessions are rarely good for you.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  On the other hand, Rachael Cayley has written about
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://explorationsofstyle.com/2018/02/22/write-your-way-out/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;writer’s block&lt;/a&gt;
  in a way that resonates with me a lot:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;notion-quote notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
  When we diagnose ourselves as having writer’s block, we can start to believe
  that we aren’t currently able to write. If you find yourself with a sore leg,
  it may well be that avoiding walking is a sound strategy. If you find yourself
  unable to write, might it be a sound strategy to avoid writing? The answer to
  that question is almost always no. Not writing has little-to-no curative
  power, in my experience.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I find that maintaining a rhythm of writing and a forward-moving momentum is
  what helps me write more. Writing inspires writing. Except when everything I
  manage to write makes me cringe and wonder how I’ve ever been able to write
  beautiful sentences and wonderful paragraphs.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  One thing’s for sure: I can’t wait to move on from this part of the cycle,
  back into the bliss of writing where words come to life and take control of
  themselves and my fingers on a keyboard or grabbing a pen are just a vehicle
  for the words to appear and join each other for a dance.
&lt;/p&gt;

    </content>
  </entry> 
  <entry>
    <title>From Juhis with Love #010 - A wonderful October</title>
    <link href="https://hamatti.org/posts/external-from-juhis-with-love-010-a-wonderful-october/" />
    <updated>2025-11-01T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://hamatti.org/posts/external-from-juhis-with-love-010-a-wonderful-october/</id>
    <content type="html">
      
&lt;p&gt;
  In October issue of &lt;strong&gt;From Juhis with Love&lt;/strong&gt;, I share updates of my
  projects and lovely bits from the internet.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://buttondown.com/juhis/archive/010-a-wonderful-october/&quot;&gt;Read #010 - A wonderful October&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;

    </content>
  </entry> 
  <entry>
    <title>Progressive enhancement is a crucial design principle for smart devices</title>
    <link href="https://hamatti.org/posts/progressive-enhancement-is-a-crucial-design-principle-for-smart-devices/" />
    <updated>2025-10-29T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://hamatti.org/posts/progressive-enhancement-is-a-crucial-design-principle-for-smart-devices/</id>
    <content type="html">
      &lt;p&gt;
  Last week on Tuesday, Oct 21st 2025,
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://edition.cnn.com/business/live-news/amazon-tech-outage-10-20-25-intl&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;AWS had an outage on one of its datacenters&lt;/a&gt;
  that had big effect on a lot of digital services and websites.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Some of the more bizarre examples were
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/10/smart-beds-leave-sleepers-hot-and-bothered-during-aws-outage/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;the smart beds that couldn’t be adjusted and that heated up to
    uncomfortable temperatures&lt;/a&gt;. As someone with smart home automations that didn’t even notice the issue,
  it inspired me to write about why so many smart devices are horrible by
  design.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  When I’ve been building my smart home automation system at home, a key
  principle has been that
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://hamatti.org/posts/network-stress-test-for-my-smart-home/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;it needs to be a progressive enhancement&lt;/a&gt;: if Internet or any 3rd party service is down, I need to be able to do
  everything I can do with automations: turn my lights on and off, start my
  entertainment devices and so on.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Any “smart” device that stops operating when a 3rd party service that’s out of
  your control goes down is not a smart device: it’s electronic waste waiting to
  happen.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  For a brief moment of time in my life during the pandemic, I owned IKEA
  SYMFONISK speakers. They were “smart” speaker collab by IKEA and Sonos. There
  was no way to listen to music other than sending it over the Internet and at
  any time,
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2019/12/30/21042871/sonos-recycle-mode-trade-up-program-controversy&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Sonos is able to &lt;/a&gt;&lt;i class=&quot;notion-text-italic&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2019/12/30/21042871/sonos-recycle-mode-trade-up-program-controversy&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;brick&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2019/12/30/21042871/sonos-recycle-mode-trade-up-program-controversy&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;
    your devices&lt;/a&gt;, ie. decide it cannot play music and there’s nothing you can do. SYMFONISK
  speakers didn’t even have a 3.5mm audio jack to connect a device to it
  physically. So I sold them to a friend and purchased dumb speakers instead.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  There are so many examples of shitty, user-hostile product design where
  internet connectivity and extra services have not been made an extra benefit
  but a required part and the
  &lt;b class=&quot;notion-text-bold&quot;&gt;hardware will outlive the service&lt;/b&gt; almost every
  single time. It means throwing away perfectly good appliances just because a
  company decided it’s not financially smart anymore to support old ones.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  If your bed, fridge, car or TV can be disabled or made unusable by the company
  some years after you purchased it, you’re getting the short stick. You are
  being screwed over by the businesses who know you’ll come back to buy the next
  version when the only reason to do so is because they just decided it’s time
  for you to switch.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  An outage on a service or network is an often temporary and short thing and
  not the problem itself. It’s the ability to permamently make your electronics
  trash and the fact that it’s inevitable because no company will keep all of
  their old services up and running forever.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I hope more people would stop buying devices and appliances with such designs
  because that’s the only message corporations listen to.
&lt;/p&gt;

    </content>
  </entry> 
  <entry>
    <title>Obsidian is as simple or complex as you make it</title>
    <link href="https://hamatti.org/posts/obsidian-is-as-simple-or-complex-as-you-make-it/" />
    <updated>2025-10-22T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://hamatti.org/posts/obsidian-is-as-simple-or-complex-as-you-make-it/</id>
    <content type="html">
      &lt;p&gt;
  As an Obsidian user, I often notice people mentioning how they want a simple,
  cross-platform note taking tool but
  &lt;i class=&quot;notion-text-italic&quot;&gt;not Obsidian because it’s too complex&lt;/i&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I feel it’s a branding issue. Especially a lot of bloggers and influencers
  create super complex systems (partly because it’s easier to make content of
  complex than simple systems) and “you absolutely need these 25 plugins”
  pieces.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;b class=&quot;notion-text-bold&quot;&gt;But Obsidian is only as complex as you make it.&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At its core, Obsidian is a text editor with live Markdown rendering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  If you want simple notes tool, you can use it to create notes and write to
  them in plain text or Markdown. You can make one long note or multiple smaller
  ones. You can store them all in one folder or have as many folders as you
  want.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  In my opinion, it’s even crucially important to start simple and keep it that
  way until you notice a need for something more complex. Gradually introducing
  new features and plugins means you will not get overwhelmed by the software.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I like Obsidian’s design. It allows you to start quickly and make notes but it
  has a very high ceiling so it will grow with your notes and needs.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  If you’re looking for a good, simple cross-platform notes app, I think you
  should give Obsidian a go and not install any plugins or follow any influencer
  guides. Just start writing notes and see if the UX feels good for your flow.
&lt;/p&gt;

    </content>
  </entry> 
  <entry>
    <title>PyCon Finland 2025 recap</title>
    <link href="https://hamatti.org/posts/pycon-finland-2025-recap/" />
    <updated>2025-10-19T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://hamatti.org/posts/pycon-finland-2025-recap/</id>
    <content type="html">
      
&lt;p&gt;
  In 2016, I gave my first developer conference talk,
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/Yi4uWzF6-Ug&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Data Scraping for Beginners&lt;/a&gt;, as a beginner speaker and met a lot of fantastic people in the conference.
  It kickstarted my journey as a public speaker and in the 9 years since, I’ve
  been on different stages sharing my stories hundreds of times.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  It was the last PyCon Finland for a long time, until this October when thanks
  to the great initiative by Plone Conference organisers Rikupekka Oksanen, Asmo
  Soukka and others who with the support of other local Python communities
  decided to bring back
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://fi.pycon.org/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;PyCon Finland&lt;/a&gt; and
  organise it as part of
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://2025.ploneconf.org/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;this year’s Plone Conference&lt;/a&gt;
  in Jyväskylä.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I proposed my talk
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://hamatti.org/posts/debugging-python&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Debugging Python&lt;/a&gt;
  which was accepted in the Friday morning block.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;notion-heading_2 notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
  chapter 0 where I talk about conferences
&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;notion-quote notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
  When you’re sending your people, your teams to conferences, you’re not just
  buying them some “knowledge”. No, you’re investing in something much more
  valuable. You’re helping them come back as more inspired, more connected, more
  curious, and more engaged members of the community. And yes, that’s something
  that can’t be measured or reported back, I’m afraid. But here’s the thing: you
  might notice that spark in their eyes when they come back to office and start
  talking about that new component they can’t wait to design and build.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://matthiasott.com/notes/the-lifeblood-of-the-web&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Matthias Ott wrote this&lt;/a&gt;
  less than a week before PyCon Finland and I felt it deep in my bones. It’s
  such a great way to describe why attending conferences is such an impactful
  move.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I’ve shared more good insights from others in
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://hamatti.org/posts/chance-of-serendipity/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Chance of serendipity&lt;/a&gt;
  that I highly recommend reading if you’re not quite sure why people attend
  events like these.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I probably didn’t learn something specific that I could bring to my job next
  week and immediately implement. I did get a lot of inspiration, new ideas and
  enthusiasm that I can definitely bring to the office.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;notion-heading_2 notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
  chapter 1 where we travel to Jyväskylä
&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  From Turku, we arrived with a two-person delegate, representing our
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://archipylago.dev/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;local Python community archipylago&lt;/a&gt;. Me and Tero took the train to Jyväskylä Thursday afternoon and spent most
  of the travel time by playing one of my favourite two player board games Lost
  Cities that I got to teach Tero.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://hamatti.org/assets/img/posts/pycon-finland-2025-recap/1.png.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Lost Cities card game being played in a train table. Cards in five colours are organised in columns based on their colors so that both players have their own columns where numbers are played in ascending order. &quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I almost always travel alone and while I do enjoy it, having a friend to
  travel with makes the trips fly by like it did this time as well. And with
  Tero we always end up into such good discussions given enough time so every
  time we learn something new and get new ideas.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  After a train trip from Turku through Tampere to Jyväskylä came to its end, we
  checked in to the hotel, ate dinner in
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hotellialba.fi/a-la-carte&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;the hotel restaurant&lt;/a&gt;
  (the food was incredible!). I had a burger with thick patty, delicious Jukola
  cheese, paprika-tomato-chutney and crispy fries and it was one of the best
  I’ve had in a long time.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://hamatti.org/assets/img/posts/pycon-finland-2025-recap/2.png.webp&quot; alt=&quot;A delicious burger with a thick patty, nicely melted cheese and some greens poking from between. Rest of the plate is filled with crispy fries. &quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  As PyCon Finland was part of Plone Conference that had been already going for
  a couple of days, there was a party in the evening that we joined. Usually,
  when I got to conferences around Europe, I know quite a lot of people (and
  there’s quite a few people who know me) so it was a really weird social
  experience to be in the conference where I knew only a couple of people and
  where everyone else already knew each other through the Plone community and
  the week’s earlier conference days.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  We didn’t stay quite as long as some of the party goers (I remember seeing
  some photos in Discord from around 4.30) but went back to the hotel where I
  did final adjustments to my slides and enjoyed a good night sleep.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;notion-heading_2 notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
  chapter 2 where I speak at the conference
&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  The hardest part of doing a conference talk is waking up early enough to not
  miss it. This time I managed to get up, eat breakfast at the hotel and walked
  across the parking lot to the venue at University of Jyväskylä’s Agora
  building.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Since I had an early morning speaking slot, I went directly to do a tech check
  and missed the lightning talk signups. I didn’t then have a change to make
  people laugh with my version number comparison lightning talk.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  My talk was the last talk of the morning slot. As I was waiting for my moment,
  I listened as Alexander Loechel
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://2025.ploneconf.org/schedule/talks/edutap&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;introduced eduTAP&lt;/a&gt;, a mobile app and ecosystem aimed for universities in Europe and around the
  world to provide authentication of student status, access to different
  services and even payments. I also got to
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://2025.ploneconf.org/schedule/talks/guillotina-volto-a-new-backend-for-volto&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;learn about Guillotina Volto&lt;/a&gt;
  from Nil Bacardit and Roger Boixader Güell but as I was nervously preparing
  for my own talk to start and haven’t used Plone or its frontend system Volto
  before, I didn’t follow too intensively.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;https://hamatti.org/assets/img/posts/pycon-finland-2025-recap/3.png.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Juhis is standing in front of a room presenting with both of his arms up like he’s showing that something is very big. Next to him is a slide with a picture of yellow rubber ducks in sailor costumes and title Rubber duck debugging. Next to his laptop on the table there’s an avocado plushie and two rubber ducks. &quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://masto.ai/@tero&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Tero&lt;/a&gt;.
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Kep3kN2Ay04&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer nofollow&quot;&gt;Watch the recording&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://2025.ploneconf.org/schedule/talks/debugging-python&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;The third slot was mine&lt;/a&gt;. The room filled up with developers eager to see my rubber ducks and learn a
  trick or two about debugging. I’ve performed the talk a couple of times in the
  past so I was confident in my content and timing. At one point, I noticed I
  hadn’t been breathing quite enough and started to feel the consequences but
  managed to pull myself back and I don’t think anyone in the audience even
  noticed.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I was very satisfied with my talk. Last conference I did it was in PyCon
  Sweden 2023 and back then I felt it was my best conference talk and this one
  was neck and neck with it. The hall and audience was bigger in Sweden and I
  tend to perform better the bigger the audience is but on this one, I had a
  better opportunity to read audience’s faces which made it a lovely experience.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  If you&#39;re interested in the talk, I have it written in blog format at
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://hamatti.org/posts/debugging-python&quot;&gt;Debugging Python&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  The feedback I received from the talk was so good and made my week.
  &lt;b class=&quot;notion-text-bold&quot;&gt;If you ever see a talk in an event that you enjoyed, tell the speaker
    that!&lt;/b&gt;
  It feels good to get positive feedback.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  One of my favourite things while doing talks like these is seeing people’s
  faces light up when they learn something new or when they smile or laugh at
  the right moments. That’s when I know I’ve succeeded in doing what I came to
  do.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  And the best part of these is meeting new people, learning from them and
  having great discussions and there was no shortage of those discussions in
  this conference. Whether it was the discussions right after the talk, during
  the hallway track at the venue or while grabbing a beer after the event, I
  cherish all of them and want to thank everyone who came to chat. ❤️
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I didn’t have to go through my talk alone. I had my support group of Frank,
  Uni and Cado:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;https://hamatti.org/assets/img/posts/pycon-finland-2025-recap/4.png.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Two rubber ducks: one dressed as a hunter and another is a unicorn and an avocado plush in front of a laptop that has a quirky Pikachu and Firefox stickers on its cover. &quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://masto.ai/@tero&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Tero&lt;/a&gt;.
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I finally remembered to bring my ducks to my debugging talk! And of course,
  Cado who is my conference talk support animal was with me the whole way. (&lt;a href=&quot;https://mastodon.world/@hamatti/111382189307669156&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Cado is no stranger to PyCon stages&lt;/a&gt;.)
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;notion-heading_2 notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
  chapter 3 where I get to relax and learn from others
&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Even after hundreds of times on the stage and high confidence in my talk, the
  butterflies find their way to my stomach a bit before the talk. Once the talk
  starts, they go their own way and after the talk, I get to relax, continue
  discussions and enjoy others’ talks.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  A sign of the quality of the conference was that pretty much before every talk
  slot, we had the discussion of “oh, I’d like to see them all” and had to
  choose only one.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Here’s a short recap of the talks I particularly enjoyed.
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://maurits.vanrees.org/weblog&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Maurits van Rees also wrote notes from the talks he watched&lt;/a&gt;
  so if you’re interested in some of the other talks, I recommend checking his
  blog out.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Patrik Lauha: Muuttolintujen Kevät - Automatic Bird Sound Classifier&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://hamatti.org/assets/img/posts/pycon-finland-2025-recap/5.png.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Patrik speaking in front of an auditorium with a slide t hat shows a wolrd map that’s blue in Europe and grey elsewhere and two maps of Finland with mostly red and yellow dots in the south and white in the north. &quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3gkCFFWGetM&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;Watch the recording&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  After my talk, we had the keynote of the day where
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://2025.ploneconf.org/schedule/keynotes/muuttolintujen-kevat-automatic-bird-sound-classifier&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Patrik Lauha talked about a fascinating project&lt;/a&gt;. They trained a model to recognise birds by their singing and built a mobile
  app where people all around Finland can record birds as they sing and learn
  which birds they are.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  What was especially interesting was how they transformed audio into images and
  then did image recognition to identify birds. I hadn’t even thought of such
  possibility and apparently it helps a lot in simplifying the data and doing
  comparisons.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;
  Robert Silén: Building RAG AI Applications with MariaDB Vector and Python
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://hamatti.org/assets/img/posts/pycon-finland-2025-recap/6.png.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Robert speaking in front of an auditorium with a title slide about building RAG AI applications with MariaDB Vector and Python &quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ndWI0vSakzQ&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;Watch the recording&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  After the lunch,
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://2025.ploneconf.org/schedule/talks/building-rag-ai-applications-with-mariadb-vector-and-python&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Robert Silén from MariaDB Foundation talked about vector databases&lt;/a&gt;
  and how to augment AI models with custom data to create custom chatbots from
  which to ask questions about your data.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I’m not much of an LLM fan and haven’t done much in this space so my focus was
  a bit off during the talk.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;An interlude about making friends in a conference&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  In
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://hamatti.org/posts/shy-introverts-short-guide-to-speaking-in-conferences/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Shy introvert&#39;s (short) guide to speaking in conferences&lt;/a&gt;
  I wrote:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;notion-quote notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
  The time leading up to your talk is nervous and many people like to stay away
  from people to practice. What I like to do is spend my conference day making
  friends. Before the talks, during breakfast, during breaks and lunch, I try to
  find people to talk with. Especially great if I can find groups with some
  people I made friends with before the event that I can ease my way into the
  discussion through someone I know.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;notion-quote notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
  Both of these lead towards one goal:
  &lt;b class=&quot;notion-text-bold&quot;&gt;instead of speaking to strangers, by the time my talk starts, I&#39;m talking
    to friends&lt;/b&gt;. And speaking to friends is so much easier than to strangers.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I met next talk’s speaker Fodil during the lunch break as he joined our table
  and we had a lovely discussion about (human) languages, living abroad,
  experiencing different cultures and what not.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  This block had so many interesting talks but when I heard Fodil was the one
  speaking about Shiny, a tool to create interactive dashboards, that I was
  familiar with from R world but hadn’t used with Python, it was an easy
  decision to join his talk.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  He asked me to take some photos of him talking — the same thing I asked Tero
  to do for my talk — and I was happy to help out. This is one of the tips I
  recommend everyone to do if you’re speaking in a conference. If you don’t
  already have a friend who’s gonna attend your talk, make friends with someone
  and ask them to take some photos. It can suck to give a talk and leave the
  conference only to realise you have no photos to remember the talk from or
  share with friends.one who does talks to do: if you don’t already have friends
  in the conference who will at
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;
  Mohamed El Fodil Ihaddaden: Shiny for Python: Reactive Web Apps Made Simple
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://hamatti.org/assets/img/posts/pycon-finland-2025-recap/7.png.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Fodil speaking in front of a room with a slide that reads: Shiny Core and Shiny express. &quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=P1GYA9zqJCo&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;Watch the recording&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  So I listened to Fodil who showed us what Shiny can do, how to avoid certain
  pitfalls with long-running data fetching and a few tips for how to use it with
  Python to use different types of data and interactions.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Talks that showcase tools through demos that are
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/feddelegrand7/shinyfinland&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;available in GitHub&lt;/a&gt;
  are cool ones in conferences because you can go and try them out yourself and
  tinker, and continue from them.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Katrin Zaks: Accessibility‑First Development: A New Core Company Value&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://hamatti.org/assets/img/posts/pycon-finland-2025-recap/8.png.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Karin presenting in front of a room with a slide about Putting accessibility into practice. &quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5y8bCe-qvzI&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;Watch the recording&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I love seeing talks about accessibility in tech conferences so while there
  were other interesting talks for this slot, the choice was rather easy.
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://2025.ploneconf.org/schedule/talks/accessibility-first-development-a-new-core-company-value&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Katrin talked about accessibility-first development&lt;/a&gt;
  where accessibility is not considered as a necessary evil that’s added at the
  end but rather a fundamental part of building software for everyone.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Her talk was excellent and I liked how it focused mostly on why accessibility
  matters and how to adapt company’s approach to it.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Tatu Aalto: Why as Developer I Am Blind to Bugs&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://hamatti.org/assets/img/posts/pycon-finland-2025-recap/9.png.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Tatu is presenting in front of a room with a slide that has an image of two construction workers yelling at each other through a broken wall and title Not easy in my open-source projects. &quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gVeYjyq5-B0&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;Watch the recording&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  We had two talks about bugs in the conference! And they were completely
  different. I got to meet Tatu after my talk and he strengthened my debugging
  duck crew with a teeny-tiny duck which I’ll put in special spot at home so I
  don’t lose it.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  In his own talk in the afternoon, Tatu talked about his journey from testing
  to software development and to building test automation tools and how he
  understood that there are (at least) two roles (developer and tester) inside
  him that need to work together to build quality software.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Lightning talks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I &lt;b class=&quot;notion-text-bold&quot;&gt;love&lt;/b&gt; lightning talks. They are this unique
  part of conferences where you can talk about anything you want for 5 minutes
  and are often filled with variety of topics, a lot of fun and light-hearted
  content and announcements for projects and events. This time wasn’t any
  difference.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  We started with a brilliant presentation about the history of casserole in
  Finnish cuisine from 1800s to today. What a great way to start the lightning
  talks. I don’t enjoy eating casserole but I loved learning about their
  history.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  There were also a bunch of announcements and proposals for different Plone
  events, including the next Plone Conference in Maastricht next year.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  One that touched me personally was a talk about how it’s okay to feel good
  about the things you do and build and talk about them. Especially in the
  community space, I try to make sure the spotlight isn’t on me and my
  motivations because as the face of the activities I often get too much credit
  that’s more deserved by others who make the community what it is and I don’t
  want my ego to get too much into the driving seat.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;notion-heading_2 notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
  chapter 4 where I say thanks
  &lt;s class=&quot;notion-text-strikethrough&quot; style=&quot;text-decoration-thickness: 3px&quot;&gt;and go home&lt;/s&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://hamatti.org/assets/img/posts/pycon-finland-2025-recap/10.png.webp&quot; alt=&quot;An avocado plushie, Python logo built from LEGOs and a PyCon Finland 2025 badge of Juha-Matti Santala &quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PyCon Finland was an absolutely lovely experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;b class=&quot;notion-text-bold&quot;&gt;Big thanks to all the organisers, speakers and friends — old and new.&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  The local grassroots Python community situation in Finland looks very
  different than it did a couple of years ago and I hope that we can together
  make PyCon Finland a reality in 2026 as well.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I got so much new ideas and inspiration that I’ve been missing for a while
  now.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  If you, my dear reader, have a PyCon in your country or somewhere close by, I
  highly recommend joining when it happens next time. I have been to many across
  Europe and I have always come home better than when I left home. Never a bad
  one because the community of Pythonistas is just lovely.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;https://hamatti.org/assets/img/posts/pycon-finland-2025-recap/13.jpg.webp&quot; alt=&quot;A group picture of PyCon Finland and Plone Conference participants&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    The wonderful people of Plone Conference and PyCon Finland. Photo by event
    organizers.
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;notion-heading_2 notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
  chapter 5 where instead of going home, I went to Lokacon
&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  A few days before the conference I learned that on Saturday, Jyväskylän
  Science Fiction Seura 42 were organising
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scifi42.fi/lokacon/lokacon-2025/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Lokacon&lt;/a&gt;, a science fiction and literary event at the library. Since I had booked a
  hotel for the night after the conference, I decided to book my train trip to
  the afternoon and joined the event.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://hamatti.org/assets/img/posts/pycon-finland-2025-recap/11.png.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Juha sitting in front of a room, presenting with two Star Wars comics covers on a screen behind him. There are a handful of people visible in the audience. &quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I had time to listen to two talks and they were both excellent. Juha Hautala
  took us to a journey through time and talked about the history of Star Wars
  comics from the late 1970s to today. There were a lot of familiar comics for
  me but also a bunch of interesting ones that I hadn’t heard of so I have some
  backlog to catch up.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://hamatti.org/assets/img/posts/pycon-finland-2025-recap/12.png.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Katja speaking with a Don Rosa Donald Duck comic on the screen and text in Finnish around it explaining how to analyse fantasy comics. &quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://ankkatohtorinlokikirja.com/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Ankkatohtori (lit. Duck Dr.) Katja Kontturi&lt;/a&gt;
  who wrote
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://jyx.jyu.fi/jyx/Record/jyx_123456789_44805&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;her doctoral thesis on Don Rosa’s comics&lt;/a&gt;
  talked about her journey from a fan of the comics to a doctor of them and what
  she discovered. I also bought her book that’s based on her thesis: Ankkalinna,
  portti kahden maailman välillä (eng. Duckburg, portal between two worlds) and
  got a dedication from her on the book as well.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Going home is always the sad part of conferences because it means going back
  to day-to-day. One of the reasons I became a professional community builder
  was that I hated doing that so much that I didn’t want to go that route and
  instead, I got to continue in the events space and with communities even when
  it was time to go home.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully one day I’ll get back to that world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Until then, our
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://archipylago.dev/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;archipylago&lt;/a&gt;
  and
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://turkufrontend.fi/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Turku ❤️ Frontend&lt;/a&gt;
  meetups continue so if you’re in the are around Turku and want to feel the
  same magic, see you there!
&lt;/p&gt;

    </content>
  </entry> 
  <entry>
    <title>Networking and writing as a catalyst for relationships and opportunities</title>
    <link href="https://hamatti.org/posts/networking-and-writing-as-a-catalyst-for-relationships-and-opportunities/" />
    <updated>2025-10-08T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://hamatti.org/posts/networking-and-writing-as-a-catalyst-for-relationships-and-opportunities/</id>
    <content type="html">
      &lt;p&gt;
  Joan Westenberg published
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.joanwestenberg.com/p/i-don-t-network-i-write&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;I Don&#39;t Network. I Write.&lt;/a&gt;
  about how writing can be a (better) replacement for networking in the context
  of building credibility and gaining opportunities. I found the arguments for
  writing to be very much inline with my own thoughts.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;notion-quote notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
  Writing has given me rooms I couldn’t have entered otherwise. My words
  circulate in spaces where I am absent. They argue for me, persuade for me,
  provoke on my behalf etc. And unlike a conversation at a bar, they persist.
  They can be returned to, challenged, reinterpreted. Writing isn’t opposed to
  networking at all. It’s networking’s more honest sibling. One is presence; the
  other is permanence.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  When I talk about
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://notes.hamatti.org/my-projects/talks/why-developers-should-write-blog-posts-(talk)&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;blogging for developers&lt;/a&gt;, I talk about building a body of work and a set of documentation that lasts
  for a long time in the era of social media where posts have visibility of
  maybe few minutes or hours and even accounts and platforms have lifecycles
  measured in years.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Taylor Desseyn phrased it wonderfully when he said (no direct source, I
  learned this
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mRd_1Bt9qrs&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;through Jason Lengstorf&#39;s discussion with Maggie Appleton&lt;/a&gt;)
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;notion-quote notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
  Learning in public is interviewing at scale
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  which is very much the same sentiment: you can network or interview personally
  one person or position at a time but by writing, you can showcase your
  thinking and your skills at scale and potentially reach many relevant people
  by writing something once.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Joan&#39;s description of networking rang different in my ears however. I&#39;m not
  saying that this type of networking doesn&#39;t happen but I&#39;ve found it to be —
  at least in my circles — not the main way of networking.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://archipylago.dev/blog/hallway-track-is-where-magic-happens/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;encourage people to network&lt;/a&gt;. Both for career opportunities but also for personal relationships. I&#39;ve
  made so many great, life-long friendships through what people would call
  networking.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  To me, networking is about doing things together, about building trust. It&#39;s
  about getting to know other people who share similar interests, learning from
  them, sharing ideas and collaborating.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Like Joan, I don&#39;t personally find much value in the type of networking where
  one goes to pitch their skills or services and the goal is to collect as many
  business cards or LinkedIn connections as possible. That kind of networking to
  me feels hollow and pointless. I&#39;m interested in getting to know people and
  their thoughts and ideas and passions.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;notion-quote notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
  When someone finds me through my writing, the conversation begins on different
  ground. We’re not trading business cards, we’re engaging in thought. And that
  makes for a stronger foundation.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I love attending events like meetups and conferences because those are prime
  spots for me to engage in the exchange of thoughts with people. The talks or
  workshops give me a frame: this person is interested in this topic (or vice
  versa if I&#39;m the speaker) and we have common ground to continue the
  discussions and go deeper, way beyond trading business cards.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I also love organising things with other people and work with people on
  projects. Usually when you&#39;re deep in collaboration and focus on a shared
  goal, your discussions with people deepen too. Sometimes it&#39;s the content that
  goes deep but often it&#39;s also the level of familiarity with those people.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Some of the best networking moments for me have been late nights organising
  Slush startup conference, working for hours with great people making things
  happen, solving problems and building trust.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  To me, there&#39;s no moment of separation between &quot;networking&quot; and &quot;what happens
  after successful networking&quot;. It&#39;s all about building relationships to me. Of
  course, not every relationship end up leading to something that lasts but
  those that do, are already way ahead of what my writing leads to.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  The benefit of writing is the scale but it&#39;s downside is that it&#39;s only the
  starting point and the relationship and trust building will follow from that.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  It also makes me wonder if there&#39;s a tipping point when your writing has
  enough readers that it starts to heavily outweight other means in efficiency.
  I&#39;m a writer with still very small audience so while I do see some benefits
  through my writing (other than satisfying my inner need to write and its
  helpfulness in documenting things for myself), they are likely very much
  smaller than for those with large audiences.
&lt;/p&gt;

    </content>
  </entry> 
  <entry>
    <title>Tabletop game shows</title>
    <link href="https://hamatti.org/posts/tabletop-game-shows/" />
    <updated>2025-10-01T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://hamatti.org/posts/tabletop-game-shows/</id>
    <content type="html">
      &lt;p&gt;
  I love playing board games but there are moments when I’m not with a group to
  play with. In those moments, I need to extend my playgroup to imaginary
  parasocial playgroups and watch others play in Youtube.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  While I occasionally enjoy learning about new games through review videos, my
  bread and butter is talkshow-esque board game shows where —
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://hamatti.org/posts/board-game-nights-are-my-favourite-way-to-socialise-and-make-new-friends/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;like in real life&lt;/a&gt;
  — gaming is only part of the fun.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;notion-heading_2 notion-color-default&quot;&gt;Tabletop with Wil Wheaton&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PL7atuZxmT956cWFGxqSyRdn6GWhBxiAwE&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Geek &amp; Sundry’s Wil Wheaton’s Tabletop&lt;/a&gt;
  is one of the first breakout hits of the genre. It’s been a decade since it
  finished but the episodes are still wonderful and all available on Youtube.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Each episode, Wil is joined by creative people, mostly actors, and they play a
  different game while teaching how the game works. The main focus is on the
  banter and fun between the players and I sometimes just listen to the episodes
  without watching the video — they are that good.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;notion-heading_2 notion-color-default&quot;&gt;No Rolls Barred&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/@NoRollsBarred&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;No Rolls Barred&lt;/a&gt;
  is a British tabletop gaming show that started during the pandemic as a way to
  showcase how you can play board games in lockdown with online tools and after
  the pandemic ramped up its production values to an in-person show.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  The group mainly consists of actors and Youtube personalities and the format
  is very similar to Wil Wheaton’s Tabletop in that you get to learn a new game
  while enjoying the personalities and chemistry of the people. Where it differs
  from Tabletop is that the crew is mostly the same. Each episode has a subset
  of the crew playing and there are occasional guests but mainly you get to also
  learn about the players and find your own favourites.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;notion-heading_2 notion-color-default&quot;&gt;Overboard by Polygon&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLaDrN74SfdT5jEs3RCI53nBUkuURSWrhq&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Overboard&lt;/a&gt;
  is a board game show by video game media Polygon. While gameplay production is
  similar to Tabletop and NRB, it’s very different in style. It has more focus
  on the gameplay itself rather than the characters. Which is weird because the
  crew is the real highlight of anything Polygon does, this included.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Where the previous two are shows focused on board games, Overboard is more of
  an occasional video type amongts many others that Polygon puts out and feels
  more like an office gaming night.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;notion-heading_2 notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
  Game Night by BoardGameGeek
&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  The last one on the list is completely different from the other three — other
  than it’s a group of people sitting around a table playing board games.
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLBIiHc7zsjdzziFFZQqeTrfXlhKFeApUq&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;BoardGameGeek’s Game Night&lt;/a&gt;
  is a show where people teach you how to play various games. It’s not full of
  actors creating a show around their personalities but a high quality series
  that follows the pattern of How to Play — See people play — Short discussion
  of the game.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  For pure board game content, it’s by far the best and I really enjoy learning
  new games and seeing them being played on the show.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  It’s been going on for 13 seasons already so there’s a massive backlog of
  videos to watch if you’re new to the show.
&lt;/p&gt;

    </content>
  </entry> 
  <entry>
    <title>From Juhis with Love #009: End of summer</title>
    <link href="https://hamatti.org/posts/external-from-juhis-with-love-009-end-of-summer/" />
    <updated>2025-09-30T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://hamatti.org/posts/external-from-juhis-with-love-009-end-of-summer/</id>
    <content type="html">
      
&lt;p&gt;
  In September issue of &lt;strong&gt;From Juhis with Love&lt;/strong&gt;, I share updates of my
  projects and lovely bits from the internet.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://buttondown.com/juhis/archive/009-end-of-summer/&quot;&gt;Read #009: End of summer&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;

    </content>
  </entry> 
  <entry>
    <title>File organisation in Eleventy: Filters</title>
    <link href="https://hamatti.org/posts/file-organisation-in-eleventy-filters/" />
    <updated>2025-09-24T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://hamatti.org/posts/file-organisation-in-eleventy-filters/</id>
    <content type="html">
      
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.11ty.dev/docs/filters/&quot; class=&quot;notion-text-href&quot;&gt;Filters&lt;/a&gt;
  are a handy feature in Eleventy that allows you to run functions on input from
  templates.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;notion-quote notion-color-default&quot;&gt;
  A filter is a function which can be used within templating syntax to transform
  data into a more presentable format. Filters are typically designed to be
  chained, so that the value returned from one filter is piped into the next
  filter.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  They are used with a pipe character (&lt;code class=&quot;notion-text-code&quot;&gt;|&lt;/code&gt;)
  from templates like in the documentation example:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre class=&quot;language-html&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-html&quot;&gt; &amp;#60;h1&amp;#62;{{ name | makeUppercase }}&amp;#60;/h1&amp;#62;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Here, &lt;code class=&quot;notion-text-code&quot;&gt;name&lt;/code&gt; is a variable that contains
  some value and &lt;code class=&quot;notion-text-code&quot;&gt;makeUppercase&lt;/code&gt; is a filter
  it is passed to.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  To create a filter, you call
  &lt;code class=&quot;notion-text-code&quot;&gt;addFilter&lt;/code&gt; method in your configuration:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre class=&quot;language-javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-javascript&quot;&gt;export default function(eleventyConfig) {
	eleventyConfig.addFilter(&quot;makeUppercase&quot;, function(value) {
		return value.toUpperCase()
	}); 
});&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  When you have one or two filters, they live comfortably in the main function
  but due to their usefulness, I tend to accumulate a large collection over
  time. They are handy small utility functions so it’s easy to create one for
  any use case.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s how I organise my filters:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I have a &lt;code class=&quot;notion-text-code&quot;&gt;_11ty/&lt;/code&gt; folder for all sorts of
  scripts that I use to run my Eleventy project. There, I create a
  &lt;code class=&quot;notion-text-code&quot;&gt;filters.js&lt;/code&gt; file that contains all my
  filters and export them.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s an example of a small project I started recently&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre class=&quot;language-javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-javascript&quot;&gt;function ongoing(isOngoing) {
  return isOngoing ? &quot;ongoing&quot; : &quot;finished&quot;;
}

function finishedSeries(series) {
  return series.filter((serie) =&amp;#62; !serie.ongoing).length || 0;
}

export default { ongoing, finishedSeries };&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  The function name matches the filter name exactly here so that I can in my
  config file then do this
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre class=&quot;language-javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-javascript&quot;&gt;import filters from &#39;./11ty/filters.js&#39;

export default function(eleventyConfig) {
	Object.entries(filters).forEach(([name, callback]) =&amp;#62; {
    eleventyConfig.addFilter(name, callback);
  });
});&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  This will go through all the filters and register them with the function name
  as filter name and the function callback as the function.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  I don’t have to remember the syntax of
  &lt;code class=&quot;notion-text-code&quot;&gt;addFilter&lt;/code&gt; anymore and I can keep all of
  my filters in one place. That’s handy when I need to debug a misbehaving
  filter or add a new filter. Everything is tidily in one place.
&lt;/p&gt;

    </content>
  </entry>
</feed>
