<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
  <rss version="2.0"
    xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
    xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
    xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
    xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
    xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
    xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
    xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
    xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
  >
    <channel>
      <title>Piccalilli - Everything</title>
      <link>https://piccalil.li/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://piccalil.li/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <description>We are Piccalilli. A publication dedicated to providing high quality educational content to level up your front-end skills.</description>
      <language>en-GB</language>
      <copyright>Piccalilli - Everything 2026</copyright>
      <docs>https://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 17:02:48 GMT</pubDate>
      <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 17:02:48 GMT</lastBuildDate>

      
      <item>
        <title>The Index: Issue #160</title>
        <link>https://piccalil.li/the-index/160/?ref=main-rss-feed</link>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Andy Bell]]></dc:creator>
        <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 11:55:00 GMT</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://piccalil.li/the-index/160/?ref=main-rss-feed</guid>
        <description><![CDATA[<h2><a href="https://emergenceprojects.com/?utm_source=the-index&amp;utm_medium=newsletter">Emergence</a></h2>
<p>A delightfully creative website with a stunning monochromatic, texture-based look and feel.</p>
<h2><a href="https://loudroom.com/?utm_source=the-index&amp;utm_medium=newsletter">Loud Room</a></h2>
<p>Jason Santa Maria's new studio here. Refresh the page and get a different colour scheme!</p>
<h2><a href="https://blento.app/?utm_source=the-index&amp;utm_medium=newsletter">blento</a></h2>
<p>Look, we get it, building your own corner of the web can feel like too much of a job, so services like this are handy. It's all linked up to your Bluesky too.</p>
<h2><a href="https://jamieclarketype.com/case-study/wallace-and-gromit-font/?utm_source=the-index&amp;utm_medium=newsletter">Wallace and Gromit font</a></h2>
<p><a href="https://set.studio/?utm_source=the-index&amp;utm_medium=newsletter">Our</a> client Jamie Clarke here with a beauty of a font for the famous animated duo.</p>
<h2><a href="https://www.alwaystwisted.com/articles/ive-been-compiling-my-sass-wrong-for-years?utm_source=the-index&amp;utm_medium=newsletter">I’ve been compiling my Sass wrong, for years</a></h2>
<p>The old Sass <em>will</em> disappear with the upcoming 2.0.0 release, so brush up before it's too late!</p>
<h2><a href="https://piccalil.li/projects/personal-site/1/?utm_source=the-index&amp;utm_medium=newsletter">Personal website redesign: The start</a></h2>
<p>One from me to close out. I'm completely redesigning my website and breaking down the whole process over a series of posts throughout the year. It should be fun!</p>
<hr />
<p>P.S. <a href="https://www.andycarolan.com/?utm_source=the-index&amp;utm_medium=newsletter">this is a good website</a> from <a href="https://personalsit.es/?utm_source=the-index&amp;utm_medium=newsletter">personalsit.es</a>.</p>
        
        <h2>Sponsor message</h2><a href="http://polypane.app/?via=andy&utm_source=the-index&utm_medium=newsletter"><img src="https://piccalil.b-cdn.net/images/ads/polypane-30012026.jpg" alt="Polypane. The missing half of your development environment" /></a><p>See every breakpoint. Catch every accessibility issue. Make your site work for everyone.</p>
<p>Polypane is a development browser that shows your site in multiple viewports at once, with built-in tools to test accessibility (WCAG violations, color contrast, DOM structure), performance metrics, layout debugging, and meta tag validation.</p>
<p>Thousands of developers trust Polypane to build sites that work beautifully for everyone without constant tab-switching and browser resizing.</p>
<p><a href="http://polypane.app/?via=andy&utm_source=the-index&utm_medium=newsletter">Start your free trial</a></p>
<hr />
<p>Thanks for reading this issue of <a href="https://piccalil.li/the-index/">The Index</a>. We really appreciate you being a subscriber. If you’re enjoying The Index, we’d really
appreciate it if you shared this issue with your friends too.</p>
<p>Until the next issue, take it easy 👋<br/>
Andy</p>
]]></description>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Index: Issue #159</title>
        <link>https://piccalil.li/the-index/159/?ref=main-rss-feed</link>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Andy Bell]]></dc:creator>
        <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 11:55:00 GMT</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://piccalil.li/the-index/159/?ref=main-rss-feed</guid>
        <description><![CDATA[<h2><a href="https://ericwbailey.website/published/how-an-accessibility-designer-adds-keyboard-shortcuts-to-a-web-app/?utm_source=the-index&amp;utm_medium=newsletter">How an accessibility designer adds keyboard shortcuts to a web app</a></h2>
<p>Eric does such a good job of breaking down the vast complexities with accessible UI design and here they are again, doing exactly that.</p>
<h2><a href="https://patrickbrosset.com/articles/2026-01-06-fun-with-the-web/?utm_source=the-index&amp;utm_medium=newsletter">Fun with the web</a></h2>
<p>A fantastic collection of fun stuff with some sage advice on using that as a means to learn, along with other methods to improve your learning.</p>
<h2><a href="https://henry.codes/writing/ai-at-work-is-anti-labor-by-design/?utm_source=the-index&amp;utm_medium=newsletter">AI at work is anti-labor by design</a></h2>
<blockquote>
<p>“You are not asked to use this tech because it will enable better work and ideas, but because it is cheaper to your boss than your coworker’s salary.”</p>
</blockquote>
<h2><a href="https://accessibilityforeveryone.site/?utm_source=the-index&amp;utm_medium=newsletter">Accessibility for Everyone</a></h2>
<p>By far one of the best books on accessibility and it's now free to everyone!</p>
<h2><a href="https://www.alwaystwisted.com/articles/introducing-relicss-a-tool-for-front-end-archaeology?utm_source=the-index&amp;utm_medium=newsletter">Introducing ReliCSS: a tool for front-end archaeology</a></h2>
<p>Stu has been working really hard on this tool and it looks really solid. Surely it will become a key tool in our arsenal when helping clients get out of a mess with their UIs.</p>
<hr />
<p>P.S. <a href="https://melchoyce.design/?utm_source=the-index&amp;utm_medium=newsletter">this is a good website</a> from <a href="https://personalsit.es/?utm_source=the-index&amp;utm_medium=newsletter">personalsit.es</a>.</p>
        
        <h2>Sponsor message</h2><a href="http://polypane.app/?via=andy&utm_source=the-index&utm_medium=newsletter"><img src="https://piccalil.b-cdn.net/images/ads/polypane-28012026.jpg" alt="Polypane. The missing half of your development environment" /></a><p><strong>Stop resizing your browser window to test responsive designs.</strong></p>
<p>Trusted by Kevin Powell, Andy Bell, Sara Soueidan, and Scott Tolinski, Polypane shows your site in multiple viewports at once so you can build and test faster.</p>
<p>Polypane is a development browser built for modern web development. Catch accessibility issues, debug responsive layouts, and preview across devices without leaving your workflow.</p>
<p><a href="http://polypane.app/?via=andy&utm_source=the-index&utm_medium=newsletter">Start your free trial</a></p>
<hr />
<p>Thanks for reading this issue of <a href="https://piccalil.li/the-index/">The Index</a>. We really appreciate you being a subscriber. If you’re enjoying The Index, we’d really
appreciate it if you shared this issue with your friends too.</p>
<p>Until the next issue, take it easy 👋<br/>
Andy</p>
]]></description>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Index: Issue #158</title>
        <link>https://piccalil.li/the-index/158/?ref=main-rss-feed</link>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Andy Bell]]></dc:creator>
        <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 11:55:00 GMT</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://piccalil.li/the-index/158/?ref=main-rss-feed</guid>
        <description><![CDATA[<h2><a href="https://polypane.app/blog/understanding-the-fundamentals-of-css-layout/?utm_source=the-index&amp;utm_medium=newsletter">Understanding the fundamentals of CSS Layout</a></h2>
<p>Quite possibly one of the most thorough articles on layout I've ever read. It's long, but definitely worth your time.</p>
<h2><a href="https://webkit.org/blog/17758/when-will-css-grid-lanes-arrive-how-long-until-we-can-use-it/?utm_source=the-index&amp;utm_medium=newsletter">When will CSS Grid Lanes arrive? How long until we can use it?</a></h2>
<p>A nice run down of when this new layout system arrives and what options you have to work with it right now.</p>
<h2><a href="https://howbrowserswork.com/?utm_source=the-index&amp;utm_medium=newsletter">How browsers work</a></h2>
<p>This does exactly what it says on the tin. Some lovely interaction work in here too.</p>
<h2><a href="https://vale.rocks/posts/css-reset?utm_source=the-index&amp;utm_medium=newsletter">My opinionated CSS reset</a></h2>
<p>You know the rules, if there's a new CSS reset, we share it. This is a good one with some very nice typographic touches.</p>
<h2><a href="https://www.midlife.engineering/?utm_source=the-index&amp;utm_medium=newsletter">Midlife Engineering – Sound therapy for a harmonious mind</a></h2>
<p>This is very nicely done. Either play around with the sounds yourself or enjoy pre-made ones to <em>relax</em>.</p>
<hr />
<p>P.S. <a href="https://linusbohman.se/?utm_source=the-index&amp;utm_medium=newsletter">this is a good website</a> from <a href="https://personalsit.es/?utm_source=the-index&amp;utm_medium=newsletter">personalsit.es</a>.</p>
        
        <h2>Sponsor message</h2><a href="https://webdayout.com/?utm_source=WDO_Piccalilli%20Index&utm_medium=WDO_Piccalilli%20mailer&utm_campaign=Web%20Day%20Out"><img src="https://piccalil.b-cdn.net/images/ads/clearleft-ad-2.png" alt="Web Day Out by Clearleft, Brighton, March 12." /></a><p>The most interesting advances on the web right now aren’t frameworks, but steady improvements to the platform itself: better CSS, more capable browsers, and APIs designed to solve real problems.</p>
<p><strong>Web Day Out</strong> is a one day conference about making the most of that platform. Talks focus on resilient layouts, progressive enhancement, accessibility, performance, typography and the long-term maintainability of HTML, CSS and JavaScript in production.</p>
<p>The event is happening on Thursday 12 March 2026 at the Brighton Dome Studio Theatre. If you care about building for the web in a thoughtful, pragmatic way, you’ll feel right at home.</p>
<p>Use the code <code>Index10</code> for 10% off tickets.</p>
<p><a href="https://webdayout.com/?utm_source=WDO_Piccalilli%20Index&utm_medium=WDO_Piccalilli%20mailer&utm_campaign=Web%20Day%20Out">Book your ticket</a></p>
<hr />
<p>Thanks for reading this issue of <a href="https://piccalil.li/the-index/">The Index</a>. We really appreciate you being a subscriber. If you’re enjoying The Index, we’d really
appreciate it if you shared this issue with your friends too.</p>
<p>Until the next issue, take it easy 👋<br/>
Andy</p>
]]></description>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Some advice on managing your design career upwards</title>
        <link>https://piccalil.li/blog/some-advice-on-managing-your-design-career-upwards/?ref=main-rss-feed</link>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Ron Bronson]]></dc:creator>
        <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 11:55:00 GMT</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://piccalil.li/blog/some-advice-on-managing-your-design-career-upwards/?ref=main-rss-feed</guid>
        <description><![CDATA[<p>Becoming a design manager is a trade that most people make it without naming what they're giving up, which is why so many end up unhappy on the other side.</p>
<p>I've gone from individual contributor to manager to director, and the most consistent mistake I see is people treating management as the "next rung" instead of a fundamentally different job. We treat someone's ability to manage others as a reflection of their worth, yet we rarely teach what management actually requires. That gap does real damage — both to the people who take the role for the wrong reasons and to the people who end up reporting to them.</p>
<p>When someone asks me whether they should become a manager, I ask if they want responsibility for outcomes you don't directly control, or are they looking for validation, stability, or a raise? Those are not the same thing. At <a href="https://donmoynihan.substack.com/p/requiem-for-18f">18F</a>, managers weren't paid more than individual contributors. That stripped away the usual incentives and made intent visible very quickly. The people who stepped into management because they cared about others' growth thrived or wanted to take the next path on their career progression. There are pros and cons to a relatively “flat” org structure like this, but I found it useful.</p>
<p>In one of my early jobs, I had a senior director who trusted me with leading an org-wide project. Not only was I put in charge, they invited me to leadership meetings and let me speak.  That experience shaped my career in ways I could not have anticipated at the time. Someone with positional authority chose to see me, pulled me into the conversation, and made my perspective matter. That's the job. Being seen often equates with being invited, and managers who understand this spend their energy opening doors, not guarding them can develop talent.</p>
<p>Deciding to give up everyday responsibility on design choices is not an easy one. I miss front-line delivery work and might choose it in my next role. There’s nothing like actually working on the problems in front of you, rather than just triaging or dealing with escalations. I’ve had front-end designers worry about losing their craft, and they're right to. You will write less code.</p>
<p>If your identity is tightly bound to being the person who solves the hardest technical problem, management will feel like erosion. The increasing number of “player-coach” roles that let designers keep designing while managing are the best of both worlds, but it takes a mindset to both focus on delivering artifacts while also coaching someone who may or may not be on your same project.</p>
<p></p>
<p>A few years ago, I took over coaching a new high school tennis team. Early into my tenure, I would notice the players looking at me for validation during crucial moments of the match. This didn’t happen with my old teams, but I realized what I needed to do. One of the things I emphasize through the pre-season and our practices is trust. Not just from me, but the entire coaching staff. I want the players to understand that they’ve been given the tools to make decisions out on the court. Sometimes, they’ll make the right ones. Other times, it won’t work, but by reminding them that they get to make the call because you’re the one seeing the ball is a lesson that transcends sports. As a director, I want my managers to instill this into their teams and same for individual contributors, because it’s crucial that people learn it for themselves. Few things are more rewarding than seeing someone grow into their craft and having a hand in that.</p>
<p>It's also worth saying plainly: you can grow without managing people. Leadership is not synonymous with line management. I've met outstanding principal designers who influence direction, mentor deeply, and carry real organizational weight without ever owning performance reviews. Some of my favorite designers are professionals I knew we could trust with almost any task in their toolbox; folks that delight clients and their colleagues alike. With senior designers and principals, my question is just ensuring they’re staying engaged and challenged by the work. Coaching and mentoring are non-managerial ways for them to contribute without having to “manage” someone.</p>
<p>On the flip side, I've watched senior designers become the glue — mentoring, stabilizing, unblocking — and then stall because none of that work was owned or legible. If you don't claim authority somewhere, the organization will take the value and flatten the role. This can be one of the ways that elevating into a leadership role can be a way to build yourself into a growth role in a company where you’ve spent a long time. It’s also where considering opportunities elsewhere are a chance to reframe how people see you; new jobs with a different title can give you a chance to reinvent yourself.</p>
<p>If you're considering management, be honest with yourself. If what energizes you is coaching, advocating, and shaping how work happens beyond your own hands, then management can be deeply rewarding. If what energizes you is making things and being close to the work, protect that instinct. The field needs senior practitioners just as much as it needs good managers.</p>
        
        ]]></description>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Index: Issue #157</title>
        <link>https://piccalil.li/the-index/157/?ref=main-rss-feed</link>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Andy Bell]]></dc:creator>
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 11:55:00 GMT</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://piccalil.li/the-index/157/?ref=main-rss-feed</guid>
        <description><![CDATA[<h2><a href="https://www.disnetdev.com/blog/2026-01-20-skyreader-a-rss-reader-on-the-at-protocol/?utm_source=the-index&amp;utm_medium=newsletter">Skyreader: A RSS Reader on the AT Protocol</a></h2>
<p>It is the year of the personal site already, but maybe this tool makes it the year of RSS for you too?</p>
<h2><a href="https://adamsilver.io/blog/design-in-code-get-praise/?utm_source=the-index&amp;utm_medium=newsletter">Design in code, get praise</a></h2>
<p>A great rundown of <em>actual</em> prototypes being so much better than interactive pictures, AKA Figma prototypes.</p>
<h2><a href="https://tetralogical.com/blog/2025/12/03/common-misconceptions-about-disability/?utm_source=the-index&amp;utm_medium=newsletter">Common misconceptions about disability</a></h2>
<p>A thoroughly good article here. TetraLogical <em>again</em> coming through as the canonical resource for quality accessibility work.</p>
<h2><a href="https://gsap.com/SOTY-2025/?utm_source=the-index&amp;utm_medium=newsletter">GSAP site of the year 2025</a></h2>
<p>Very nice website, built by the legendary Cassie Evans.</p>
<h2><a href="https://cssstats.com/?utm_source=the-index&amp;utm_medium=newsletter">CSS stats</a></h2>
<p>This is really handy, especially the custom properties breakdown sand colour visualisations.</p>
<hr />
<p>P.S. <a href="https://tink.uk/?utm_source=the-index&amp;utm_medium=newsletter">this is a good website from personalsit.es</a>.</p>
        
        <h2>Sponsor message</h2><a href="https://webdayout.com/?utm_source=WDO_Piccalilli%20Index&utm_medium=WDO_Piccalilli%20mailer&utm_campaign=Web%20Day%20Out"><img src="https://piccalil.b-cdn.net/images/ads/clearleft-ad-1.png" alt="Web Day Out, featuring Rachel Andrew, Manuel Matuzovič and Jake Archibald. Brighton, March 16." /></a><p>The last few years have seen an explosion of capabilities within HTML, CSS, and vanilla JavaScript. If you haven’t been able to keep up, don’t worry: that’s what <strong>Web Day Out</strong> is for.</p>
<p>Join us in Brighton for a one day conference about what you can do in web browsers today. Featuring talks from Manuel Matuzovič, Rachel Andrew, Jake Archibald and more.</p>
<p><strong>When</strong>: Thursday 12 March 2026<br>
<strong>Where</strong>: Brighton Dome Studio Theatre, Brighton, UK<br>
<strong>Discount</strong>: use the code <code>Index10</code> to get 10% off your ticket</p>
<p><a href="https://webdayout.com/?utm_source=WDO_Piccalilli%20Index&utm_medium=WDO_Piccalilli%20mailer&utm_campaign=Web%20Day%20Out">Book your ticket</a></p>
<hr />
<p>Thanks for reading this issue of <a href="https://piccalil.li/the-index/">The Index</a>. We really appreciate you being a subscriber. If you’re enjoying The Index, we’d really
appreciate it if you shared this issue with your friends too.</p>
<p>Until the next issue, take it easy 👋<br/>
Andy</p>
]]></description>
        
      </item>
    
    </channel>
  </rss>
