<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
      <title>This day’s portion – Posts</title>
      <link>https://www.thisdaysportion.com/posts/</link>
      <description>
        
          More or less developed 250-1500 word essays, mostly about the web and its politics. Some of it’s technical.
        
      </description>
      <generator>Zola</generator>
      <language>en</language>
      <atom:link href="https://www.thisdaysportion.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
      <lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 20:52:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
      <item>
          <title>Minimum CSS</title>
          <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 20:52:48 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>mail@thisdaysportion.com</author>
          <link>https://www.thisdaysportion.com/posts/minimum-blog-css/</link>
          <guid>https://www.thisdaysportion.com/posts/minimum-blog-css/</guid>
          <description xml:base="https://www.thisdaysportion.com/posts/minimum-blog-css/">&lt;p&gt;I came across a blog with 147 lines of CSS today, including a couple of &lt;code&gt;font-face&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; declarations and a handful of custom properties. It looked pretty good and was perfectly readable, which is a testament to the author’s skill and judgement, the expressiveness of CSS and the robustness of browser defaults.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This sort of thing always gets me thinking about the minimum CSS required to publish a blog. You might start by arguing the answer to that question is &lt;i&gt;none at all&lt;&#x2F;i&gt;, and, strictly speaking, that’s true. Browsers style markup without you lifting a finger by putting margins between things, bolding, italicising, colouring links and lots of other things. You can even add a single line to your website’s &lt;code&gt;head&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; and get light and dark modes thrown in.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you take that approach you &lt;em&gt;will&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; hit on one problem, especially on a mobile. Any wide image will extend beyond the edge of the screen. You’ll still be able to see the whole image by scrolling horizontally, but that’s a pretty rubbish experience for your readers. So the bare minimum CSS is this:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;img {
	max-inline-size: 100% !important;
	block-size: auto !important;
}
&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Four lines. Sort of. If you want this to work with browsers that don’t understand logical properties like &lt;code&gt;block-size&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;, you’ll need to add a few more lines to set maximum width and height, check whether the browser supports logical properties with &lt;code&gt;supports&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; and, if it does, unset the maximum width and height and finally add the above lines.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It can get verbose quite quickly.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, that’s cool — a few lines of CSS and you’ve got a responsive website that doesn’t bork on a mobile. Except it’s not particularly readable on a laptop, even less so on a desktop monitor, what with everything extending across the whole of the screen. A comfortable line length (or &lt;dfn&gt;measure&lt;&#x2F;dfn&gt;) is — well, that’s a matter of art and science, conjecture, and dependent on a bunch of contextual factors, such as the language we’re writing in, font metrics and the nature of the text itself  — but it’s definitely less than the width of your desktop monitor.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which means you should probably add some CSS that stops lines getting too long:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;body {
	max-inline-size: 60ch;
}
&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But as we know, not every browser will understand &lt;code&gt;max-inline-size&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; (or &lt;code&gt;ch&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; for that matter), so you might want to do the &lt;code&gt;max-width&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;supports&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; dance again. Or, like me, you might reach a compromise and set a few basic readability rules that work on pretty much any browser on earth, and accept that readers using older or more obscure browsers miss out on goodies such as logical properties and the &lt;code&gt;lh&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; unit. If you’re feeling brave you’ll describe this as &lt;i&gt;progressive enhancement&lt;&#x2F;i&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And really, why stop at the text’s width if you’re looking to make your text as readable as possible? Measure is just one of several typographic elements you can tweak. For example, most browsers set line height (or &lt;dfn&gt;leading&lt;&#x2F;dfn&gt;) to 1.2 times the font size. That’s OK for headings and titles, but probably too narrow for long runs of prose. The ideal leading? &lt;i&gt;It depends on…&lt;&#x2F;i&gt; etc. etc., but probably sits somewhere between 1.35 and 1.6 times the font size.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add margins, padding and proximity to these bare-ish necessities. A border here and there to separate page blocks. You’ll probably need more than 147 lines, and the weird thing is you may find you reach a sort of CSS critical mass where your blog suddenly looks &lt;em&gt;designed&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;. &lt;del datetime=&quot;2026-01-25&quot;&gt;215&lt;&#x2F;del&gt; &lt;ins datetime=&quot;2026-01-25&quot;&gt;248&lt;&#x2F;ins&gt; lines at &lt;em&gt;this&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; precise moment in time, looking at &lt;em&gt;this&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; text. Expressive, combinational magic, CSS.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      <item>
          <title>“If Mein Kampf is your favourite book of course you’re a Nazi” is not a phrase I hoped to be writing in 2026 but here we are on the indieweb</title>
          <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 20:58:01 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>mail@thisdaysportion.com</author>
          <link>https://www.thisdaysportion.com/posts/manuel-kampf/</link>
          <guid>https://www.thisdaysportion.com/posts/manuel-kampf/</guid>
          <description xml:base="https://www.thisdaysportion.com/posts/manuel-kampf/">&lt;p&gt;Manuel &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;manuelmoreale.com&#x2F;thoughts&#x2F;moral-false-dichotomies&quot;&gt;arguing for some specious neutrality and detachment&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;…if I tell you my favorite book is the [sic] &lt;cite&gt;Mein Kampf&lt;&#x2F;cite&gt;, you have every reason to be perplexed and ask follow-up questions. But if you just assumed, based on that, that I’m a Nazi sympathizer, that would be wrong.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If “raising an eyebrow” is your only reaction to this statement with all [gestures] &lt;em&gt;this&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; going on: you’re a problem.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;bix.blog&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2026-01-21-no-that-really-does-make-someone-a-nazi&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Bix asks&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;…how do I square my appreciation for Ye Olde Blogroll (where I am listed) and People and Blogs (which just featured me) with his [Manuel’s] penchant for trying to discuss things from the perspective of a view from nowhere which only can ever look out at nothing and leave us wondering what the hell?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because the indieweb isn’t a good thing in and of itself. In theory, I could write a &lt;cite&gt;Mein Kampf&lt;&#x2F;cite&gt; appreciation blog, add a blogroll pointing to other Nazi blogs, and conduct a set of interviews with interesting Nazi bloggers and it’d be indieweb.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The question is indieweb &lt;em&gt;for what?&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; If it’s a means to extricate yourself from the noise of social media, fine — you’ll probably gather quite a following — but not if you’re then advocating for politicial detachment and neutrality when fascism is on the rise.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      <item>
          <title>Excavating Blogger</title>
          <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 07:32:20 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>mail@thisdaysportion.com</author>
          <link>https://www.thisdaysportion.com/posts/excavating-blogger/</link>
          <guid>https://www.thisdaysportion.com/posts/excavating-blogger/</guid>
          <description xml:base="https://www.thisdaysportion.com/posts/excavating-blogger/">&lt;p&gt;Over Christmas and the new year I wrote my way through some ideas on redefining the term “indieweb”. One of the conclusions I drew was that the indieweb doesn’t have to consist of websites that emphasise the &lt;em&gt;personal&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, small, cosy or whatever — we could (and should) look to include and share writing from journalists, academics and thinkers, with the ultimate aim of helping them move away from US-based intermediaries like Substack, Beehiv etc. (I should also make a belated resolution to not use &lt;em&gt;that&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; word anymore — I sometimes think it’s part of the problem.)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The web bit of indieweb is a lot different from the networks created on centralised, mediated platforms. A lot of the time, its existence is solipsistic — no-one knows what’s in my &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.thisdaysportion.com&#x2F;glossary&#x2F;rss&#x2F;&quot;&gt;RSS&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; stream, and I won’t know if you’ve responded to something I’ve written unless you ping me, whether that’s through a webmention, comment or email. This is why the practices of linking and subscribing are so important: there’s no other way to expand our indieweb horizons beyond a few popular authors that everyone shares — the indieweb influencers, if you like.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m finding that &lt;em&gt;my&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; stream is consisting of more and more blogging that’s simply kept going since its early-2000s hey day, a rich seam that needs to be rediscovered and nurtured again. Blogger — bought and still just about kept on life support by the squarely unindieweb Google — remains a source of just the sort of posts I’m referring to: erudite, quasi-scholarly, discursive. Yes, it’s predominantly white (as is the blogosphere in general, or at least &lt;em&gt;my&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; network), and still pre-occupied with early 2000s concerns such as hauntology, but we need more notes on &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;torpedotheark.blogspot.com&#x2F;2026&#x2F;01&#x2F;on-spinozas-four-great-disciples.html&quot;&gt;Spinoza’s four great disciples&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;blissout.blogspot.com&#x2F;2025&#x2F;09&#x2F;apropos-of-nothing.html&quot;&gt;the history of “poptimism”&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; in our streams.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is this important? Well, as I’ve argued before, if the indieweb is a “corner” of the web that’s mainly for a few tech-savvy, mass social media refusers, then &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.thisdaysportion.com&#x2F;posts&#x2F;amateurs-and-professionals-a-less-individual-indieweb&#x2F;&quot;&gt;writers will end up on Substack&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. While Blogger is of course owned by Google, it’s been so neglected it operates as an old-fashioned looking Bear or Pika, but with a distinct cohort of writers. That’s good, but not very resilient. For an example, look to Typepad, a similarly venerable, unloved platform that recently gave up the ghost. It hosted &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;chrisdillow.substack.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Chris Dillow&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; — one of the smartest independent economic commentators we have — and thankfully he’s now publishing again. On Substack.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      <item>
          <title>Adding “indieweb” to the glossary</title>
          <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 11:52:11 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>mail@thisdaysportion.com</author>
          <link>https://www.thisdaysportion.com/posts/adding-indieweb-to-the-glossary/</link>
          <guid>https://www.thisdaysportion.com/posts/adding-indieweb-to-the-glossary/</guid>
          <description xml:base="https://www.thisdaysportion.com/posts/adding-indieweb-to-the-glossary/">&lt;p&gt;At the risk of boring you, here’s yet another post about the indieweb. Well, more of an update, really. After spending a lot of the new year thinking through and writing about the thing I refer to as the “indieweb”, I’ve come up with a more polished definition, and added an entry to &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.thisdaysportion.com&#x2F;glossary&quot;&gt;my website glossary&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.thisdaysportion.com&#x2F;glossary&#x2F;indieweb&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Glossary entry for “indieweb”&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And if you’re looking for my one paragraph definition:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indieweb is a portmanteau of &lt;i&gt;independent&lt;&#x2F;i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;web&lt;&#x2F;i&gt;. It refers to creative web work, such as articles, essays, blog posts, art, video, social media style posts and audio, that is not published on large, centralised, commercial platforms.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actually, I’m not sure that is a portmanteau? Feel free to correct me.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At heart, the independent web is not publishing on the Facebooks, Substacks and Xs of this world. It’s a response to a societal threat.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Facebooks, Substacks and Xs have spent billions on making it easy to publish on their platforms in a search for fresh blood. It’s not surprising that publishing on smaller, often not-for-profit platforms (or even your own website) is more difficult, but we could make it easier by working collectively rather than in our metaphorical sheds.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, do get in touch if you have any thoughts on my definition, or if you’re interested in setting up some sort of collective, independent publishing effort.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      <item>
          <title>The indieweb’s future</title>
          <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 09:53:59 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>mail@thisdaysportion.com</author>
          <link>https://www.thisdaysportion.com/posts/indieweb-2030/</link>
          <guid>https://www.thisdaysportion.com/posts/indieweb-2030/</guid>
          <description xml:base="https://www.thisdaysportion.com/posts/indieweb-2030/">&lt;p&gt;Venkatram asked &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;vhbelvadi.com&#x2F;indieweb-carnival-round-up-dec-2025&quot;&gt;where we think the indieweb will be in 2030&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, which prompted me to explore what we mean by &lt;i&gt;indieweb&lt;&#x2F;i&gt; in a couple of posts.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I argue that the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;indieweb.org&#x2F;&quot;&gt;“official” definition&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; addresses concerns over Facebook and X’s ownership of our content, and that it represents an effort to wrest ownership from corporate social media to our websites.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.thisdaysportion.com&#x2F;posts&#x2F;defining-the-indieweb-for-2026&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Defining the indieweb for 2026&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.thisdaysportion.com&#x2F;posts&#x2F;amateurs-and-professionals-a-less-individual-indieweb&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Amateurs and professionals: towards a less individual indieweb&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2026 these concerns — at least in regard to microblogging style social media — have been allayed by the growth of the fediverse. There’s no longer any need to publish everything we write on our websites, including tweet-length updates, for syndication to other services. Nor do we need to collect and publish responses — such as likes, boosts and replies — using services such as Bridgy and micro.blog. Indeed, by doing this we lose some of the strengths of traditional website publishing, such as its asynchronicity and detachment from the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.humanetech.com&#x2F;youth&#x2F;the-attention-economy&quot;&gt;attention economy&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, companies such as Substack and Beehiv do form a threat to independent, longer form writing, which ironically appears to have become more popular since the official indieweb definition was first penned, albeit through the medium of the email newsletter. I contend that these platforms and their funders form a structural risk to expression and ultimately democracy through their commitment to scaling, commodification and profit.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2026, any &lt;i&gt;indieweb&lt;&#x2F;i&gt; definition should address these threats.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I argue that writers whose living is dependent on their writing, such as academics and journalists, are ill-served by the indieweb. There are several reasons for this, including a decades-old techno-optimism and individualism that values a hobbyist, DIY approach to building our own websites. As a result, when we talk about indieweb we generally mean a group of individual bloggers with some technical nous, rather than the “professional” writing you can find in magazines such as &lt;cite&gt;Tribune&lt;&#x2F;cite&gt; and &lt;cite&gt;The London Review of Books&lt;&#x2F;cite&gt; and more modern, online publications such as &lt;cite&gt;Lit Hub&lt;&#x2F;cite&gt; and &lt;cite&gt;Novara Media&lt;&#x2F;cite&gt;. Yet all of these are independent in that they offer a place for professional writers to publish their work away from the Substacks of this world.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to encourage more independent writing, we need to make it easier for professional writers to publish their work away from convenient, large scale platforms. While smaller platforms such as Pika and Bear offer viable alternatives, often they won’t provide the features — or feel — professional writers are looking for, and ultimately pose some of the same threats as Substack and Beehiv: vendor lock-in and reliance on small or even single person teams whose values we depend on to align with our own.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel the solution lies in moving away from a dependence on platforms to a less individual and less technological approach to publishing. We need more, ever smaller publications that handle hosting, design, content management and subscriptions, and that we form with people we trust and in some sense &lt;em&gt;know&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;. Ideally, we’d see more spontaneous collectives emerging, where those with the technological know how take a background role to support the writers. Something similar to how we can fairly easily create a Mastodon instance for a few members, but technologically agnostic and without the moderation workload.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Substack famously has a nazi problem, which prompted many of its members to move to other centralised platforms, such as Beehiv and Ghost. As these are structurally inclined to enshittify over time, I expect professional authors to become ever more concerned with the platforms they use. In theory, the indieweb as I define it should grow.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s possible that smaller platforms continue to develop and offer a home to Substack refugees — it would help if new platforms’ branding wasn’t so resolutely “indie”, and they considered the quality writing they could support. The Bear discover feed is a good idea, but it works on a simple upvoting system rather than any editorial judgement.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We seem to be miles away from being able to form blogging and writing collectives. This is understandable, of course: it’s reliant on volunteering and incurs costs. There is, however, a healthy collection of volunteer-run Mastodon servers out there, which I expect is partly explained by the fact it’s relatively easy to set up a server. Perhaps this is where new, self-hosted platforms could help, or agreed sets of software. Is this a use for &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;bonfirenetworks.org&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Bonfire&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fediverse also has a well-developed understanding of the value of independent publishing, and seems to have moved on from the 1990s techno-optimism and individualism that still characterises the indieweb. To be blunt: it’s more politically active and inclined to collective thought and action.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for the hobbyist indieweb, I think it’ll grow very healthily, as more people take the time to learn how to set up their own site, and more Pika and Bear-like platforms develop. In turn, this will encourage more people to write about non-tech subjects, which may also encourage more professional writers.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And having read this post, you might be surprised to hear that this makes me really happy. The hundreds of personal feeds I subscribe to are a constant source of interest, knowledge and entertainment. Long may that continue.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      <item>
          <title>On using indieweb protocols like webmentions and keeping your website separate from social media</title>
          <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 10:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>mail@thisdaysportion.com</author>
          <link>https://www.thisdaysportion.com/posts/using-indieweb-tech/</link>
          <guid>https://www.thisdaysportion.com/posts/using-indieweb-tech/</guid>
          <description xml:base="https://www.thisdaysportion.com/posts/using-indieweb-tech/">&lt;p&gt;Venkatram thoroughly — and entertainingly — &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;vhbelvadi.com&#x2F;indieweb-carnival-round-up-dec-2025&quot;&gt;rounds up the responses&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to his &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;indieweb.org&#x2F;IndieWeb_Carnival&quot;&gt;indieweb carnival&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; question &lt;q&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;vhbelvadi.com&#x2F;indieweb-carnival-future&quot;&gt;…where do you see the IndieWeb in 2030, just five short years from now?&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;q&gt; In it he discusses my post &lt;cite&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.thisdaysportion.com&#x2F;posts&#x2F;defining-the-indieweb-for-2026&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Defining the indieweb for 2026&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;cite&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn’t get round to actually answering the question in December — banging out three longish posts in two days was always a little ambitious — but I will try and complete the triptych this weekend. Unfortunately, I’m back at work tomorrow, and we’re playing Oxford this afternoon.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, Venkatram wryly notes that despite my claim that &lt;q&gt;trying to recreate social media on websites through protocols and processes such as POSSE and webmentions is no longer necessary&lt;&#x2F;q&gt; I did in fact ping him a notification using a… &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;indieweb.org&#x2F;Webmention&quot;&gt;webmention&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; 😀&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess I should make it clear that I don’t think you need webmentions or &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;indieweb.org&#x2F;POSSE&quot;&gt;POSSE&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; in order to try and recreate the mechanics of social media on websites — and in fact it’s better not to do this. They can make your posting and pinging life a little more convenient, though.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, I linked to 29 other sites in &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.thisdaysportion.com&#x2F;posts&#x2F;amateurs-and-professionals-a-less-individual-indieweb&#x2F;&quot;&gt;my last blog post&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, and posted a link to the article from my fediverse account, along with a summary. &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;echofeed.app&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Echofeed&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; automates sending webmentions to any external site I reference in a post, and will toot the link from my Mastodon account when I publish. I &lt;em&gt;could&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; do both of these things manually by sending emails or just writing a new toot, but Echofeed saves a bit of effort. And I’ll be honest, it’s a nice feeling when a system you’ve hooked up actually works.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, I wouldn’t use webmentions and POSSE to post every waking thought and reaction to my website before syndicating them to Mastodon, and then pull in all the responses to my site. Apart from the effort involved, my site is something entirely different from social media, and all the better for &lt;em&gt;not&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; recreating the attention economy of likes, boosts, follower counts and responses. Also, who wants to feed the man all that &lt;em&gt;data&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s value in extricating our blogs from the gruesome mechanics of social media, such as publishing likes and boosts. I have an ambivalent enough relationship with my fediverse account as it is.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, it’s New Years Day. If you’re reading this, thank you, and have a safe, fulfilling 2026 x&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      <item>
          <title>Amateurs and professionals: towards a less individual indieweb</title>
          <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 17:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>mail@thisdaysportion.com</author>
          <link>https://www.thisdaysportion.com/posts/amateurs-and-professionals-a-less-individual-indieweb/</link>
          <guid>https://www.thisdaysportion.com/posts/amateurs-and-professionals-a-less-individual-indieweb/</guid>
          <description xml:base="https://www.thisdaysportion.com/posts/amateurs-and-professionals-a-less-individual-indieweb/">&lt;p&gt;In my last post I considered &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.thisdaysportion.com&#x2F;posts&#x2F;defining-the-indieweb-for-2026&#x2F;&quot;&gt;what the term &lt;i&gt;indieweb&lt;&#x2F;i&gt; means as we enter 2026&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, hitting on this definition:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The IndieWeb is a people-focused alternative to the “corporate web”. It consists of creative websites such as blogs that are not published on closed, corporate platforms characterised by VC-funding, scale and marketisation.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea is to frame the indieweb as a response to a threat from corporate platforms, especially those dealing in long form articles, such as Substack and Beehiv. An independent web offers a place for us to publish essays and articles without corporate intermediaries, who, I would argue, pose an existential threat to expression and even democracy.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Side note: I appreciate I need to spell out the how of this in more detail at some point, and that I can sound like a crazed conspiracy theorist. Bear with me.)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The current &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;indieweb.org&#x2F;&quot;&gt;“official” indieweb definition&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; refers to &lt;q&gt;personal websites&lt;&#x2F;q&gt;, a reference you’ll note I have ruthlessly excised. Why? Well, I feel it suggests the indieweb is a mainly hobbyist pursuit, something we tinker with on our own, rather than somewhere you’ll find “proper” writing with a broader appeal.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;call-out&quot;&gt;
&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;A note on amateurism&lt;&#x2F;summary&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be clear, I am all for amateurism, not least because I am an amateur writer. I don’t write for a living. I work at a university, but I’m not an academic.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And as the great man says:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;…in communist society, where nobody has one exclusive sphere of activity but each can become accomplished in any branch he wishes, society regulates the general production and thus makes it possible for me to do one thing today and another tomorrow, to hunt in the morning, fish in the afternoon, rear cattle in the evening, blog after dinner…&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;details&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d argue that one of the positive outcomes of the internet DIY culture is that it does allow anyone to write, and that writing without a home in traditional media publications can be better than what you’ll find in the NYT’s and Guardians of this world. Take &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.theguardian.com&#x2F;technology&#x2F;2025&#x2F;dec&#x2F;30&#x2F;ai-pull-plug-pioneer-technology-rights&quot;&gt;The Guardian’s coverage of AI&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; compared with anything from &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;2ndbreakfast.audreywatters.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Audrey Watters&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;garymarcus.substack.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Gary Marcus&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;thetechbubble.substack.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Edward Ongweso Jr&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But if the corporate web poses a danger to expression and democracy, we need more “professional” writers who are unable to find a home for their writing in traditional outlets to publish on the indieweb. This could be authors, journalists and academics — anyone whose writing is a part of their professional existence, paid or not. Platforms such as Substack shouldn’t be where they end up.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For writers, the threat from the corporate platforms is insidious — it aims to make small businesses, DIYers and grifters of us all before setting us in competition with each other, to then be monetised in a marketplace it controls. Read this fascinating &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;techcrunch.com&#x2F;2025&#x2F;11&#x2F;23&#x2F;beehiivs-ceo-isnt-worried-about-newsletter-saturation&#x2F;&quot;&gt;interview with Beehiv founder Tyler Den&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for an insight into how the platforms see what they label “content creation”. There’s no mention of writing itself, or its quality — just the ability to create a personal brand on his platform:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year, we’ve seen tons of these journalists, whether it’s from The Washington Post or other traditional outlets, where these people have built up these personal brands, they have their beat, they know their audience really well, and they actually now have the tools and capabilities to go independent. I think that’s inspiring and fun and interesting, and ideally, we can be part of the toolkit to help empower them.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, there are very sound reasons for professional writers ending up on Beehiv. There’s the convenience, its brand recognition, the ease of setting up subscriptions and payments — and the (promised, at least) access to a potentially lucrative market.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A hobbyist indieweb doesn’t offer these features, and without the resources of a Substack they can be hard (but not impossible) to set up.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I think there’s also something in how the indieweb presents itself to the outside world that doesn’t talk to professional writers. The term “indieweb” itself is homespun. That’s fine, of course, but I feel there should be room for writing that isn’t quite as ramshackle, cosy or even &lt;em&gt;personal&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And, just like the mediated, corporate web, the indieweb sees the world from an individual perspective: &lt;em&gt;my&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; website, &lt;em&gt;my&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; domain — an essentially DIY effort. What if I don’t have the time, inclination or skills to set up my own website?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So how do we get more professional writers publishing on the indieweb?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We could start by extending our definition beyond the individual and hobbyist, and admit more actually-independently published authors who are not writing on their own website. Not every professional writer is a brand on Substack — there are plenty of magazines out there regularly publishing high quality articles from household names (well, to my household, anyway). Some — the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;lrb.co.uk&quot;&gt;LRB&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;tribunemag.co.uk&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Tribune&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.redpepper.org.uk&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Red Pepper&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, for example — are decades old, venerable publications. Some have a history of fighting fascism.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are also many newer, independent publications emerging online — a quick scan of my RSS feed returns &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;corporatewatch.org&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Corporate Watch&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;crimethinc.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;CrimethInc&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;jacobin.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Jacobin&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.liberalcurrents.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Liberal Currents&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;lithub.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Lit Hub&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.mcsweeneys.net&#x2F;&quot;&gt;McSweeney’s&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;newsocialist.org.uk&#x2F;&quot;&gt;New Socialist&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;novaramedia.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Novara Media&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.radicalphilosophy.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Radical Philosophy&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;salvage.zone&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Salvage&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;thebeemagazine.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;The Bee&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;national.thelead.uk&#x2F;&quot;&gt;The Lead&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;theluddite.org&#x2F;&quot;&gt;The Luddite&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;manchestermill.co.uk&#x2F;&quot;&gt;The Mill&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;thequietus.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;The Quietus&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;totalpropaganda.net&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Total Propaganda&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, in addition to the hundreds of personal blogs I subscribe to. There’s a certain melancholy in rediscovering a magazine feed that hasn’t published for a year or two, but it is a lively, ever-changing scene.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Admitting these writers begins by simply subscribing to (possibly financially), engaging with and linking to their publishers on our websites and beyond. I post &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.thisdaysportion.com&#x2F;links&#x2F;&quot;&gt;hundreds of links&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; here every year, often from these types of publications — I also syndicate them (a use for POSSE!) to my Mastodon account (you can even &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.thisdaysportion.com&#x2F;links&#x2F;index.xml&quot;&gt;subscribe to the Links RSS feed&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have some &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.thisdaysportion.com&#x2F;posts&#x2F;blogging-collectively&#x2F;&quot;&gt;thoughts on a more collective indieweb&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, where those who have the skills to set up a website simply help those that don’t, rather than leaving everyone to skill-up themselves. This is a longer term aim, along with the introduction of more platforms aimed at professional writers. The likes of &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;pika.page&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Pika&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;bearblog.dev&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Bear&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; feel resolutely &lt;em&gt;hobbyist&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; to me, although perhaps &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;write.as&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Write.as&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; has a broader, more writerly appeal?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ideally, I’d like to see more spontaneous collective publications arise. Not necessarily branded magazines, but groups of like minded individuals providing a website to edit, publish and promote each others’ writing, as well as newcomers without the time and resources to do it themselves. Anything that helps us overcome the individualism inherent to publishing on both the indieweb and corporate platforms.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that leaves just one more thing before I finally get round to answering &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;vhbelvadi.com&#x2F;indieweb-carnival-future&quot;&gt;Venkatram’s question about the future of the indieweb&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. My updated definition still includes &lt;i&gt;people-focused&lt;&#x2F;i&gt;, but I want to move away from it being quite as bound to personality — and it sounds a bit management-speak, anyway. How does this sound?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The IndieWeb is a freer, more meaningful alternative to the “corporate web”. It consists of creative websites such as blogs that are not published on closed, corporate platforms characterised by VC-funding, scale and marketisation.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      <item>
          <title>Defining the indieweb for 2026</title>
          <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 15:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>mail@thisdaysportion.com</author>
          <link>https://www.thisdaysportion.com/posts/defining-the-indieweb-for-2026/</link>
          <guid>https://www.thisdaysportion.com/posts/defining-the-indieweb-for-2026/</guid>
          <description xml:base="https://www.thisdaysportion.com/posts/defining-the-indieweb-for-2026/">&lt;p&gt;Venkatram asks &lt;q&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;vhbelvadi.com&#x2F;indieweb-carnival-future&quot;&gt;…where do you see the IndieWeb in 2030, just five short years from now?&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;q&gt;, a seemingly simple question which invites a not-so-simple answer. Before replying, I thought it would be worth reviewing what the indieweb is and has become since &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.thisdaysportion.com&#x2F;posts&#x2F;indiewebish&#x2F;&quot;&gt;I explored the term&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; getting on for five years ago.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s start with &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;indieweb.org&#x2F;&quot;&gt;the “official” definition&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The IndieWeb is a people-focused alternative to the “corporate web”.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We are a community of independent and personal websites based on the principles of: owning your domain and using it as your primary online identity, publishing on your own site first (optionally elsewhere), and owning your content.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This still seems fairly solid, even if it’s grounded in a set of late-2010s concerns and view of the web. Ceding one’s social media content to proprietary, locked down corporate platforms like Twitter and Facebook was an ongoing worry back then, exacerbated by our increasing awareness of big tech’s role in events such as Brexit and the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.amnesty.org&#x2F;en&#x2F;latest&#x2F;news&#x2F;2022&#x2F;09&#x2F;myanmar-facebooks-systems-promoted-violence-against-rohingya-meta-owes-reparations-new-report&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Myanmar military’s atrocities against the Rohingya people&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. That’s why, I think, this definition of the indieweb emphasises “personal” and “ownership” — it’s trying to recreate social media through the medium of the website.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would argue the fediverse has solved these problems, and that trying to recreate social media on websites through protocols and processes such as &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;indieweb.org&#x2F;POSSE&quot;&gt;POSSE&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;indieweb.org&#x2F;Webmention&quot;&gt;webmentions&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is no longer necessary. I can set up my own fediverse server, or join one that broadly aligns with my values and choose to move to another should that change, taking my social graph with me. If the server shuts down, I can download an archive of my content.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Syndicating every post from my site to social media is possible — and quite satisfying — but represents a lot of work for little practical return. Blogs are self-contained entities which are easily shared through separate protocols and platforms, such as linking from other websites, email, RSS and, yes, social media. There’s little need to stitch together a Frankenstein’s monster on the site itself — after all, this is how blogging communities have been formed for decades.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, we could argue that keeping public, social streams — represented by, say, a list of likes and boosts — away from the writing allows us to sidestep social media’s structural problems, such as its &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.thisdaysportion.com&#x2F;posts&#x2F;six-commenting-principle-and-broadcast-twitter&#x2F;&quot;&gt;synchronicity and commodification&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. There is value in the traditional, separated website and blog, and its methods of sharing and responding.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, there is no doubt a &lt;q&gt;people-focused alternative to the “corporate web”&lt;&#x2F;q&gt; is as important now as it was 5-10 years ago. That corporate web has expanded — we still contend with X and Facebook, as well as services such as Substack and Beehiv. Some may appear to offer more ethical alternatives, but they share the same underlying problems: VC-funded growth, vendor lock-in and the marketisation of what they crudely term &lt;i&gt;content&lt;&#x2F;i&gt;. Ultimately, all are inimical to writing as a whole, and, when we consider their normalisation of fascism and hyper-individualism, democracy itself.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, an updated definition of the indieweb needs to respond to a more relevant set of problems. Here’s what I’m going with:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The IndieWeb is a people-focused alternative to the “corporate web”. It consists of creative websites such as blogs that are not published on closed, corporate platforms characterised by VC-funding, scale and marketisation.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s opinionated, but I think these times demand we take a stance. It’s also flexible enough to include smaller, but-still-centralised platforms, such as &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;pika.page&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Pika&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;pika.page&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Bear&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, even if I do think &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.thisdaysportion.com&#x2F;posts&#x2F;collectives-not-more-tech&#x2F;&quot;&gt;community-powered self-hosting&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is ultimately the healthiest approach to publishing websites.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve also tried to move away from the individualism of the original definition (&lt;em&gt;your&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; domain, &lt;em&gt;your own&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; website etc.), which I think reflects the way in which social media, and tech in general, encourages us to view ourselves as self-contained, individual units within a web economy. This allows for joint publication efforts, which I’ll touch on in the next post. I better get a move on — I see I’ve only got 33 hours or so to actually answer Venkatram’s question 😁&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Updated 31 Dec for clarity.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      <item>
          <title>Publishing books in RSS episodes</title>
          <pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 07:41:50 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>mail@thisdaysportion.com</author>
          <link>https://www.thisdaysportion.com/posts/publishing-books-via-rss/</link>
          <guid>https://www.thisdaysportion.com/posts/publishing-books-via-rss/</guid>
          <description xml:base="https://www.thisdaysportion.com/posts/publishing-books-via-rss/">&lt;p&gt;A few years back I speculated &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.thisdaysportion.com&#x2F;posts&#x2F;books-that-are-never-finished&#x2F;&quot;&gt;what a book published online – rather than just marketed and distributed via the web – might look like&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Apart from its more fluid, less canonical nature, it struck me that the web offers a way to serialise novels by publishing them in an &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.thisdaysportion.com&#x2F;glossary&#x2F;rss&#x2F;&quot;&gt;RSS&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; feed to a schedule, which is what the very cool &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;lettrss.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;lettrss&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; does. Appropriately enough, its current book is &lt;cite&gt;A Christmas Carol&lt;&#x2F;cite&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Victorians were great serialisers, not least because serialisation meant an author could earn more money than by just publishing a single novel. Readers also loved serials – long Victorian novels are made more digestible when they’re split into 50 bite-size snacks, and a story with cliffhangers and complete-in-themselves episodes gives a subscriber something to look forward to every week.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Magazines such as &lt;cite&gt;The Strand&lt;&#x2F;cite&gt; would periodically publish novel episodes or short stories from collections such as &lt;cite&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;sherlock.leonpaternoster.com&quot;&gt;The Adventures of Sherlock Holmes&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;cite&gt;. Publishing to a schedule – and in response to commercial needs – influenced the form of the novel. It becomes episodic, a series of self-contained acts, each with a beginning, middle and cliffhanger end. This form probably reaches its apogee in &lt;cite&gt;Bleak House&lt;&#x2F;cite&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;details class=&quot;call-out&quot;&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Bleak house&lt;&#x2F;cite&gt; spoiler&lt;&#x2F;summary&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can’t think of many finer single episodes in literature than the account of Tulkinghorn’s murder. Of course, we won’t find out who committed the murder until a later episode.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;details&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RSS can replicate the features of serialisation. In the same way we might have bought a copy of &lt;cite&gt;The Strand&lt;&#x2F;cite&gt; every week, we can anticipate a new entry in our feed. And once it lands there, we can even control its appearance and choose the device we read it on.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, this only really works with novels and short stories that were written by now-dead authors – you can’t paywall or DRM RSS. The only cost is hosting static files and the labour involved in converting books to atom or RSS, which is trivial if you have the HTML to hand and can work with a &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.thisdaysportion.com&#x2F;glossary&#x2F;static-site-generator&#x2F;&quot;&gt;static site generator&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it would be interesting to see a yet unpublished work serialised in RSS. Perhaps it could work with a pay-what-you-want or membership model, or, better still, perhaps we can envisage a magazine-style collective publisher, giving you access to lots of new works for a monthly fee.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      <item>
          <title>On not choosing nice versions of AI</title>
          <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 08:12:40 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>mail@thisdaysportion.com</author>
          <link>https://www.thisdaysportion.com/posts/no-nice-ai/</link>
          <guid>https://www.thisdaysportion.com/posts/no-nice-ai/</guid>
          <description xml:base="https://www.thisdaysportion.com/posts/no-nice-ai/">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;…of all the actions a man may take in order to create himself as he wills to be, there is not one which is not creative, at the same time, of an image of man such as he believes he ought to be.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whenever anyone states that “AI is the future, so…” or “many people are using AI anyway, so…” they are not only expressing an opinion — they‘re shaping that future.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I read this sort of opinion fairly often in my RSS stream, which may be surprising considering my views on LLMs and therefore who I choose to follow.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps it’s because of a residual respect for exciting new tech among folk who, like me, spend a lot of time with little computing machines. Maybe some don’t like discussion with an adversarial tone, where they’re asked to make a &lt;em&gt;choice&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; about something beyond its supposed technical utility. Maybe they’ve found what’s broadly termed “AI” useful at some point. Maybe they even think LLMs are a societal good, having not experienced any direct harm.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anil Dash published one of these articles recently, essentially arguing that because many millions of people are freely using LLMs, &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.anildash.com&#x2F;2025&#x2F;11&#x2F;14&#x2F;wanting-not-to-want-ai&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Mozilla’s choice to integrate “safe” AI into Firefox is a net, protective good&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It bore all the hallmarks of an “it’s the future, so…” argument. Firstly, there was the breezy “this call will be recorded before we move on to your query”-like list of AI’s harms in the first paragraph (&lt;q&gt;Good morning, just a few things before we deal with your question. Genocide, mass unemployment, fascism, misinformation, environmental destruction. Now, how can I help you today?&lt;&#x2F;q&gt;)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then we have the (unlinked) assertion that “millions of people find AI-generated media images emotionally moving”, which might be true, but doesn’t represent LLMs’ main, more worrying use — &lt;q&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;marcwatkins.substack.com&#x2F;p&#x2F;recapping-openais-education-forum&quot;&gt;the majority of the active weekly users of ChatGPT are students&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;q&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then the appeal to a silent majority of “normal”, reasonable, but ultimately &lt;em&gt;passive&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; users — your friends and family no less — who, I hate to break it to you, while they are there to be persuaded, don’t like your &lt;em&gt;tone&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;. Compare these folk with the “rabid” “zealots” criticising Mozilla for adopting AI.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As ever with these sorts of articles, there’s a profound unwillingness to actually engage with an argument unless it’s in abstract terms, and an equally profound dislike of “ethical” discussion that asserts you have to &lt;em&gt;choose&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; a side. Instead, we resort to appeals to tone and your average person in the street — to marketing, in other words.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The thing is, offering a “safer”-to-Firefox-users version of a technology that runs the catastrophic gamut of “undermining labor to appropriating content without consent to having egregious environmental impacts to eroding trust in public discourse” is weak tea, even if you did trust Mozilla to somehow protect &lt;em&gt;you&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, rather than simply offer &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;tabstack.ai&#x2F;&quot;&gt;a whitewashed, “ethical” brand of AI to the market&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, or for it not to be &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.anonymco.com&#x2F;about-us&quot;&gt;staffed by ex-Facebook execs&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. It’s like hoping for a nice fascism.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No, there is no meeting the AI behemoth half way: if you feel it’s structurally inimical to a healthy society, you should call it out as such, rather than mithering about people who &lt;em&gt;do&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; object, or appealing to a silent majority of “normal” people in an effort to use it safely.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mozilla should position itself as the anti-AI and anti-advertising browser, thereby expressing what web they want through choosing the right path. Going all in on a “safe” version is at best shuffling the deck chairs, at worst creating a nice brand for egregious technology.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, if there is a point to our blogging about the state of the world, it is to express how we want the world to be through our choices about it, whether we’re a blogger with half-a-dozen subscribers, or a tech influencer.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
    </channel>
</rss>