<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:base="https://tylersticka.com/">
  <title>Tyler Sticka</title>
  <subtitle>Personal website of Tyler Sticka, including selected web design and interactive projects, articles and more.</subtitle>
  <link href="https://tylersticka.com/journal/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://tylersticka.com/"/>
  <updated>2026-02-01T18:22:34Z</updated>
  <id>https://tylersticka.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name>Tyler Sticka</name>
    <email>hello@tylersticka.com</email>
  </author><entry>
    <title>The Keyboard I Never Wanted</title>
    <link href="https://tylersticka.com/journal/the-keyboard-i-never-wanted/"/>
    <updated>2026-01-23T05:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://tylersticka.com/journal/the-keyboard-i-never-wanted/</id>
    <content xml:lang="en-us" type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;tt&gt;Hello, RSS reader! 👋 This post has some bespoke art direction you’ll only see if you &lt;a href=&quot;https://tylersticka.com/journal/the-keyboard-i-never-wanted/&quot;&gt;view it directly&lt;/a&gt;. No hard feelings if you prefer to read here, I just wanted you to know! ✌️&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I used a Logitech K800 “Wireless Illuminated” keyboard for more than a decade. Its keys were soft and comfy. The wireless part made it easy to move around when I switched from a wordy task to an artsy one or vice versa. It conveniently shared a receiver with my mouse. I liked it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;_keyboard&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://tylersticka.com/images/xt51pc8s45-600.avif&quot; srcset=&quot;https://tylersticka.com/images/xt51pc8s45-300.avif 300w, https://tylersticka.com/images/xt51pc8s45-600.avif 600w, https://tylersticka.com/images/xt51pc8s45-900.avif 900w, https://tylersticka.com/images/xt51pc8s45-1200.avif 1200w&quot; sizes=&quot;
    (max-width: 767px) 100vw,
    600px&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;254&quot; alt=&quot;Product image of the Logitech K800 keyboard&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But eventually, the battery stopped holding a charge. Many keys were visibly worn down, some were sticking. So I looked for a replacement, starting with the same brand I’d had such a positive experience with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By that time, Logitech (or were they “Logi” now?) had retired the K800 in favor of their new (at the time) flagship professional keyboard, Craft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Craft was slick. Craft had a fancy dial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Craft cost twice as much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;_keyboard&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://tylersticka.com/images/SZlPvP8Ebt-600.avif&quot; srcset=&quot;https://tylersticka.com/images/SZlPvP8Ebt-300.avif 300w, https://tylersticka.com/images/SZlPvP8Ebt-600.avif 600w, https://tylersticka.com/images/SZlPvP8Ebt-900.avif 900w, https://tylersticka.com/images/SZlPvP8Ebt-1200.avif 1200w&quot; sizes=&quot;
    (max-width: 767px) 100vw,
    600px&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;156&quot; alt=&quot;Product image of the Craft keyboard&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I bought one anyway. The K800 served me so well, and this was its successor!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sure, the keys were flatter now, and more clicky like a laptop. The battery seemed pretty anemic from day one. The dial was fun, but relegated to volume control since the volume keys tended to stick (on macOS specifically, for some reason).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But switching between devices was easier! And it looked nice on my desk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, sunk cost fallacy fully in effect, I convinced myself to like it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until one fateful morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I sat in my office chair, woke my machine, typed my password… and felt a single key wobble awkwardly beneath my fingertip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I gentled lifted the loose keycap, turning it slowly between my thumb and forefinger to inspect every angle. A bit of plastic support on its underside had grown brittle enough to fall apart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I contacted Logitech support. I figured it was out of warranty, but surely they’d have some way to purchase a replacement keycap (or even a set) for a premium product they still (at the time) manufactured and sold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And after the usual customer service song and dance, they did give me an option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exactly one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Buy a whole new Craft. At full price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At last, the veil of the sunk cost lifted. “I don’t even really &lt;em&gt;like&lt;/em&gt; this keyboard,” I thought to myself. “It cost more than what it replaced and lasted a fraction of the time. If I’m going to spend the money, I might as well get something more reliable, something I can repair…”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh no.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was going to have to research keyboards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;this-is-not-my-beautiful-hobby&quot;&gt;This is not my beautiful hobby&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I wanted something repairable, then it had to be modular. And when it comes to modularity in keyboards, mechanical was clearly the way to go. A whole subculture of enthusiasts supported a thriving landscape of components and vendors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But all those options were &lt;em&gt;intimidating&lt;/em&gt;. Layouts, keycaps, profiles, plastics, printing methods, switches, O-rings, PCBs, lighting, plates, cases, connectivity and firmware options to evaluate, jargon and acronyms to decode, compatibility issues to catch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And pricing varied wildly. Some builds cost less than a food delivery, others more than a new MacBook, and it wasn’t always clear why. Materials? Technology? Scarcity? Brand?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It didn’t help that I lacked nostalgia for any particular &lt;em&gt;sound&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;feel&lt;/em&gt;. My only vivid memory of mechanical keyboards was being distracted by the loud &lt;em&gt;clicks&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;clacks&lt;/em&gt; bouncing off the walls and partitions of shared office spaces. This made evaluating reviews and impressions pretty tough, as they often emphasized an aesthetic experience I’d rather avoid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, I had some help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After seeing my plight on social media, two friends reached out with advice:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://markllobrera.com/&quot;&gt;Mark Llobrera&lt;/a&gt; posed a handful of initial questions via email, patiently (but enthusiastically) sharing &lt;a href=&quot;https://markllobrera.com/tags/keyboards/&quot;&gt;his deep well of keyboard knowledge&lt;/a&gt; throughout a lengthy correspondence.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/197221674@N02/&quot;&gt;Jason Kogler&lt;/a&gt; used mechanical keyboards already, but happened to be in the market for a new one around the same time, and our wish lists mostly overlapped. He helped refine and validate my choice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Big thanks to them for volunteering to educate me!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-i-chose&quot;&gt;What I chose&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Mark and Jason’s help, I picked out a &lt;strong&gt;Keychron K2 Max&lt;/strong&gt;, specifically the hot-swappable model in black with an aluminum frame. (This was last year, there are newer models now.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;_keyboard&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://tylersticka.com/images/gp644z6eP3-420.avif&quot; srcset=&quot;https://tylersticka.com/images/gp644z6eP3-210.avif 210w, https://tylersticka.com/images/gp644z6eP3-420.avif 420w, https://tylersticka.com/images/gp644z6eP3-630.avif 630w, https://tylersticka.com/images/gp644z6eP3-840.avif 840w&quot; sizes=&quot;
    (max-width: 636px) 100vw,
    420px&quot; width=&quot;420&quot; height=&quot;168&quot; alt=&quot;Product image of the Keychron K2 Max keyboard&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deciding factors:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Arrived assembled and functional. I needed a working keyboard!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reasonably priced. I just didn’t feel confident enough to justify the expense of a premium or boutique brand. (I wanted the mechanical keyboard equivalent of &lt;a href=&quot;https://daverupert.com/2025/07/always-buy-the-yamaha/&quot;&gt;the $200 Yamaha guitar&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Supports the most common, standard, full-size components. (I bought a cheap wrist rest to ease my transition from the lower-profile Craft.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Switches may be “hot-swapped” whenever, no soldering required. (This came in handy right away.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multiple connectivity options, with easy shortcuts to switch between three devices.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No number pad. Based on the dust my last one gathered, I figured I’d reclaim some desk space.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open-source firmware (&lt;a href=&quot;https://qmk.fm/&quot;&gt;QMK&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The “Super Red” switches it shipped with were still too loud for me, so I replaced them with &lt;a href=&quot;https://milktooth.com/products/silent-frozen&quot;&gt;TTC Silent Frozen linear switches&lt;/a&gt;. The upgrade went as smoothly as advertised, and I’m really happy with the result: Key presses are &lt;em&gt;far&lt;/em&gt; quieter, with a pleasant softness not unlike my K800 in its prime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I disabled the RGB lighting and haven’t missed it. As a result, the battery life is astounding: I’ve charged it exactly three times since it arrived seven months ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m still using the keycaps it came with, and they are… fine. I think I’d prefer the broader face of a more traditional key profile, but I’ve yet to spot a set with the right mix of extras and appearance, in stock at a price point I can justify. Someday!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;soapbox-time&quot;&gt;Soapbox time&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far, I’m much happier with this keyboard. It’s quiet, responsive, holds a charge forever. It’s heavy enough to feel stable, small enough to move around when I want. Easy to take apart, fix, clean or customize. I forget I’m using it, which was really the goal. Don’t think, just type!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That outcome is rewarding. Understanding my options (and the associated vocabulary) is empowering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I’m still irritated it was even necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Compared to the gorgeous, personalized, lovingly crafted keyboards I saw hobbyists share through the course of my research… or even compared to the strong opinions I hold for other tools of the trade (computer mice, drawing tablets, art supplies, software)… my keyboard needs seem pretty basic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The truth is, I’d have happily continued buying the same dependable, reasonably priced, off-the-shelf keyboard every 7–10 years. And to be fair, I received a few recommendations for less modular brands that might have fit the bill. But my trust has been eroded by the relentless trend toward products (in any category) with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DHXBacEH0qo&quot;&gt;increasingly higher costs and lower lifespans&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More and more it seems the only way to avoid sinking money into landfill fodder is to become an expert in &lt;em&gt;every, single, thing&lt;/em&gt;. And only if you’re lucky enough to have the time, money, support system and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spoon_theory&quot;&gt;spoons&lt;/a&gt; to do so… a very tall order, especially these days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like to learn. I like to tinker. But the obligation really kills the vibe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;panel&quot; id=&quot;just-putting-this-out-there&quot;&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;panel__title&quot;&gt;Just putting this out there…&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;panel__content rhythm&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re involved with a project or product that breaks this cycle and involves (or might benefit from) a web application, &lt;a href=&quot;https://tylersticka.com/about/#contact&quot;&gt;get in touch with me&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloudfour.com/and-you/&quot;&gt;my team&lt;/a&gt;. I’d love to work together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;</content>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>Faking a Fieldset-Legend</title>
    <link href="https://tylersticka.com/journal/faking-a-fieldset-legend/"/>
    <updated>2026-01-20T16:56:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://tylersticka.com/journal/faking-a-fieldset-legend/</id>
    <content xml:lang="en-us" type="html">&lt;p&gt;My buddy &lt;a href=&quot;https://chriskirknielsen.com/&quot;&gt;Christopher Kirk-Nielsen&lt;/a&gt; wanted to mimic the look of a &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;legend&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; inside a &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;fieldset&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; for a section of a blog post: Specifically, the way the &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;legend&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; element magically overlays and partially clips the border of the containing &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;fieldset&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chris posed this challenge &lt;a href=&quot;https://front-end.social/@chriskirknielsen/115692516298506089&quot;&gt;on Mastodon&lt;/a&gt;, where &lt;a href=&quot;https://social.lol/@tylersticka/115696450792695179&quot;&gt;I suggested a solution&lt;/a&gt; he ended up building upon for &lt;a href=&quot;https://chriskirknielsen.com/blog/yearnotes-2025/&quot;&gt;his 2025 Yearnotes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s a refined version of the demo I shared…&lt;/p&gt;

      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cloudfour.com/thinks/faking-a-fieldset-legend/&quot;&gt;Read more at Cloud Four…&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>My Favorite Games of 2025</title>
    <link href="https://tylersticka.com/journal/favorite-games-of-2025/"/>
    <updated>2025-12-23T17:55:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://tylersticka.com/journal/favorite-games-of-2025/</id>
    <content xml:lang="en-us" type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;tt&gt;Hello, RSS reader! 👋 This post has some bespoke art direction you’ll only see if you &lt;a href=&quot;https://tylersticka.com/journal/favorite-games-of-2025/&quot;&gt;view it directly&lt;/a&gt;. No hard feelings if you prefer to read here, I just wanted you to know! ✌️&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As much as I enjoy books, comics, music and animation, I find it easiest to write about video games. So instead of an all-encompassing media recap, I thought I’d focus on my personal favorites of the games I got around to playing this year, peppered with my own illustrations throughout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;released-this-year&quot;&gt;Released this year&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://store.steampowered.com/app/2134320/ENA_Dream_BBQ/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ENA: Dream BBQ&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a first-person narrative adventure that constantly surprised me with its surreal twists and exquisite animation. I’m very excited for future chapters!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;_fanart&quot; style=&quot;--h: 300;&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Formless Star’s three field researchers: Turbine (looking a bit downtrodden), Anemo (looking chipper) and Vane (looking confused)&quot; src=&quot;https://tylersticka.com/images/6mKarje2Nn-800.avif&quot; srcset=&quot;https://tylersticka.com/images/6mKarje2Nn-400.avif 400w, https://tylersticka.com/images/6mKarje2Nn-800.avif 800w, https://tylersticka.com/images/6mKarje2Nn-1200.avif 1200w, https://tylersticka.com/images/6mKarje2Nn-1600.avif 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 479px) 100vw, 800px&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;387&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://splendidland.itch.io/formless-star&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Formless Star&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a cozy, top-down, creature-collecting adventure with beautiful character designs and pixel art, irreverent writing and an abundance of heart for such a condensed little adventure. I found the ending quite touching!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.playstation.com/en-us/games/ghost-of-yotei/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ghost of Yōtei&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;’s story is more straightforward than that of &lt;a href=&quot;https://tylersticka.com/journal/favorite-games/#ghost-of-tsushima&quot;&gt;its predecessor&lt;/a&gt;, which has pros and cons. On one hand, I didn’t connect as deeply with this entry’s supporting cast. On the other, I felt a greater sense of agency in directing Atsu’s journey from humbler beginnings, with less obvious demarcation between primary and secondary objectives. It was a pleasure to lose myself in this gorgeous impression of 1600s Japan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;_fanart&quot; style=&quot;--h: 61;&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;An imagined encounter between the protagonists of ElecHead and Öoo&quot; src=&quot;https://tylersticka.com/images/63C4D_GQHN-480.avif&quot; srcset=&quot;https://tylersticka.com/images/63C4D_GQHN-240.avif 240w, https://tylersticka.com/images/63C4D_GQHN-480.avif 480w, https://tylersticka.com/images/63C4D_GQHN-720.avif 720w, https://tylersticka.com/images/63C4D_GQHN-960.avif 960w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 480px) 100vw, 480px&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;320&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nama Takahashi’s 2021 release, &lt;a href=&quot;https://namatakahashi.notion.site/elechead&quot;&gt;ElecHead&lt;/a&gt;, is an excellent (if &lt;em&gt;occasionally&lt;/em&gt; opaque) puzzle platformer. But this year’s follow-up, &lt;a href=&quot;https://namatakahashi.notion.site/oooo&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Öoo&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; impressed me. I felt that satisfying “a-ha!” moment again and again as I crawled and combusted my way through a colorful and quirky microbiome, never once reaching for a walkthrough along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sega.com/like-a-dragon-yakuza/like-a-dragon-pirate-yakuza-in-hawaii&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Like a Dragon: Pirate Yakuza in Hawaii&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is the fourteenth (!!) game I’ve played in a series known for mixing emotional, street-level melodrama with unabashedly silly side content. This entry focuses overwhelmingly on the latter, with “substory” vibes throughout from moment one of its truly &lt;em&gt;bonkers&lt;/em&gt; premise. Where else can I sail a pirate ship to &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtube.com/watch?v=9CBfIjSNQHw&quot;&gt;the attract theme from Daytona USA&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;_fanart&quot; style=&quot;--h: 295;&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Poco&#39;s small clown protagonist, running with rubber-hose arms stretched behind&quot; src=&quot;https://tylersticka.com/images/8SGkFHTOK_-540.avif&quot; srcset=&quot;https://tylersticka.com/images/8SGkFHTOK_-270.avif 270w, https://tylersticka.com/images/8SGkFHTOK_-540.avif 540w, https://tylersticka.com/images/8SGkFHTOK_-1080.avif 1080w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 479px) 100vw, 540px&quot; width=&quot;540&quot; height=&quot;405&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://store.steampowered.com/app/3454610/Poco/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Poco&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is an astonishingly good point-and-click adventure! The character models are goofy and adorable, the painted backgrounds are lovely, the puzzles are &lt;em&gt;just&lt;/em&gt; challenging enough, and there’s even a map and hint system. Demonstrates more thoughtfulness and polish than many longer, higher-budget games I’ve played.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://squeakross.cool/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Squeakross: Home Squeak Home&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; might be the best 2-D nonogram game ever? It builds on the foundations of Jupiter’s Picross games in terms of UI/UX, with many improvements I’m sure to miss in competing games. The puzzle quality is consistently top-notch, clearly authored by human beings. The decorating features never fully captured my interest, but the creative theming makes for a more memorable (and cozy) experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I’d be remiss not to mention &lt;a href=&quot;https://tiledwords.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tiled Words&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, my friend (and &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloudfour.com/&quot;&gt;Cloud Four&lt;/a&gt; alum) &lt;a href=&quot;https://paulmakeswebsites.com/&quot;&gt;Paul Hebert&lt;/a&gt;’s letter-shifting crossword puzzle challenge. It’s been a blast watching this evolve from a rough proof-of-concept into my favorite daily game to help kick-start my brain each morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&quot;panel panel--positive&quot; id=&quot;honorable-mention-roguelites&quot;&gt;&lt;h3 class=&quot;panel__title&quot;&gt;Honorable Mention: “Roguelites”&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;panel__content rhythm&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before this year, the only &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Roguelike&quot;&gt;roguelike&lt;/a&gt; game I’d really enjoyed was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.playbalatro.com/&quot;&gt;Balatro&lt;/a&gt;. But then I discovered &lt;a href=&quot;https://store.steampowered.com/app/3723470/Far_Fishing/&quot;&gt;Far Fishing&lt;/a&gt;, which led me to &lt;a href=&quot;https://poncle.games/vampire-survivors&quot;&gt;Vampire Survivors&lt;/a&gt;, then &lt;a href=&quot;https://store.steampowered.com/app/1942280/Brotato/&quot;&gt;Brotato&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://store.steampowered.com/app/3405340/Megabonk/&quot;&gt;Megabonk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like the way these games invert traditional “bullet hell” conventions for a play experience that’s action-packed yet strangely &lt;em&gt;relaxing&lt;/em&gt;. And the wealth of incremental items and upgrades makes for an incredibly addictive loop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As with many addictive things, enjoyability diminishes as the pace of rewards slows down, so I struggle to highlight any one title. But I was entertained enough by the subgenre in aggregate to merit acknowledgement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(I’m also enjoying &lt;a href=&quot;https://dogpilegame.com/&quot;&gt;Dogpile&lt;/a&gt;, a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Suika_Game&quot;&gt;Suika&lt;/a&gt;-like deck builder with appealing, cartoony visuals.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;new-to-me&quot;&gt;New to me&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These came out before 2025, but I first played them this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;_fanart&quot; style=&quot;--h: 280;&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;The Watcher looks determined, with Secretary floating above her shoulder&quot; src=&quot;https://tylersticka.com/images/dsJ-8BKhFV-600.avif&quot; srcset=&quot;https://tylersticka.com/images/dsJ-8BKhFV-300.avif 300w, https://tylersticka.com/images/dsJ-8BKhFV-600.avif 600w, https://tylersticka.com/images/dsJ-8BKhFV-900.avif 900w, https://tylersticka.com/images/dsJ-8BKhFV-1200.avif 1200w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 479px) 100vw, 600px&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;497&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sunsetvisitor.studio/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1000xResist&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (2024) is a triumph! There’s a surefootedness to it that’s remarkable for a team’s first game. The story is unique and fascinating throughout, the vocal performances are textured and believable, the soundtrack swells at all the right moments. I had literal dreams about this game until I reached its conclusion!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;_fanart&quot; style=&quot;--h: 78;&quot;&gt;
&lt;img style=&quot;--h: 60;&quot; alt=&quot;Crypt Custodian&#39;s feline protagonist, Pluto, trots along while looking unsure about their predicament&quot; src=&quot;https://tylersticka.com/images/_ZV3lJ5132-560.avif&quot; srcset=&quot;https://tylersticka.com/images/_ZV3lJ5132-280.avif 280w, https://tylersticka.com/images/_ZV3lJ5132-560.avif 560w, https://tylersticka.com/images/_ZV3lJ5132-840.avif 840w, https://tylersticka.com/images/_ZV3lJ5132-1120.avif 1120w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 479px) 100vw, 560px&quot; width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;420&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As much as I enjoy Kyle Thompson’s previous releases (&lt;a href=&quot;https://store.steampowered.com/app/1281790/SHEEPO/&quot;&gt;Sheepo&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://isletsgame.com/&quot;&gt;Islets&lt;/a&gt;), he really outdid himself with &lt;a href=&quot;https://tophat.studio/games_CryptCustodian.html&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Crypt Custodian&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (2024). I love the look of it: Characters with stylish silhouettes against lush and moody backdrops. Encounters provide just enough challenge without sacrificing the game’s surprisingly mellow tone. The UI affordances for telegraphing Pluto’s relationship to the ground are surprisingly effective: I found myself moving with the confidence of a 3D platformer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;_fanart&quot; style=&quot;--h: 140;&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;The unsettling visage of Norco&#39;s &#39;Drone Priest&#39; floats aloft against an impression of a polluted sky&quot; src=&quot;https://tylersticka.com/images/i5IUredDNs-600.avif&quot; srcset=&quot;https://tylersticka.com/images/i5IUredDNs-300.avif 300w, https://tylersticka.com/images/i5IUredDNs-600.avif 600w, https://tylersticka.com/images/i5IUredDNs-900.avif 900w, https://tylersticka.com/images/i5IUredDNs-1200.avif 1200w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 479px) 100vw, 600px&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://norcogame.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Norco&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (2022) is a thoughtfully designed point-and-click adventure set in a near-future dystopian Louisiana. Filled with characters that range from &lt;em&gt;strangely endearing&lt;/em&gt; to &lt;em&gt;truly repellent&lt;/em&gt;, the naturalistic dialog and undercurrent of humor kept me engaged through far more dark and upsetting (but effective and purposeful) story beats than I’d normally have the stomach for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://store.steampowered.com/app/1634860/Minishoot_Adventures/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Minishoot’ Adventures&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (2024) (&lt;a href=&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/app/1634860/discussions/0/3193619419608326566/#c3193619890122198223&quot;&gt;note the apostrophe&lt;/a&gt;) overcame my general dislike of “bullet hell” shooters with one brilliant design decision: You retain items and experience between deaths, rewarding both skill &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; perseverance. Before long, I’d settled into that cozy Zelda/Metroid exploration flow, wandering a bright and cartoony world, uncovering new skills and secrets, and dispatching a wide array of enemies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;_fanart&quot; style=&quot;--h: 250;&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;The Prince, looking carefree and cheerful&quot; src=&quot;https://tylersticka.com/images/4BFKw09Utz-400.avif&quot; srcset=&quot;https://tylersticka.com/images/4BFKw09Utz-200.avif 200w, https://tylersticka.com/images/4BFKw09Utz-400.avif 400w, https://tylersticka.com/images/4BFKw09Utz-600.avif 600w, https://tylersticka.com/images/4BFKw09Utz-800.avif 800w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 400px) 100vw, 400px&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a longtime fan of &lt;a href=&quot;https://tylersticka.com/journal/favorite-games/#katamari-damacy&quot;&gt;Katamari Damacy&lt;/a&gt;, I’m ashamed to admit I’d never played its direct sequel until &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.bandainamcoent.eu/katamari/we-love-katamari-reroll-royal-reverie&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We Love Katamari Reroll+ Royal Reverie&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (2023). While I prefer the original game’s soundtrack, less frequent banter, and slow ascent to an epic climax, I have to admit these courses are more fun to play and &lt;em&gt;replay&lt;/em&gt;. And the postmodern narrative is an inspired choice given creator Keita Takahashi’s conflicted feelings about directing a follow-up (as described &lt;a href=&quot;https://bossfightbooks.com/products/katamari-damacy-by-l-e-hall&quot;&gt;in L.E. Hall’s wonderful book&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.shredders-revenge.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles: Shredder’s Revenge&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (2022) gracefully iterates on the classic Konami brawlers with an expanded roster, improved controls, an overworld map and fewer “quarter-eating” frustrations. The visuals and audio &lt;em&gt;ooze&lt;/em&gt; (pun intended) polish and nostalgia in equal measure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;_fanart&quot; style=&quot;--h: 280;&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Loddlenaut&#39;s protagonist meets two of the game&#39;s fish-like &#39;loddles,&#39; both with friendly, cheerful expressions&quot; src=&quot;https://tylersticka.com/images/25OmT7gvYU-700.avif&quot; srcset=&quot;https://tylersticka.com/images/25OmT7gvYU-350.avif 350w, https://tylersticka.com/images/25OmT7gvYU-700.avif 700w, https://tylersticka.com/images/25OmT7gvYU-1050.avif 1050w, https://tylersticka.com/images/25OmT7gvYU-1400.avif 1400w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 479px) 100vw, 700px&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;525&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tend to dislike survival games, but &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.loddlenaut.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Loddlenaut&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (2023) won me over. There’s &lt;em&gt;just&lt;/em&gt; enough danger (managing resources, inventory and oxygen) and mystery (where’d all this gunk come from?) to keep me engaged but not frustrated. The art and aesthetic are super cute, the controls feel great, the vibes are cozy, and potentially monotonous tasks like cleaning and crafting are &lt;em&gt;just&lt;/em&gt; simplified enough to be fun. (If you fondly remember &lt;a href=&quot;https://info.sonicretro.org/Chao_Garden&quot;&gt;Chao gardens&lt;/a&gt;, you’ll probably enjoy the game’s “loddles” as much as I did.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pokecommunity.com/threads/pok%C3%A9mon-unbound-completed.382178/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pokémon Unbound&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (2022) is a fan-made, full-game overhaul of Pokémon FireRed with its own region, campaign and features. I’m amazed by how much the presence of honest-to-goodness, substantial side-quests, puzzles and mini-games (alongside &lt;em&gt;many&lt;/em&gt; quality-of-life improvements) reinvigorated my love for this decades-old formula.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;revisited&quot;&gt;Revisited&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve played all these before in some form or another, but gave them a fresh look in 2025.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;_fanart&quot; style=&quot;--h: 200;&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Jade and Pey&#39;j looking intensely at the viewer&quot; src=&quot;https://tylersticka.com/images/udyxXXSCLC-640.avif&quot; srcset=&quot;https://tylersticka.com/images/udyxXXSCLC-320.avif 320w, https://tylersticka.com/images/udyxXXSCLC-640.avif 640w, https://tylersticka.com/images/udyxXXSCLC-960.avif 960w, https://tylersticka.com/images/udyxXXSCLC-1280.avif 1280w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 479px) 100vw, 640px&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ubisoft.com/en-us/game/beyond-good-and-evil/20th-anniversary-edition&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Beyond Good &amp;amp; Evil: 20th Anniversary Edition&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (2024) convinced me to add the game to &lt;a href=&quot;https://tylersticka.com/journal/favorite-games/#beyond-good-and-evil&quot;&gt;my all-time faves&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though not without its flaws, the vibes of Beyond Good &amp;amp; Evil remain so special and distinct. I adore the Mediterranean-inspired environments (canals &amp;gt; roadways), the stylized character designs, the emphasis on exploration, photo­journalism and (approachable) stealth over combat, and Christophe Héral’s eclectic soundtrack. Whether or not &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.polygon.com/gaming/24191681/beyond-good-evil-2-development-what-happened&quot;&gt;its sequel ever escapes development hell&lt;/a&gt;, I appreciate this entry more with every playthrough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;_fanart&quot; style=&quot;--h: 110;&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Rayman, Murfy and Globox looking friendly (and a little dimwitted)&quot; src=&quot;https://tylersticka.com/images/jTyQK0iXVM-800.avif&quot; srcset=&quot;https://tylersticka.com/images/jTyQK0iXVM-400.avif 400w, https://tylersticka.com/images/jTyQK0iXVM-800.avif 800w, https://tylersticka.com/images/jTyQK0iXVM-1200.avif 1200w, https://tylersticka.com/images/jTyQK0iXVM-1600.avif 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 479px) 100vw, 800px&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I then revisited an earlier effort by the same team on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JXwnyu5FFlY&quot;&gt;my beloved Dreamcast&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.raymanpc.com/wiki/en/Rayman_2&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rayman 2: The Great Escape&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (1999). Each stage fully invests in its theme, with no one mechanic overstaying its welcome. I love the look of the game, too: Organic, hand-painted textures (especially gorgeous in the Dreamcast version) adorn lush forests, damp caves, creaking ships and rusty old factories. Character designs are whimsical, exaggerated and cartoony, the score is swash­buckling and catchy. While not without common issues of the era (camera, audio mix, etc.), it remains a standout in its genre.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;_fanart&quot; style=&quot;--h: 260;&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;A cloaked member of the Order of the EZIC star readying a message to deliver to the player&quot; src=&quot;https://tylersticka.com/images/iRWtkKDpkY-520.avif&quot; srcset=&quot;https://tylersticka.com/images/iRWtkKDpkY-260.avif 260w, https://tylersticka.com/images/iRWtkKDpkY-520.avif 520w, https://tylersticka.com/images/iRWtkKDpkY-780.avif 780w, https://tylersticka.com/images/iRWtkKDpkY-1040.avif 1040w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 479px) 100vw, 520px&quot; width=&quot;520&quot; height=&quot;431&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m not sure why I didn’t connect with &lt;a href=&quot;https://papersplea.se/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Papers, Please&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (2013) the first time I played. Maybe I’ve matured, or maybe &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.marsaftermidnight.com/&quot;&gt;Mars After Midnight&lt;/a&gt; excited the right synapses, but this year’s playthrough felt &lt;em&gt;radically&lt;/em&gt; better. I lost myself in the rhythm of the gameplay loop, I admired the interface and presentation, I took genuine interest in the story as I retried days to correct mistakes or discover new endings. I found myself looking for, and finding, glimmers of humor and lightness in the gloom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;_fanart&quot; style=&quot;--h: 60;&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Shadow holds a yellow chaos emerald, silently looking at the viewer&quot; src=&quot;https://tylersticka.com/images/bpV-GNbXU8-520.avif&quot; srcset=&quot;https://tylersticka.com/images/bpV-GNbXU8-260.avif 260w, https://tylersticka.com/images/bpV-GNbXU8-520.avif 520w, https://tylersticka.com/images/bpV-GNbXU8-780.avif 780w, https://tylersticka.com/images/bpV-GNbXU8-1040.avif 1040w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 479px) 100vw, 520px&quot; width=&quot;520&quot; height=&quot;520&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went into &lt;a href=&quot;https://sonicxshadowgenerations.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sonic X Shadow Generations&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (2024) primarily for the new “Shadow Generations” content. But I ended up mostly falling back into the core game, thanks to the removal of lives (emboldening me to experiment more with different paths) and much smoother performance (at least compared to the PS3/360 original). These improvements helped me better appreciate Generations’ stage designs, which pay homage to a surprisingly diverse range of Sonic’s history while standing on their own thanks to some really clever routes, stage-specific gimmicks and exciting set pieces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;_fanart&quot; style=&quot;--h: 300; padding: 6.5%;&quot;&gt;
&lt;img style=&quot;translate: -1% 0;&quot; src=&quot;https://tylersticka.com/images/LavtYyl44m-558.avif&quot; srcset=&quot;https://tylersticka.com/images/LavtYyl44m-372.avif 372w, https://tylersticka.com/images/LavtYyl44m-558.avif 558w, https://tylersticka.com/images/LavtYyl44m-744.avif 744w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 371px) 80vw, 372px&quot; width=&quot;372&quot; height=&quot;320&quot; alt=&quot;A chibi Samus Aran in her Fusion Suit&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After building &lt;a href=&quot;https://tylersticka.com/journal/game-boy-advance/&quot;&gt;my custom Game Boy Advance&lt;/a&gt;, I ended up replaying four 2-D Metroid games in a row, starting with my GBA’s visual inspiration and hopping between other titles/consoles from there:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.metroidwiki.org/wiki/Metroid_Fusion&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Metroid Fusion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (2002): &lt;span class=&quot;u-inline-block&quot;&gt;Beautiful and chilling&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.metroidwiki.org/wiki/Metroid:_Zero_Mission&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Metroid: Zero Mission&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (2004): &lt;span class=&quot;u-inline-block&quot;&gt;All-around approachable introduction&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.metroidwiki.org/wiki/Super_Metroid&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Super Metroid&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (1994): &lt;span class=&quot;u-inline-block&quot;&gt;Better every playthrough&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.metroidwiki.org/wiki/Metroid:_Samus_Returns&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Metroid: Samus Returns&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (2017): &lt;span class=&quot;u-inline-block&quot;&gt;Underrated&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;on-my-radar&quot;&gt;On my radar&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My backlog has modestly grown &lt;a href=&quot;https://tylersticka.com/journal/video-game-backlog-zero/&quot;&gt;since clearing it this Spring&lt;/a&gt;. Games I’m excited to play include &lt;a href=&quot;https://neva.game/&quot;&gt;Neva&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://venbagame.com/&quot;&gt;Venba&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.awaceb.com/tchia&quot;&gt;Tchia&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://mistermorris.games/haiku-the-robot/&quot;&gt;Haiku the Robot&lt;/a&gt;. (I guess I like two-syllable protagonist names ending in a vowel? Weird!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To &lt;em&gt;keep&lt;/em&gt; that backlog reasonable, I held off on plenty of 2025 releases that piqued my interest. I hope to eventually play &lt;a href=&quot;https://kaizengameworks.com/portfolio-items/promise-mascot-agency/&quot;&gt;Promise Mascot Agency&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://despelote.game/&quot;&gt;despelote&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://store.steampowered.com/app/2870350/Pipistrello_and_the_Cursed_Yoyo/&quot;&gt;Pipistrello and the Cursed Yoyo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://doottinygames.itch.io/kabuto-park&quot;&gt;Kabuto Park&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://store.steampowered.com/app/2393760/Tall_Trails/&quot;&gt;Tall Trails&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://swordoftheseagame.com/&quot;&gt;Sword of the Sea&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://henrygame.com/&quot;&gt;Henry Halfhead&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://hexecutable.itch.io/consume-me&quot;&gt;Consume Me&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://store.steampowered.com/app/2592160/Dispatch/&quot;&gt;Dispatch&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://skatestory.com/&quot;&gt;Skate Story&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sega.com/sonic-the-hedgehog/sonic-racing-crossworlds&quot;&gt;Sonic Racing: Crossworlds&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.marvel.com/games/marvel-cosmic-invasion&quot;&gt;Marvel Cosmic Invasion&lt;/a&gt;. (I’d also like to check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://compulsiongames.com/games/south-of-midnight/&quot;&gt;South of Midnight&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.doublefine.com/games/keeper&quot;&gt;Keeper&lt;/a&gt; when/if they release for PS5… they seem too lovely to confine to a handheld or older GPU!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m sure 2026 will stretch my wishlist even further. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.somethingwemade.se/toem2/&quot;&gt;TOEM 2&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://store.steampowered.com/app/2666920/Building_Relationships/&quot;&gt;Building Relationships&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://hermitandpig.com/&quot;&gt;Hermit and Pig&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.luckshotgames.com/big-hops&quot;&gt;Big Hops&lt;/a&gt; all seem like my cup of tea. I’m morbidly curious to try &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sega.com/like-a-dragon-yakuza/yakuza-kiwami-3-dark-ties&quot;&gt;a remake of my least favorite Yakuza game&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fabraz.com/#bubsy&quot;&gt;a Bubsy game that might actually be okay&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or maybe I’ll mostly replay &lt;a href=&quot;https://tylersticka.com/journal/favorite-games/&quot;&gt;old favorites&lt;/a&gt;. Or learn &lt;a href=&quot;https://godotengine.org/&quot;&gt;Godot&lt;/a&gt;, draw a comic, teach &lt;a href=&quot;https://tylersticka.com/journal/buster-how-is-that-comfortable/&quot;&gt;Buster&lt;/a&gt; a new trick, tinker with more electronics, pick up the guitar again, try some new recipes. Assuming the world continues to afford me leisure time, I’ll use it as I please. Life’s too short to succumb to &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fear_of_missing_out&quot;&gt;FOMO&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>Them’s the Breaks</title>
    <link href="https://tylersticka.com/journal/htmhell-advent-calendar-2025-15/"/>
    <updated>2025-12-15T17:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://tylersticka.com/journal/htmhell-advent-calendar-2025-15/</id>
    <content xml:lang="en-us" type="html">&lt;p&gt;On the web, it’s easy to take line breaks for granted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We get them for free between our headings, paragraphs, list items, &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; elements and more. We display them as-is in our code snippets thanks to &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;pre&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;. And most magically of all, our browsers insert breaks &lt;em&gt;automatically&lt;/em&gt; where lines of text (or other text-like “inline” elements) would otherwise outgrow their container.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But sometimes, that isn’t enough.&lt;/p&gt;

      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://htmhell.dev/adventcalendar/2025/15/&quot;&gt;Read more at HTMHell…&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>That time Steve Silberman wrote me a nice email…</title>
    <link href="https://tylersticka.com/journal/that-time-steve-silberman-wrote-me-a-nice-email/"/>
    <updated>2025-12-14T22:20:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://tylersticka.com/journal/that-time-steve-silberman-wrote-me-a-nice-email/</id>
    <content xml:lang="en-us" type="html">&lt;p&gt;It was July of 2009. Twitter wasn’t a cesspool yet, and I’d released two silly mashups using its API: &lt;a href=&quot;https://portwiture.com/&quot;&gt;Portwiture&lt;/a&gt;, which built a Flickr mood board from keywords you’d tweeted, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://tylersticka.com/journal/find-where-your-twitter-friends-blog-with-tweetplus/&quot;&gt;TweetPlus&lt;/a&gt;, which discovered where your friends were blogging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a random Wednesday morning, I welcomed this email to my inbox:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tyler:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just spent some time tweeting madly about Portwiture (like, almost too much) and then found TweetPlus.  I am a contributing editor of Wired magazine, and you are a genius. The UI messages in Tweet Plus are hilarious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Tyler Sticka has built two of the best – and most hiply designed – applications of the Twitter API in Portwiture and Tweet Plus. He’s a software poet.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s a true thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yay Tyler.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steve Silberman&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We began a brief correspondence. When I asked his permission to include that quote in my portfolio, Steve replied:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feel free to use that quote, I sent it to you for that purpose if it’s not too dorky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When he found a bug in Portwiture and I mentioned some API frustrations:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dude:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I dig the API issue.  You’re still a genius.  You’re one of the smartest web designers I’ve ever come across, and I’ve been coming across them since 1994.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully someday we’ll have a coffee. In the meantime, keep it up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steve&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s hard to overstate how much those messages meant (and still mean) to me. It’s not like Steve wouldn’t have been busy: Wired would publish his award-winning article “The Placebo Problem” just a few weeks after our chat (&lt;a href=&quot;https://bookshop.org/p/books/neurotribes-the-legacy-of-autism-and-the-future-of-neurodiversity-steve-silberman/29fa7f7942a2e266&quot;&gt;Neurotribes&lt;/a&gt; arriving quite a while after). His testimonial was featured on my website and résumé for many years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sadly, we never had that coffee: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thetransmitter.org/spectrum/the-legacy-of-steve-silberman-and-his-book-neurotribes/&quot;&gt;Steve passed away in August of last year&lt;/a&gt;. I missed the news at the time, lost in the chaos of election cycle coverage and fragmented social media. An offhand, past-tense reference in my Mastodon feed finally clued me in, prompting me to share this story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you like someone’s work, let them know.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>My Custom Game Boy Advance</title>
    <link href="https://tylersticka.com/journal/game-boy-advance/"/>
    <updated>2025-11-21T21:40:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://tylersticka.com/journal/game-boy-advance/</id>
    <content xml:lang="en-us" type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;tt&gt;Hello, RSS reader! 👋 This post has some bespoke art direction you’ll only see if you &lt;a href=&quot;https://tylersticka.com/journal/game-boy-advance/&quot;&gt;view it directly&lt;/a&gt;. No hard feelings if you prefer to read here, I just wanted you to know! ✌️&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After a couple years of enjoying &lt;a href=&quot;https://tylersticka.com/journal/neo-geo-pocket-color/&quot;&gt;my customized Neo Geo Pocket Color&lt;/a&gt;, I was ready for another handheld project. This time, I decided to modify an original AGB model Game Boy Advance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;A modified Game Boy Advance with a clear blue shell, red triggers, translucent yellow buttons, and aftermarket backlit display (showing the Metroid Fusion title screen)&quot; src=&quot;https://tylersticka.com/images/v8AMeCId4C-800.avif&quot; srcset=&quot;https://tylersticka.com/images/v8AMeCId4C-600.avif 600w, https://tylersticka.com/images/v8AMeCId4C-800.avif 800w, https://tylersticka.com/images/v8AMeCId4C-1200.avif 1200w, https://tylersticka.com/images/v8AMeCId4C-1600.avif 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 479px) 100vw, 800px&quot; width=&quot;1600&quot; height=&quot;1200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;why&quot;&gt;Why?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I own a dozen or so Game Boy, Game Boy Color and Game Boy Advance cartridges, but no console to enjoy them on. (I long ago traded in my GBA toward a DS, then the DS toward a 3DS.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I considered a modern compatible handheld, such as the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.analogue.co/pocket&quot;&gt;Analogue Pocket&lt;/a&gt;. But these tend to mimic the vertical orientation of the original Game Boy line… understandably so, it’s iconic! But I’ve always preferred the ergonomics of a horizontal layout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This made &lt;a href=&quot;https://gbhwdb.gekkio.fi/consoles/agb/&quot;&gt;an AGB model&lt;/a&gt; the clear choice: Horizontal, common, and fully backwards-compatible (unlike a Game Boy Micro or Nintendo DS).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;aesthetic&quot;&gt;Aesthetic&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;_samus&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://tylersticka.com/images/7T1Mnhli50-640.avif&quot; srcset=&quot;https://tylersticka.com/images/7T1Mnhli50-240.avif 240w, https://tylersticka.com/images/7T1Mnhli50-320.avif 320w, https://tylersticka.com/images/7T1Mnhli50-480.avif 480w, https://tylersticka.com/images/7T1Mnhli50-640.avif 640w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 479px) 38vw, 316px&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; alt=&quot;Detail of the custom GBA focused on the yellow, translucent d-pad&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://tylersticka.com/images/FOncDgbyRs-640.avif&quot; srcset=&quot;https://tylersticka.com/images/FOncDgbyRs-240.avif 240w, https://tylersticka.com/images/FOncDgbyRs-320.avif 320w, https://tylersticka.com/images/FOncDgbyRs-480.avif 480w, https://tylersticka.com/images/FOncDgbyRs-640.avif 640w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 479px) 27vw, 226px&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; alt=&quot;Detail of the custom GBA focused on the rose red right trigger&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://tylersticka.com/images/LavtYyl44m-640.avif&quot; srcset=&quot;https://tylersticka.com/images/LavtYyl44m-320.avif 320w, https://tylersticka.com/images/LavtYyl44m-480.avif 480w, https://tylersticka.com/images/LavtYyl44m-640.avif 640w, https://tylersticka.com/images/LavtYyl44m-800.avif 800w, https://tylersticka.com/images/LavtYyl44m-960.avif 960w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 479px) 55vw, 452px&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;412&quot; alt=&quot;Chibi fanart by yours truly of Samus Aran in her Fusion Suit&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Game Boy Advance line sold &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nintendo.co.jp/ir/pdf/2007/070426e.pdf#page=21&quot;&gt;tens of millions of units&lt;/a&gt;, so the selection of aftermarket components is vast compared to that of the cult classic &lt;abbr title=&quot;Neo Geo Pocket Color&quot;&gt;NGPC&lt;/abbr&gt;. To narrow down my choices, I decided to pay homage to the first-party exclusive title I associate most with the &lt;abbr title=&quot;Game Boy Advance&quot;&gt;GBA&lt;/abbr&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.metroidwiki.org/wiki/Metroid_Fusion&quot;&gt;Metroid Fusion&lt;/a&gt;. Specifically, I wanted to echo the strikingly alien (almost aquatic?) look of Samus Aran’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.metroidwiki.org/wiki/Fusion_Suit&quot;&gt;Fusion Suit&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;how&quot;&gt;How?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I sourced the donor console from eBay after striking out at local thrift stores. It took a while, but eventually I found a reasonably-priced AGB with plenty of cosmetic scuffs and scratches (easier to see in person than in photos), a few parts in need of cleaning, but no signs of internal damage (water, corrosion, etc.).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;_before&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Holding the unmodified GBA at an angle to show its hard-to-read display&quot; src=&quot;https://tylersticka.com/images/WbkC04vOO4-800.avif&quot; srcset=&quot;https://tylersticka.com/images/WbkC04vOO4-200.avif 200w, https://tylersticka.com/images/WbkC04vOO4-400.avif 400w, https://tylersticka.com/images/WbkC04vOO4-600.avif 600w, https://tylersticka.com/images/WbkC04vOO4-800.avif 800w, https://tylersticka.com/images/WbkC04vOO4-1200.avif 1200w, https://tylersticka.com/images/WbkC04vOO4-1600.avif 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;
    (max-width: 767px) 100vw,
    360px&quot; width=&quot;1600&quot; height=&quot;1200&quot; /&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Before modification. (Is this thing on?)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The AGB’s fatal flaw is its lack of a backlight: Fixing that was my top functional priority. &lt;a href=&quot;https://retrogamerepairshop.com/collections/gba-displays/products/game-boy-advance-drop-in-720x480-ips-backlight-with-osd?variant=42373088018604&quot;&gt;A hispeedido display&lt;/a&gt; might have been the best option for its integer scaling, but I went with FunnyPlaying’s product for its approachability. I still consider myself a beginner at this stuff, so the pre-laminated display and purpose-built compatible shells are welcome conveniences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once I made that decision, I carefully selected my Fusion-themed components:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://retrogamerepairshop.com/collections/gba-displays/products/funnyplaying-game-boy-advance-3-0-m2-kit-1?variant=44202717053100&quot;&gt;“Yellow” FunnyPlaying M2 display kit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://retrogamerepairshop.com/collections/gba-shells/products/funnyplaying-game-boy-advance-laminated-ita-ready-shells?variant=42342199492780&quot;&gt;“Clear blue” shell&lt;/a&gt; (specifically for this display kit)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://retrogamerepairshop.com/collections/gba-buttons/products/jellybelly-game-boy-advance-custom-lemon-candy-buttons?variant=42561891893420&quot;&gt;“Lemon candy” d-pad and A/B buttons&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://retrogamerepairshop.com/collections/gba-buttons/products/high-quality-game-boy-advance-buttons?variant=44430864056492&quot;&gt;“Rose red” triggers&lt;/a&gt; (like Samus’s helmet)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://retrogamerepairshop.com/collections/gba-buttons/products/funnyplaying-game-boy-advance-button-sets?variant=38014813307052&quot;&gt;“Clear black” sides&lt;/a&gt; (like her arm cannon)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also decided to add &lt;a href=&quot;https://retrogamerepairshop.com/collections/gba-power/products/funnyplaying-game-boy-advance-white-pcb-usb-c-rechargeable-battery-mod?variant=42416405774508&quot;&gt;a rechargeable battery&lt;/a&gt; after noticing the donor console’s power light sometimes flickered when using NiMH batteries, a problem I thought could worsen with a backlit display or flash carts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After everything arrived, I disassembled the console, gave various parts and membranes a good clean with isopropyl alcohol and lint-free swabs, and followed &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ov9J8WugDXI&quot;&gt;the Macho Nacho Productions install guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I avoided any &lt;a href=&quot;https://tylersticka.com/journal/neo-geo-pocket-color/#:~:text=While%20reassembling&quot;&gt;wire-snapping mishaps&lt;/a&gt; this time around (😮‍💨), there were still new lessons to learn:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The soldering process went terribly until I discovered my iron wasn’t heating evenly! I eventually found the cold spots and adjusted my grip to avoid them. Probably time for a replacement.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I struggled to apply &lt;a href=&quot;https://retrogamerepairshop.com/collections/gba-stickers/products/game-boy-advance-holographic-sticker-labels-set-of-2?variant=32154604994634&quot;&gt;fresh sticker labels&lt;/a&gt; to the transparent shell, only to decide I preferred how it looked without. Thankfully these peeled away with a flexible plastic spudger and a bit of alcohol to remove any residue.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Since I already own a few GBA cartridges, I thought I’d wait to purchase a flash cart. But one of my games refused to boot (even after cleaning) and another had a compelling community patch to fix a few issues, so I caved and bought an &lt;a href=&quot;https://krikzz.com/our-products/cartridges/everdrive-gba-mini.html&quot;&gt;Everdrive GBA Mini&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;impressions&quot;&gt;Impressions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project felt like the exact right difficulty jump for me. While there’s nothing about the Game Boy Advance play experience as tough to replicate as the Neo Geo Pocket Color’s clicky thumb­stick, it’s a more powerful system with more parts to contend with and potential upgrades to consider. This build was challenging but fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;The modified GBA resting on an outdoor picnic table while a Samus Aran Amiibo figure keeps watch nearby&quot; src=&quot;https://tylersticka.com/images/qIjbmyuMOp-800.avif&quot; srcset=&quot;https://tylersticka.com/images/qIjbmyuMOp-600.avif 600w, https://tylersticka.com/images/qIjbmyuMOp-800.avif 800w, https://tylersticka.com/images/qIjbmyuMOp-1200.avif 1200w, https://tylersticka.com/images/qIjbmyuMOp-1600.avif 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 479px) 100vw, 800px&quot; width=&quot;1600&quot; height=&quot;1200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I’m very pleased with the result! The GBA might be the last mainstream console where 2-D, sprite-based games reigned supreme, so it’s wonderful to admire all that lovely pixel art without finding a lamp or straining my eyes. Its size, weight, orientation and hingeless design give it a comfy, balanced feel. Having the entire Game Boy line playable on actual hardware with modern conveniences is simply delightful. And it’s so satisfying to see and hold the Metroid Fusion console variant I’ve always wanted but Nintendo never made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That doesn’t mean it’s perfect. The AGB model’s d-pad is famously mushy, a problem &lt;a href=&quot;https://handheldlegend.com/products/gameboy-advance-tactile-conversion-pcb-hhl&quot;&gt;additional mods might have helped&lt;/a&gt;. I could have used &lt;a href=&quot;https://retrogamerepairshop.com/collections/gba-buttons/products/game-boy-advance-high-quality-conductive-pads?variant=40232654045356&quot;&gt;yellow conductive pads&lt;/a&gt; so start/select have the same hue as the other face buttons. There will always be a newer display, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.boxypixel.com/collections/game-boy-advance&quot;&gt;more premium shell&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.timeextension.com/news/2025/11/the-best-gba-flash-carts-new-feature-makes-a-hideo-kojima-classic-playable&quot;&gt;better flash cart&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But that’s fine by me. My custom Game Boy Advance is the same wonderful console that earned its scuffs and scratches over 20+ years of enjoyment, elevated to the best of my present-day ability, budget and whimsy. I can always tinker more if I feel like it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For now, I’ve got games to play! ✌️&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>Responsive Letter Spacing</title>
    <link href="https://tylersticka.com/journal/responsive-letter-spacing/"/>
    <updated>2025-11-20T16:30:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://tylersticka.com/journal/responsive-letter-spacing/</id>
    <content xml:lang="en-us" type="html">&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year, a longtime customer shared a new iteration of their brand guidelines. Of particular interest were changes to typography, including heavier weights for headings, and a request to tighten all &lt;code&gt;letter-spacing&lt;/code&gt; by a certain percentage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the latter change worked well in print and certain other applications, it was a bit too aggressive for web and digital. The smaller the text, the more the loss of white space impaired readability…&lt;/p&gt;

      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cloudfour.com/thinks/responsive-letter-spacing/&quot;&gt;Read more at Cloud Four…&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>Simple One-Time Passcode Inputs</title>
    <link href="https://tylersticka.com/journal/simple-one-time-passcode-inputs/"/>
    <updated>2025-11-11T16:45:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://tylersticka.com/journal/simple-one-time-passcode-inputs/</id>
    <content xml:lang="en-us" type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you’ve signed into an online service in the last decade, chances are you’ve been asked to fill a one-time passcode (“OTP”) field with a handful of digits from a text, email or authenticator app…&lt;/p&gt;

      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cloudfour.com/thinks/simple-one-time-passcode-inputs/&quot;&gt;Read more at Cloud Four…&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>Talking CSS, Web Components, App Design and (gulp) AI on ShopTalk Show</title>
    <link href="https://tylersticka.com/journal/talking-css-web-components-app-design-and-gulp-ai-on-shoptalk-show/"/>
    <updated>2025-11-03T18:25:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://tylersticka.com/journal/talking-css-web-components-app-design-and-gulp-ai-on-shoptalk-show/</id>
    <content xml:lang="en-us" type="html">&lt;p&gt;I had a blast chatting with Chris and Dave on &lt;a href=&quot;https://shoptalkshow.com/689/&quot;&gt;episode 689 of ShopTalk Show&lt;/a&gt;, my personal favorite podcast about building websites…&lt;/p&gt;

      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cloudfour.com/thinks/talking-css-web-components-app-design-and-gulp-ai-on-shoptalk-show/&quot;&gt;Read more at Cloud Four…&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry><entry>
    <title>AI Browsers, ad nauseam</title>
    <link href="https://tylersticka.com/journal/ai-browsers-ad-nauseam/"/>
    <updated>2025-10-22T17:20:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://tylersticka.com/journal/ai-browsers-ad-nauseam/</id>
    <content xml:lang="en-us" type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you think Machine Learning and Web Browsing go together like chocolate and peanut butter, congratulations: This is &lt;em&gt;your&lt;/em&gt; moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the standbys like &lt;strong&gt;Chrome&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Edge&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Firefox&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Safari&lt;/strong&gt; and (ugh) &lt;strong&gt;Brave&lt;/strong&gt; have integrated some form of AI assistant, with varying degrees of prominence and control. (At a glance, Firefox’s implementation seems &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/ai-chatbot&quot;&gt;most configurable&lt;/a&gt;, Safari’s seems &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.apple.com/en-gb/guide/mac-help/mchl62d5873e/mac&quot;&gt;easiest to overlook&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there’s also been an &lt;em&gt;avalanche&lt;/em&gt; of newcomers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deta released a beta (a “Deta Beta,” if you will) of &lt;strong&gt;Surf&lt;/strong&gt; back in December of 2024: It functions more like a notebook than a browser. December was also when The Browser Company revealed &lt;strong&gt;Dia&lt;/strong&gt;, which officially stole focus from Arc by May of this year. (Atlassian liked it &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.atlassian.com/blog/announcements/atlassian-acquires-the-browser-company&quot;&gt;so they put a ring on it&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perplexity launched &lt;strong&gt;Comet&lt;/strong&gt; in July. Opera stopped sponsoring YouTube ad-reads long enough to release &lt;strong&gt;Neon&lt;/strong&gt; in September. That same month, &lt;strong&gt;Fellou&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Oeuvre&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Genspark&lt;/strong&gt; all launched their own “agentic” browsers… just kidding, I made one of those up (the other two are real, though).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And OpenAI &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/ai/2025/04/chatgpt-head-tells-court-openai-is-interested-in-buying-chrome/&quot;&gt;couldn’t buy Chrome&lt;/a&gt;, but they’re totally over it, they aren’t sure what they ever saw in Chrome, they have their own browser now, its name is &lt;strong&gt;ChatGPT Atlas&lt;/strong&gt;, they went public yesterday so it’s pretty serious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look, &lt;a href=&quot;https://tylersticka.com/journal/browsers-are-weird-right-now/&quot;&gt;browsers are weird right now&lt;/a&gt;, and I’m all for fresh takes in that space. &lt;a href=&quot;https://tylersticka.com/journal/browsers-again/&quot;&gt;I’m still using Vivaldi&lt;/a&gt;, I’m thrilled to see &lt;a href=&quot;https://servo.org/blog/&quot;&gt;continued progress on Servo&lt;/a&gt;, and purpose-built options like &lt;a href=&quot;https://browser.horse/&quot;&gt;Horse&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://polypane.app/&quot;&gt;Polypane&lt;/a&gt; always bring a smile to my face.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So even though I have a certain degree of skepticism toward AI (under­statement of the year), I genuinely want to be as excited for any high-profile browser launch as I was &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20110623034401/http://weblogs.mozillazine.org/ben/archives/009698.html&quot;&gt;the first time I tried Mozilla’s weird upstart&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://scottmccloud.com/googlechrome/&quot;&gt;read Scott McCloud’s Google Chrome comic&lt;/a&gt;. I believe it’s possible, and I miss that feeling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the vibes are way off. There’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.stephaniestimac.com/posts/2025/10/chatgpt-atlas-isnt-competing-against-other-browsers/&quot;&gt;too little investment in the web as a platform&lt;/a&gt;, too much focus on routing as much of the web experience as possible through a specific product or service offering, and it’s increasingly tough to even tell one of these Chromium forks apart from the other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For all those reasons, these applications feel less like new browsers to me, and more like &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.chromium.org/2013/12/keeping-chrome-extensions-simple.html#:~:text=the%20then%2Dubiquitous%20toolbar&quot;&gt;those branded browser toolbars&lt;/a&gt; I seemed to find &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eweek.com/security/enough-with-the-browser-toolbars-already/&quot;&gt;installed on every relative’s PC&lt;/a&gt; through the early 2010s or so. If history is repeating itself, I hope these won’t &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2021/12/happy-21st-birthday-to-google-toolbar-which-inexplicably-still-exists/&quot;&gt;stick around quite as long&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
