<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"><channel><title><![CDATA[Ben Werdmuller]]></title><description><![CDATA[Writing at the intersection of technology, journalism, and community.]]></description><link>https://werd.io/</link><image><url>https://werd.io/favicon.png</url><title>Ben Werdmuller</title><link>https://werd.io/</link></image><generator>Ghost 6.16</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 20:11:27 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://werd.io/rss/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><ttl>60</ttl><item><title><![CDATA[Journalism lost its culture of sharing]]></title><description><![CDATA["The data are clear: The open-source culture that defined an earlier era of online journalism has collapsed."]]></description><link>https://werd.io/journalism-lost-its-culture-of-sharing/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">6978e9983031e1000163a857</guid><category><![CDATA[Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[Notable links]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Ben Werdmuller]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 16:36:40 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>[<a href="https://source.opennews.org/articles/journalism-lost-sharing-culture/?ref=werd.io">Scott Klein and Ben Welsh in Source</a>]</p><p>I agree, strongly, with this piece about (re)building an open source culture in news by <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/kleinmatic.bsky.social?ref=werd.io">Scott Klein</a> and <a href="https://palewi.re/who-is-ben-welsh/?ref=werd.io">Ben Welsh</a>. But then, I would: I spent over a decade working to build open source communities, and then another decade and change working alongside and then inside newsrooms.</p><p>So it&#x2019;s to my chagrin that the newsroom where I currently serve as Senior Director of Technology is one of the places listed here where open source contributions have significantly dropped off:</p><blockquote>&#x201C;At ProPublica, teams published detailed white papers alongside major investigations, explaining their quantitative methodologies with scientific rigor, allowing other researchers to verify and learn from their work. Major news organizations ran active blogs where they shared techniques and lessons learned. Conference presentations at NICAR and elsewhere became venues for passing along hard-won knowledge.&#x201D;</blockquote><p>The effect of this work didn&#x2019;t just lift the work of journalism, it attracted new people to it:</p><blockquote>&#x201C;This culture made newsrooms more attractive places to work for civic-minded technologists. If you had programming skills and wanted to use them to make a difference, journalism offered you the chance to build things that mattered and share them with the world.&#x201D;</blockquote><p>I think there&#x2019;s a lot to be gained by collaborating on an open source basis. We typically run small, resource-constrained teams where building new software is contextually hard. And we have problems that, if they&#x2019;re not identical, are at least significantly overlapping; by <em>not</em> collaborating on them, we further an ecosystem where low-resource organizations are all solving the same sorts of things with very few people and very little money in parallel.</p><p>I was present at the News Product Alliance Summit session described in this piece, and I think the analysis of both the causes of this decline and some of the solutions are spot on. I was particularly enamored by the idea of an Open Source Editor (or director &#x2014; does everything in news need to be an editor?) and public recognition for great open technical work in the field of journalism.</p><p>I think it&#x2019;s also worth saying that open source, done well, is about much more than just releasing your code. A good open source project is a community, not a package. So there&#x2019;s a lot of ecosystem development and community management involved to foster the kind of real collaboration that is required for this to succeed &#x2014; even after newsrooms have overcome the institutional hurdles to releasing their work in the first place.</p><p>I&#x2019;m really grateful that Scott and Ben have been championing this cause. I&#x2019;m right there with them, and I&#x2019;ll do what I can to help. It&#x2019;s a concrete way we can build a more successful, efficient news ecosystem with stronger technology capabilities, and that&#x2019;s something we should all want.</p><p>[<a href="https://source.opennews.org/articles/journalism-lost-sharing-culture/?ref=werd.io">Link</a>]</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Hiring in an era of fake candidates, real scams and AI slop]]></title><description><![CDATA["Red flags that both job seekers and employers should watch for, in an era of AI slop and application scams."]]></description><link>https://werd.io/hiring-in-an-era-of-fake-candidates-real-scams-and-ai-slop/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">697621ddd523b400016305ea</guid><category><![CDATA[AI]]></category><category><![CDATA[Notable links]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Ben Werdmuller]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 13:59:57 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>[<a href="https://themarkup.org/hello-world/2026/01/24/fake-candidates-recruiter-scams-ai-slop?ref=werd.io">Andrew Losowsky at The Markup</a>]</p><p><a href="https://losowsky.com/?ref=werd.io">Andrew Losowsky</a> discusses the impact of AI on his hiring process:</p><blockquote>&#x201C;Within 12 hours of posting the role, we received more than 400 applications. At first, most of these candidates seemed to be genuine. However, as the person who had to read them all, I quickly saw some red flags, which were all clear indicators of inauthenticity.&#x201D;</blockquote><p>These jibe with what I&#x2019;ve seen lately too. I&#x2019;ve had the privilege of hiring for a few technical roles over the last year, and every single time, <em>almost</em> everything Andrew mentions has come up.</p><p>The good news, as he points out, is that right now there are some really strong tells. One of the most important parts of any application I run is the &#x201C;why are you excited about this job?&#x201D; question, which is really a question about mission fit. The AI-generated answers are extremely generic, heavily reference the job description itself, and start looking very samey in a sample size of hundreds.</p><p>Here&#x2019;s the thing I <em>don&#x2019;t</em> believe I&#x2019;ve encountered before:</p><blockquote>&#x201C;Someone made a fake email address similar to ours, then sent generic technical &#x201C;tests&#x201D; containing our logo to jobseekers, while linking to our job ad. Completing these tests led to a fake contract signed by someone claiming to be our CEO &#x2013; it was at this point that the scammers requested financial information, saying they needed it to issue payments.&#x201D;</blockquote><p>The thing is, without someone telling me about it, how would I know? This is where we need stronger tools &#x2013; the anti-spam protections of yore don&#x2019;t work very well against AI-powered scams. Centralized repositories of scammers and stronger anti-spam filters <em>may</em> work, but I suspect we&#x2019;re going to need to find other approaches. Impersonating to make some quick money is one thing (and bad enough), but when you consider that for both Andrew and I we&#x2019;re talking about impersonating newsrooms, this could get very bad very quickly.</p><p>[<a href="https://themarkup.org/hello-world/2026/01/24/fake-candidates-recruiter-scams-ai-slop?ref=werd.io">Link</a>]</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Notable links: Jan 24, 2026]]></title><description><![CDATA[What does the future of engineering look like? And more.]]></description><link>https://werd.io/notable-links-jan-24-2026/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">6974cadfd523b40001630218</guid><category><![CDATA[Notable links]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Ben Werdmuller]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 13:49:05 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1625440153141-1ae4c27ff33b?crop=entropy&amp;cs=tinysrgb&amp;fit=max&amp;fm=jpg&amp;ixid=M3wxMTc3M3wwfDF8c2VhcmNofDN8fGV1fGVufDB8fHx8MTc2OTI2MjUwM3ww&amp;ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=80&amp;w=2000" medium="image"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1625440153141-1ae4c27ff33b?crop=entropy&amp;cs=tinysrgb&amp;fit=max&amp;fm=jpg&amp;ixid=M3wxMTc3M3wwfDF8c2VhcmNofDN8fGV1fGVufDB8fHx8MTc2OTI2MjUwM3ww&amp;ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=80&amp;w=2000" alt="Notable links: Jan 24, 2026"><p><em>Every Friday, I share a handful of pieces that caught my eye at the intersection of technology, media, and society. This week&apos;s edition is late!</em></p><p><em>This week&apos;s links discuss the future of software development, how the EU&apos;s attempts to build sovereign tech must involve helping people to create businesses around it, the complex issues surrounding trust and safety on Bluesky and similar platforms, and a concrete protocol for making professional connections between people well.</em></p><p><em>Did I miss something important? </em><a href="mailto:ben@werd.io" rel="noreferrer"><em>Send me an email</em></a><em> to let me know.</em></p><hr><h3 id="the-five-levels-from-spicy-autocomplete-to-the-software-factory"><a href="https://www.danshapiro.com/blog/2026/01/the-five-levels-from-spicy-autocomplete-to-the-software-factory/?ref=werd.io" rel="noreferrer">The Five Levels: from Spicy Autocomplete to the Software Factory</a></h3><p>Software development is transforming incredibly quickly. This guide, although it looks a bit silly at first glance, is very aligned with what I&#x2019;ve heard from friends and seen first-hand.</p><blockquote>&#x201C;I&#x2019;ve now seen dozens of companies struggling to put AI to work writing code, and each one has moved through five clear tiers of automation. That felt familiar, and I realized that the federal government had been there first &#x2013; but for cars.<br><br>In 2013, the NHTSA created the five levels of driving automation. This was helpful, because while the highest level at the time was only level 22, it let everyone have a common language for both where things were, and where things were going.&#x201D;</blockquote><p>What follows is instructive; some of the interim steps are waypoints, but 4 and 5 seems to be where a lot of mainstream software development is going. We can thank <a href="https://claude.com/product/claude-code?ref=werd.io">Claude Code</a> for this; many of these changes took place <em>last year</em>, with some pre-work laid down by the AI vendors and various startups beforehand. My guess is that everything will have changed again by the end of the year.</p><p>In the hands of senior engineers who are getting their heads around how these tools work, AI coding is starting to work as advertised. There&#x2019;s a reason why engineers who have been coding for decades rave about it. But we&#x2019;ll also see some really bad code (particularly in enterprise organizations) and some high-profile failures. There&#x2019;s something I&#x2019;ve called <em>The Mythical Claude Code Agent Month</em> (I need to find a pithier name), where in response to process and culture failures that are hampering its software development, an organization just decides that it needs to add more AI. And hallucinations, bias, and model poisoning are all real things.</p><p>In response to this, and because a lot of engineers are ideologically or otherwise opposed to AI, I think we&#x2019;ll begin to see explicitly artisanal software companies emerge. In some industries, particularly highly-regulated ones, we&#x2019;ll also see new kinds of trust certificates emerge to prove that (regardless of how it was built) software performs well and doesn&#x2019;t leak private information.</p><p>Anyway, those are all knock-on effects. As of now, this is where mainstream software development is likely going. This isn&#x2019;t an endorsement, necessarily &#x2014; but it <em>is</em> a good-faith observation.</p><hr><h3 id="funding-open-source-for-digital-sovereignty"><a href="https://dri.es/funding-open-source-for-digital-sovereignty?ref=werd.io" rel="noreferrer">Funding Open Source for Digital Sovereignty</a></h3><p>Vital thoughts from Drupal founder <a href="https://dr.ies/?ref=werd.io">Dries Buytaert</a> on how, if Europeans and others are going to rely on open source software as a way to decouple from US services, funding the people and communities that <em>build</em> open source software must be part of the conversation:</p><blockquote>&#x201C;Open Source is the most credible path to digital sovereignty. It&apos;s the only software you can run without permission. You can audit, host, modify, and migrate it yourself. No vendor, no government, and no sanctions regime can ever take it away.<br><br>But there is a catch. When governments buy Open Source services, the money rarely reaches the people who actually build and maintain it. Procurement rules favor large system integrators, not the maintainers of the software itself. As a result, public money flows to companies that package and resell Open Source, not to the ones who do the hard work of writing and sustaining it.&#x201D;</blockquote><p>Dries&#x2019;s solution involves evaluating a company&#x2019;s open source contributions as part of a procurement process. If governments and other organizations are willing to do this in practice, that would work, at least for certain kinds of maintainers and communities. It would favor the companies that give back to an open source project over the ones that just repackage someone else&#x2019;s work, and in doing so, make it more attractive for companies to give back in the first place.</p><p>But I think there&#x2019;s another way to look at the problem: provide the tools, infrastructure, and platforms for maintainers to start companies around their work. Rather than encouraging existing companies to become open source participants, this would encourage open source participants to become companies. It might even incentivize new kinds of companies to be drawn up as co-operatives of open source maintainers.</p><p>When a company obtains software, it&#x2019;s looking for more than the code: it needs a solution to a problem. Services address organizational problems more directly than codebases alone. There&#x2019;s a reason why Dries&#x2019;s Acquia and Matt Mullenweg&#x2019;s Automattic have become so successful.</p><p>There is nothing unethical about creating services businesses (or non-profits with service missions) that are aligned with the open source nature of their underlying products &#x2014; and, indeed, that direct connection with customers will make those products better. But I&#x2019;d say that most open source maintainers either aren&#x2019;t thinking that way or are daunted by the prospect. So perhaps they could use a little help?</p><p>An open source services in a box solution for these maintainers &#x2014; including business fundamentals, sales and marketing, and a kind of operating system for running a small company around open source &#x2014; could be an interesting way to <em>both</em> make open source software more palatable for institutional buyers <em>and</em> bring more money into their ecosystems.</p><p>Code, generally speaking, is not a solution in itself, but it can be part of one. This would fill in the rest.</p><hr><h3 id="on-ice-verification-and-presence-as-harm"><a href="https://connectedplaces.online/reports/fr150-on-ice-verification-and-presence-as-harm/?ref=werd.io" rel="noreferrer">On ICE, Verification, and Presence As Harm</a></h3><p>This post by <a href="https://laurenshof.online/?ref=werd.io">Laurens Hof</a> speaks to a bunch of issues at the intersection of our current moment in history (I haven&#x2019;t yet found the words to refer to it that don&#x2019;t sound like a euphemism) and the open social web.</p><p>ICE joined Bluesky as part of a wave of Trump Administration accounts that were created last November, as an apparent intimidation tactic against a network that was perceived to be largely left-wing. It never posted and the account seemed abandoned, but Bluesky officially verified it this week. Subsequently, <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/icegov.bsky.social/post/3md4do3y4y22p?ref=werd.io">it made a post</a> to further its narrative about Liam Conejo Ramos, the five-year-old whose local public schools superintendent says <a href="https://apnews.com/article/immigration-minnesota-boy-father-detained-342f319fafb766d13afe07f5bcc1f112?ref=werd.io">was used by ICE as bait</a>.</p><p>As Laurens points out, what happened next on the two main pillars of the open social web was interesting:</p><blockquote>&#x201C;The decision by Bluesky PBC to verify the ICE account, two months after registration and without the account being active, lead to quite different responses for the fediverse and for the ATmosphere. On the fediverse, the choice by Bluesky PBC to lend legitimacy to ICE was a final nail in the coffin, with loud declarations to disconnect from Bluesky and block the bridge between these two networking protocols. Mastodon founder Eugen Rochko was the most notable account, who publicly declared to disconnect from the bridge.<br><br>Within the ATmosphere, the response focused on two parts, both a frustration with Bluesky PBC verifying the ICE account, as well as a call to block the account en-masse, which led to the ICE account quickly becoming one of the most-blocked accounts on the network.&#x201D;</blockquote><p>For Mastodon, this is in some ways an endorsement of the fediverse model. Both communities and individuals can choose not to connect with other communities and accounts that they find harmful.</p><p>This is in contrast with the AT Protocol model, which is not made of archipelagos of smaller communities; it&#x2019;s a wide town square at scale, much like Twitter was. For Bluesky, this is indicative of the tension between being an open protocol and a prominent consumer social media platform. On one hand, the protocol allows anyone to be a verifier: in this model, the government itself could have verified the ICE account, and any client that trusts the government to verify would have displayed a badge. This arrangement would avoid the appearance of Bluesky endorsing ICE. On the other hand, Bluesky the platform has its own verification service, because you need that on a commercial social network to prevent imposters and other abuse.</p><p>The timeline between verification and ICE&#x2019;s first post is a little odd. But it&#x2019;s also true that ICE is a government agency. If ICE is going to be on the platform to begin with, sticking a badge on its account to ensure everyone knows that, yes, this is the real ICE, is not a bad idea.</p><p>I&#x2019;m going to pause here and state, for the record, that not only am I not a fan of ICE, I believe they are committing crimes and following a terrifyingly fascist playbook. People are being both kidnapped and murdered on the streets.</p><p>That&#x2019;s important context for this next discussion:</p><blockquote>&#x201C;Bluesky&#x2019;s Community Guidelines lists the two major principles as &#x2018;Safety First&#x2019; and &#x2018;Respect Others&#x2019;. It is somewhat unclear how the presence of a fascist police force that is actively working to instigate civil war aligns with the principles of safety and respect that Bluesky supposedly champions.<br><br>When it comes to actual rules in the guidelines, it is all about user behaviour and the content on Bluesky. The problem is that it is the presence of ICE itself that is already causing the harm. The intimidation of &#x2018;we are here, you cannot escape us&#x2019; is the point, and the accounts by the regime are deliberately trying to provoke an outrage.&#x201D;</blockquote><p>These things are true, in my mind. But it&#x2019;s also really complicated.</p><p>If you were Bluesky, what would you do? Which precedent would you set?</p><p>Imagine if it were to ban ICE on the grounds that it is causing harm both in the world and through its presence on the platform. (It <em>is</em> causing harm.) ICE remains a government agency, and doing so would therefore be a political act. Its actions are claimed to be legal by the government. Banning it <em>could</em> set a precedent that Bluesky can ban accounts whose politics it disagrees with. At the very least, it would be contentious and cement its reputation as a left-wing network.</p><p>If it <em>doesn&#x2019;t</em> ban ICE, we get the situation we have today. People are upset that ICE has a presence on the network. Some users on Mastodon, which is largely seen as a place for people to connect safely in smaller groups, disconnect from the Bluesky bridge. Some users on Bluesky are upset that it appears to be endorsing ICE by verifying the account; it becomes one of the most-blocked accounts within a matter of hours. And then ICE uses it to spread its message. Not banning it <em>could</em> be seen as an endorsement, or as Bluesky not taking what ICE is doing and represents seriously enough. That&#x2019;s particularly true when banning the account would <em>only</em> ban them on the official Bluesky apps, not on the AT Protocol ecosystem as a whole.</p><p>It&#x2019;s not a problem that Bluesky-the-protocol would have, but the fact is that it&#x2019;s primarily a consumer platform. And if any consumer social platform makes trust and safety rulings that are, in effect, arbitrary, it sets a precedent that it can turf people off its platform on a whim, which undermines both trust and safety.</p><p>But it&#x2019;s also extremely hard, because ICE <em>is</em> terrifying, they <em>are</em> kidnapping and killing people on the streets, and most people don&#x2019;t want them in their space. Users likely moved to Bluesky to get away from the hard right wing discourse happening over on X/Twitter; the community self-selected largely based on that fact, which made it feel safer, but the platform itself doesn&#x2019;t necessarily share those values.</p><p>A social media app that aims to be town square is different to a social networking app that aims to provide a smaller, safe community. The latter has a far easier time banning accounts from entities like ICE, because it can set a tighter set of community rules. So one lesson is perhaps that we need &#x2014; or at least, many people need &#x2014; a pluralistic open social web, where we can choose communities based on our values. That&#x2019;s closer to the fediverse than to the ATmosphere model: the fediverse is smaller communities, while the social media ecosystem being built on AT Protocol is closer to an open version of Twitter.</p><p>Bluesky is in a tough position. It&#x2019;s building an open protocol but most of the users of its flagship app don&#x2019;t give two hoots about that. They&#x2019;re looking for a safe place to discuss and share, and Bluesky&#x2019;s core value for them is that it&#x2019;s not X/Twitter and doesn&#x2019;t have the toxicity of that network. It&#x2019;s considered to be easier to use than Mastodon because there&#x2019;s one place to sign up and one official app. AT Protocol wouldn&#x2019;t be as successful as it&#x2019;s becoming without that dynamic. So it has to continue to foster that community while also maintaining its protocol, and it can&#x2019;t fork itself to create multiple app experiences for different audiences. It also can&#x2019;t indicate that its flagship app is just for people who hate ICE.</p><p>My conclusion is that Bluesky is doing the only thing it can &#x2014; and this is the only path that leads to AT Protocol becoming a successful open social web protocol. You need to have a vibrant community, and most people who join one don&#x2019;t care about the underlying technology. There&#x2019;s a world, later on, where other providers create viable alternative microblogging experiences with different takes on trust and safety &#x2014; which is beginning to happen with Blacksky and Eurosky &#x2014; but the ecosystem is not there yet. Protocol success and community safety have conflicting requirements, and Bluesky has to continue navigating that ambiguity for now; later on it may be able to focus on the protocol.</p><p>Meanwhile, ICE is doing a lot of harm, and its presence may be a real risk to many of Bluesky&#x2019;s users. They may find that the fediverse, after all, is a better place for them to call home.</p><hr><h3 id="the-forwardable-email"><a href="https://pointc.co/the-forwardable-email/?ref=werd.io" rel="noreferrer">The Forwardable Email</a></h3><p>I know I share posts from <a href="https://pointc.co/?ref=werd.io">Corey</a> very regularly, but it&#x2019;s because I&#x2019;ve been working with him in various ways for over a decade, and the things he suggests are often techniques I&#x2019;ve used productively for a long time. This is another great one.</p><p>I insist on double opt-in introductions if I&#x2019;m making a connection. That means I check in with the connectee first: do they actually want this connection? It&#x2019;s a little slower, but it means connections are always consensual.</p><p>To be able do that really well, a forwardable email is the perfect tool. Here, the person who wants to be connected drafts an email designed to allow me to forward it to the connectee with a little bit of added context. It gives them what they need to make an informed decision.</p><p>Corey&#x2019;s template is actionable and really works: it&#x2019;s what I&#x2019;ve done for a decade now. It&#x2019;s simple, but the underlying structure is not what most people are doing.</p><p>Honestly, I&#x2019;m also just very happy that this is in a post on Corey&#x2019;s site, because now when I tell people to write me a forwardable email, I can just point them to this. Please, if you&#x2019;re asking me for a connection, this is the template I would like you to follow.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[On ICE, Verification, and Presence As Harm]]></title><description><![CDATA["Bluesky built a verification system designed to distribute trust, and then didn't use it when it mattered."]]></description><link>https://werd.io/on-ice-verification-and-presence-as-harm/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">69743817d523b40001630209</guid><category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[Notable links]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Ben Werdmuller]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 03:10:15 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>[<a href="https://connectedplaces.online/reports/fr150-on-ice-verification-and-presence-as-harm/?ref=werd.io#">Laurens Hof at Connected Places</a>]</p><p>This post by <a href="https://laurenshof.online/?ref=werd.io">Laurens Hof</a> speaks to a bunch of issues at the intersection of our current moment in history (I haven&#x2019;t yet found the words to refer to it that don&#x2019;t sound like a euphemism) and the open social web.</p><p>ICE joined Bluesky as part of a wave of Trump Administration accounts that were created last November, as an apparent intimidation tactic against a network that was perceived to be largely left-wing. It never posted and the account seemed abandoned, but Bluesky officially verified it this week. Subsequently, <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/icegov.bsky.social/post/3md4do3y4y22p?ref=werd.io">it made a post</a> to further its narrative about Liam Conejo Ramos, the five-year-old whose local public schools superintendent says <a href="https://apnews.com/article/immigration-minnesota-boy-father-detained-342f319fafb766d13afe07f5bcc1f112?ref=werd.io">was used by ICE as bait</a>.</p><p>As Laurens points out, what happened next on the two main pillars of the open social web was interesting:</p><blockquote>&#x201C;The decision by Bluesky PBC to verify the ICE account, two months after registration and without the account being active, lead to quite different responses for the fediverse and for the ATmosphere. On the fediverse, the choice by Bluesky PBC to lend legitimacy to ICE was a final nail in the coffin, with loud declarations to disconnect from Bluesky and block the bridge between these two networking protocols. Mastodon founder Eugen Rochko was the most notable account, who publicly declared to disconnect from the bridge.<br><br>Within the ATmosphere, the response focused on two parts, both a frustration with Bluesky PBC verifying the ICE account, as well as a call to block the account en-masse, which led to the ICE account quickly becoming one of the most-blocked accounts on the network.&#x201D;</blockquote><p>For Mastodon, this is in some ways an endorsement of the fediverse model. Both communities and individuals can choose not to connect with other communities and accounts that they find harmful. </p><p>This is in contrast with the AT Protocol model, which is not made of archipelagos of smaller communities; it&#x2019;s a wide town square at scale, much like Twitter was. For Bluesky, this is indicative of the tension between being an open protocol and a prominent consumer social media platform. On one hand, the protocol allows anyone to be a verifier: in this model, the government itself could have verified the ICE account, and any client that trusts the government to verify would have displayed a badge. This arrangement would avoid the appearance of Bluesky endorsing ICE. On the other hand, Bluesky the platform has its own verification service, because you need that on a commercial social network to prevent imposters and other abuse.</p><p>The timeline between verification and ICE&#x2019;s first post is a little odd. But it&#x2019;s also true that ICE is a government agency. If ICE is going to be on the platform to begin with, sticking a badge on its account to ensure everyone knows that, yes, this is the real ICE, is not a bad idea.</p><p>I&#x2019;m going to pause here and state, for the record, that not only am I not a fan of ICE, I believe they are committing crimes and following a terrifyingly fascist playbook. People are being both kidnapped and murdered on the streets.</p><p>That&#x2019;s important context for this next discussion:</p><blockquote>&#x201C;Bluesky&#x2019;s Community Guidelines lists the two major principles as &#x2018;Safety First&#x2019; and &#x2018;Respect Others&#x2019;. It is somewhat unclear how the presence of a fascist police force that is actively working to instigate civil war aligns with the principles of safety and respect that Bluesky supposedly champions.<br><br>When it comes to actual rules in the guidelines, it is all about user behaviour and the content on Bluesky. The problem is that it is the presence of ICE itself that is already causing the harm. The intimidation of &#x2018;we are here, you cannot escape us&#x2019; is the point, and the accounts by the regime are deliberately trying to provoke an outrage.&#x201D;</blockquote><p>These things are true, in my mind. But it&#x2019;s also really complicated.</p><p>If you were Bluesky, what would you do? Which precedent would you set?</p><p>Imagine if it were to ban ICE on the grounds that it is causing harm both in the world and through its presence on the platform. (It <em>is</em> causing harm.) ICE remains a government agency, and doing so would therefore be a political act. Its actions are claimed to be legal by the government. Banning it <em>could</em> set a precedent that Bluesky can ban accounts whose politics it disagrees with. At the very least, it would be contentious and cement its reputation as a left-wing network.</p><p>If it <em>doesn&#x2019;t</em> ban ICE, we get the situation we have today. People are upset that ICE has a presence on the network. Some users on Mastodon, which is largely seen as a place for people to connect safely in smaller groups, disconnect from the Bluesky bridge. Some users on Bluesky are upset that it appears to be endorsing ICE by verifying the account; it becomes one of the most-blocked accounts within a matter of hours. And then ICE uses it to spread its message. Not banning it <em>could</em> be seen as an endorsement, or as Bluesky not taking what ICE is doing and represents seriously enough. That&#x2019;s particularly true when banning the account would <em>only</em> ban them on the official Bluesky apps, not on the AT Protocol ecosystem as a whole.</p><p>It&#x2019;s not a problem that Bluesky-the-protocol would have, but the fact is that it&#x2019;s primarily a consumer platform. And if any consumer social platform makes trust and safety rulings that are, in effect, arbitrary, it sets a precedent that it can turf people off its platform on a whim, which undermines both trust and safety.</p><p>But it&#x2019;s also extremely hard, because ICE <em>is</em> terrifying, they <em>are</em> kidnapping and killing people on the streets, and most people don&#x2019;t want them in their space. Users likely moved to Bluesky to get away from the hard right wing discourse happening over on X/Twitter; the community self-selected largely based on that fact, which made it feel safer, but the platform itself doesn&#x2019;t necessarily share those values.</p><p>A social media app that aims to be town square is different to a social networking app that aims to provide a smaller, safe community. The latter has a far easier time banning accounts from entities like ICE, because it can set a tighter set of community rules. So one lesson is perhaps that we need &#x2014; or at least, many people need &#x2014; a pluralistic open social web, where we can choose communities based on our values. That&#x2019;s closer to the fediverse than to the ATmosphere model: the fediverse is smaller communities, while the social media ecosystem being built on AT Protocol is closer to an open version of Twitter.</p><p>Bluesky is in a tough position. It&#x2019;s building an open protocol but most of the users of its flagship app don&#x2019;t give two hoots about that. They&#x2019;re looking for a safe place to discuss and share, and Bluesky&#x2019;s core value for them is that it&#x2019;s not X/Twitter and doesn&#x2019;t have the toxicity of that network. It&#x2019;s considered to be easier to use than Mastodon because there&#x2019;s one place to sign up and one official app. AT Protocol wouldn&#x2019;t be as successful as it&#x2019;s becoming without that dynamic. So it has to continue to foster that community while also maintaining its protocol, and it can&#x2019;t fork itself to create multiple app experiences for different audiences. It also can&#x2019;t indicate that its flagship app is just for people who hate ICE.</p><p>My conclusion is that Bluesky is doing the only thing it can &#x2014; and this is the only path that leads to AT Protocol becoming a successful open social web protocol. You need to have a vibrant community, and most people who join one don&#x2019;t care about the underlying technology. There&#x2019;s a world, later on, where other providers create viable alternative microblogging experiences with different takes on trust and safety &#x2014; which is beginning to happen with Blacksky and Eurosky &#x2014; but the ecosystem is not there yet. Protocol success and community safety have conflicting requirements, and Bluesky has to continue navigating that ambiguity for now; later on it may be able to focus on the protocol.</p><p>Meanwhile, ICE is doing a lot of harm, and its presence may be a real risk to many of Bluesky&#x2019;s users. They may find that the fediverse, after all, is a better place for them to call home.</p><p>[<a href="https://connectedplaces.online/reports/fr150-on-ice-verification-and-presence-as-harm/?ref=werd.io#">Link</a>]</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Five Levels: from Spicy Autocomplete to the Software Factory]]></title><description><![CDATA["I’ve now seen dozens of companies struggling to put AI to work writing code, and each one has moved through five clear tiers of automation. That felt familiar."]]></description><link>https://werd.io/the-five-levels-from-spicy-autocomplete-to-the-software-factory/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">6973fb84d523b40001630203</guid><category><![CDATA[AI]]></category><category><![CDATA[Notable links]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Ben Werdmuller]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 22:51:48 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>[<a href="https://www.danshapiro.com/blog/2026/01/the-five-levels-from-spicy-autocomplete-to-the-software-factory/?ref=werd.io">Dan Shapiro</a>]</p><p>Software development is transforming incredibly quickly. This guide, although it looks a bit silly at first glance, is very aligned with what I&#x2019;ve heard from friends and seen first-hand.</p><blockquote>&#x201C;I&#x2019;ve now seen dozens of companies struggling to put AI to work writing code, and each one has moved through five clear tiers of automation. That felt familiar, and I realized that the federal government had been there first &#x2013; but for cars.<br><br>In 2013, the NHTSA created the five levels of driving automation. This was helpful, because while the highest level at the time was only level 22, it let everyone have a common language for both where things were, and where things were going.&#x201D;</blockquote><p>What follows is instructive; some of the interim steps are waypoints, but 4 and 5 seems to be where a lot of mainstream software development is going. We can thank <a href="https://claude.com/product/claude-code?ref=werd.io">Claude Code</a> for this; many of these changes took place <em>last year</em>, with some pre-work laid down by the AI vendors and various startups beforehand. My guess is that everything will have changed again by the end of the year.</p><p>In the hands of senior engineers who are getting their heads around how these tools work, AI coding is starting to work as advertised. There&#x2019;s a reason why engineers who have been coding for decades rave about it. But we&#x2019;ll also see some really bad code (particularly in enterprise organizations) and some high-profile failures. There&#x2019;s something I&#x2019;ve called <em>The Mythical Claude Code Agent Month</em> (I need to find a pithier name), where in response to process and culture failures that are hampering its software development, an organization just decides that it needs to add more AI. And hallucinations, bias, and model poisoning are all real things.</p><p>In response to this, and because a lot of engineers are ideologically or otherwise opposed to AI, I think we&#x2019;ll begin to see explicitly artisanal software companies emerge. In some industries, particularly highly-regulated ones, we&#x2019;ll also see new kinds of trust certificates emerge to prove that (regardless of how it was built) software performs well and doesn&#x2019;t leak private information.</p><p>Anyway, those are all knock-on effects. As of now, this is where mainstream software development is likely going. This isn&#x2019;t an endorsement, necessarily &#x2014; but it <em>is</em> a good-faith observation.</p><p>[<a href="https://www.danshapiro.com/blog/2026/01/the-five-levels-from-spicy-autocomplete-to-the-software-factory/?ref=werd.io">Link</a>]</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Forwardable Email]]></title><description><![CDATA["A way to help others actually make that connection they said they would." I've used this for a decade, and it's probably useful for you, too.]]></description><link>https://werd.io/the-forwardable-email/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">69723026d523b400016301ec</guid><category><![CDATA[Business]]></category><category><![CDATA[Notable links]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Ben Werdmuller]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 14:11:50 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>[<a href="https://pointc.co/the-forwardable-email/?ref=the-idea-bucket-newsletter">Corey Ford at Point C</a>]</p><p>I know I share posts from <a href="https://pointc.co/?ref=werd.io">Corey</a> very regularly, but it&#x2019;s because I&#x2019;ve been working with him in various ways for over a decade, and the things he suggests are often techniques I&#x2019;ve used productively for a long time. This is another great one.</p><p>I insist on double opt-in introductions if I&#x2019;m making a connection. That means I check in with the connectee first: do they actually want this connection? It&#x2019;s a little slower, but it means connections are always consensual.</p><p>To be able do that really well, a forwardable email is the perfect tool. Here, the person who wants to be connected drafts an email designed to allow me to forward it to the connectee with a little bit of added context. It gives them what they need to make an informed decision.</p><p>Corey&#x2019;s template is actionable and really works: it&#x2019;s what I&#x2019;ve done for a decade now. It&#x2019;s simple, but the underlying structure is not what most people are doing.</p><p>Honestly, I&#x2019;m also just very happy that this is in a post on Corey&#x2019;s site, because now when I tell people to write me a forwardable email, I can just point them to this. Please, if you&#x2019;re asking me for a connection, this is the template I would like you to follow.</p><p>[<a href="https://pointc.co/the-forwardable-email/?ref=the-idea-bucket-newsletter">Link</a>]</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Funding Open Source for Digital Sovereignty]]></title><description><![CDATA["Open Source alone won't deliver digital sovereignty. Europe must fix procurement and fund those who actually build it."]]></description><link>https://werd.io/funding-open-source-for-digital-sovereignty/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">69710632d523b400016301ca</guid><category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[Notable links]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Ben Werdmuller]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 17:00:34 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>[<a href="https://dri.es/funding-open-source-for-digital-sovereignty?ref=werd.io">Dries Buytaert</a>]</p><p>Vital thoughts from Drupal founder <a href="https://dr.ies/?ref=werd.io">Dries Buytaert</a> on how, if Europeans and others are going to rely on open source software as a way to decouple from US services, funding the people and communities that <em>build</em> open source software must be part of the conversation:</p><blockquote>&#x201C;Open Source is the most credible path to digital sovereignty. It&apos;s the only software you can run without permission. You can audit, host, modify, and migrate it yourself. No vendor, no government, and no sanctions regime can ever take it away.<br><br>But there is a catch. When governments buy Open Source services, the money rarely reaches the people who actually build and maintain it. Procurement rules favor large system integrators, not the maintainers of the software itself. As a result, public money flows to companies that package and resell Open Source, not to the ones who do the hard work of writing and sustaining it.&#x201D;</blockquote><p>Dries&#x2019;s solution involves evaluating a company&#x2019;s open source contributions as part of a procurement process. If governments and other organizations are willing to do this in practice, that would work, at least for certain kinds of maintainers and communities. It would favor the companies that give back to an open source project over the ones that just repackage someone else&#x2019;s work, and in doing so, make it more attractive for companies to give back in the first place.</p><p>But I think there&#x2019;s another way to look at the problem: provide the tools, infrastructure, and platforms for maintainers to start companies around their work. Rather than encouraging existing companies to become open source participants, this would encourage open source participants to become companies. It might even incentivize new kinds of companies to be drawn up as co-operatives of open source maintainers.</p><p>When a company obtains software, it&#x2019;s looking for more than the code: it needs a solution to a problem. Services address organizational problems more directly than codebases alone. There&#x2019;s a reason why Dries&#x2019;s Acquia and Matt Mullenweg&#x2019;s Automattic have become so successful.</p><p>There is nothing unethical about creating services businesses (or non-profits with service missions) that are aligned with the open source nature of their underlying products &#x2014; and, indeed, that direct connection with customers will make those products better. But I&#x2019;d say that most open source maintainers either aren&#x2019;t thinking that way or are daunted by the prospect. So perhaps they could use a little help?</p><p>An open source services in a box solution for these maintainers &#x2014; including business fundamentals, sales and marketing, and a kind of operating system for running a small company around open source &#x2014; could be an interesting way to <em>both</em> make open source software more palatable for institutional buyers <em>and</em> bring more money into their ecosystems.</p><p>Code, generally speaking, is not a solution in itself, but it can be part of one. This would fill in the rest.</p><p>[<a href="https://dri.es/funding-open-source-for-digital-sovereignty?ref=werd.io">Link</a>]</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Who owns your data?]]></title><description><![CDATA[A Supreme Court case about a bank robbery could redefine your digital rights.]]></description><link>https://werd.io/who-owns-your-data/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">696f8fa5f6713b00015b63cb</guid><category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Ben Werdmuller]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 14:26:08 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://werd.io/content/images/2026/01/getty-images-p4qjMeEnYOE-unsplash.jpg" medium="image"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="https://werd.io/content/images/2026/01/getty-images-p4qjMeEnYOE-unsplash.jpg" alt="Who owns your data?"><p><em>A note before we begin: I&#x2019;m not a lawyer, and you shouldn&#x2019;t consider anything I write or say to be legal advice. As always, this post is solely my own, and does not necessarily represent anyone I&#x2019;ve worked for or with, or any community I&#x2019;ve been a part of in any capacity. Okay? Okay.</em></p><h3 id="to-catch-a-thief-the-police-turn-to-google">To catch a thief, the police turn to Google</h3><p>It&#x2019;s May 20, 2019, a year before the pandemic. Midlothian is an old, unincorporated coal-mining town outside Richmond, VA that now serves as one of its suburbs. A man enters the Call Federal Credit Union, forces a worker to open the safe using a threatening note that implied he had taken hostages, and walks out with $195,000.</p><p>A few weeks after the robbery, the police have no strong leads. Finally, they go back and examine the security footage, and notice that in the minutes before the robbery, the perpetrator holds a smartphone to his ear &#x2014; which gives them an idea.</p><p>When Android smartphones have Location History turned on, they save detailed location information on Google&#x2019;s servers. Because it&#x2019;s centralized and indexed by Google, it can be searched by the company, as well as subpoenaed by third parties &#x2014; and obtained by law enforcement.</p><p>The police in the Midlothian case get a warrant for Google&#x2019;s location data for every cellphone in the area of the Credit Union &#x2014; a so-called geofence warrant &#x2014; for an hour around the time of the robbery. Each of the 19 cellphone owners returned to them by Google becomes a suspect; they investigate each one in turn, having conversations and methodically ruling them out. <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/news/us-news/police-used-google-location-data-find-accused-bank-robber-he-n1086836?ref=werd.io">And that&#x2019;s how they find Okello Chatrie.</a></p><hr><p>Chatrie entered a conditional guilty plea in 2019. It wasn&#x2019;t cut and dried. <a href="https://constitution.congress.gov/constitution/amendment-4/?ref=werd.io">The Fourth Amendment protects people from arbitrary searches and seizures.</a> His lawyers argued that a blanket geofence warrant that revealed everyone who happened to be within the vicinity of the Credit Union was a violation of those rights. The judge presiding over his case acknowledged that the warrant <em>did</em> likely violate his rights, but allowed the evidence to be included anyway. Chatrie was ultimately sentenced to twelve years in prison.</p><p>His legal team brought the Fourth Amendment complaint to an appeals court &#x2014; and lost. Contesting that result, they petitioned the Supreme Court, which <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2026/01/16/us/politics/supreme-court-warrants-location-data.html?ref=werd.io">has now agreed to hear the case</a>.</p><h3 id="surveillance-capitalism-is-just-surveillance">Surveillance capitalism is just surveillance</h3><p>The implications of the Supreme Court&#x2019;s eventual decision will go far beyond Chatrie&#x2019;s freedom.</p><p><a href="https://www.bjcl.org/blog/the-constitutionality-of-geofence-warrants?ref=werd.io">Google is issued tens of thousands of these geofence warrants every year</a>, handing over detailed information about cellphone users without them ever knowing.</p><p>Google isn&#x2019;t the only potential recipient for such a warrant. Much of the internet economy depends on gathering data and selling characteristics about individual people to others; Google is just one of many companies that store and trade on this data. Without protections, all of it can be used to target and identify individuals.</p><p>Data brokers buy information from third-party apps across device types (including iPhones) and sell bulk access to it. Those apps are sometimes surprising: weather apps, for example, need to understand your location to give you a useful forecast, but they often then sell that location data through brokers.</p><p>As well as advertising networks and sales teams, customers include the police, ICE, and intelligence services around the world. This data is often &#x201C;anonymized&#x201D; or &#x201C;de-identified&#x201D;, but in practice can be made identifiable again relatively easily when datasets are combined. They sell this information even without a warrant, and many security services buy subscriptions in order to circumvent legal restrictions that would ordinarily require them to get one.</p><p>This information &#x2014; whether retrieved via warrant or otherwise &#x2014; is often specific and directly identifiable. Anyone with the ability to access it about a person gains the ability to track their activities at a highly granular level. That&#x2019;s made possible by massive, centralized data collection at scale, and an assumption that users don&#x2019;t have significant rights over it.</p><p>The implication of Chatrie&#x2019;s petition to the Supreme Court is that it must answer the question: when you consent to share location data with a cloud provider like Google, do you forfeit constitutional protection against government searches of that information? But there&#x2019;s another question that should be asked alongside it: given that this information can often just be bought on the open market, what might protect people from having their personal and identifying information searched without their permission?</p><p><a href="https://law.justia.com/cases/federal/appellate-courts/ca4/22-4489/22-4489-2025-04-30.html?ref=werd.io">The court surfaced an email from a Google employee</a> that said Google&#x2019;s interface &#x201C;feels like it is designed to make things possible, yet difficult enough that people won&apos;t figure out&#x201D; how to disable tracking. This implies a third question: if a service uses <a href="https://www.deceptive.design/?ref=werd.io">dark patterns</a> to bury the implications of a consent decision, as Google and many other internet services arguably do, is it <a href="https://www.emergentmind.com/topics/informed-consent-in-privacy-law?ref=werd.io">informed consent</a> at all?</p><h3 id="is-personal-data-property">Is personal data property?</h3><p>Two cases in the late 1970s (<em>Smith v. Maryland</em> and <em>United States v. Miller</em>) established something called the <em>third-party doctrine</em>, which holds that people have no reasonable expectation of privacy over information they have voluntarily shared with third parties.</p><p>These cases were decided decades before the cloud, smart devices, and ubiquitous mobile computing: specifically, they determined that bank slips and records of outgoing calls could be accessed without a warrant. In both cases, the argument was that the person involved knows that they&#x2019;re giving this information to the bank and phone company respectively. That doesn&#x2019;t apply cleanly to how data is created and collected in the internet era, where data is often created and collected seamlessly, without our direct involvement. Regardless, the doctrine has long been used to argue that Fourth Amendment protections don&#x2019;t apply when retrieving cloud data about a person.</p><p>Those differences do matter. Much more recently, in 2018, the Supreme Court found (in <a href="https://www.supremecourt.gov/opinions/17pdf/16-402_h315.pdf?ref=werd.io" rel="noreferrer"><em>Carpenter v. United States</em></a>) that location information drawn from cell tower records <em>was</em> protected under the Fourth Amendment, recognizing that the &#x201C;detailed, encyclopedic, and effortlessly compiled&#x201D; nature of this data was different to that considered under the third-party doctrine.</p><p>Clearly, data automatically saved from geolocation on a smartphone is much more comparable to this cell tower information. This data, too, is detailed and encyclopedic, and is gathered without any input from the user. Both are buried deep in the terms and conditions of their respective underlying services, where users are probably unaware they&#x2019;ve consented to them; they only really differ in the mechanical details of how they&#x2019;re gathered. If cell tower location information maintains Fourth Amendment protections, there is no reason why Google&#x2019;s (or anyone else&#x2019;s) geolocation data should not.</p><p>But the implications of the case may be larger. My attention was drawn to <a href="https://www.supremecourt.gov/opinions/17pdf/16-402_h315.pdf?ref=werd.io">a dissent in <em>Carpenter</em> by Justice Gorsuch</a>, who agreed with the conclusion (that cell site data was protected) but disagreed with how the Court got there. He said:</p><blockquote>He did not invoke the law of property or any analogies to the common law, either there or in his petition for certiorari. Even in his merits brief before this Court, Mr. Carpenter&#x2019;s discussion of his positive law rights in cell-site data was cursory. [&#x2026;] In these circumstances, I cannot help but conclude&#x2014;reluctantly&#x2014;that Mr. Carpenter forfeited perhaps his most promising line of argument.</blockquote><p>In other words, he was disappointed that Carpenter&#x2019;s lawyers chose to argue that he had a reasonable expectation of privacy, and not that his personal data was <em>his property</em>. Gorsuch&#x2019;s opinion in the Carpenter case was, in a way, an invitation for plaintiffs to use this property argument in future cases: a signal letting them know that he would be receptive to it.</p><p>That&#x2019;s exactly what the <em>Chatrie</em> team has done: Gorsuch&#x2019;s property argument is a core part of their petition.</p><h3 id="google-the-bailee">Google the bailee</h3><p>The <em>Chatrie</em> team argued that Google&#x2019;s custody over a person&#x2019;s personal data is a <em>bailment</em>, and that because Google users can control their location data (including deleting it), it&#x2019;s their property, not Google&#x2019;s.</p><blockquote>Unlike the [Cell Site Location Information] at issue in Carpenter, Location History is in no sense a business record: users (not Google) have control over whether it is stored and can unilaterally delete it. Although the records were stored on Google&#x2019;s servers, Google was acting as a bailee rather than an owner.</blockquote><p>A <em>bailment</em> is when you give your property to someone else for safekeeping or a specific purpose, but you retain ownership and agency over it. The best analogy is a coat check or valet parking. The bailee takes possession of your stuff, but it never becomes <em>their</em> stuff. You get your coat back from the coat check; the valet returns your car. There&#x2019;s an assumption that they&#x2019;ve treated them well in the meantime; their owners retain Fourth Amendment rights over them throughout.</p><p>Google itself filed an amicus brief in the original <em>Chatrie</em> case, indicating that those rights were also preserved for location data under its custody. <a href="https://www.lawfaremedia.org/article/how-google-s-location-history-program-could-upend-digital-surveillance-law?ref=werd.io">As Lawfare summarized it last year</a>:</p><blockquote>Google ultimately asserted in its Chatrie amicus brief that its users retain Fourth Amendment rights in their Location History data. Moreover, four days after the oral arguments in the Chatrie case, Google <a href="https://blog.google/products/maps/updates-to-location-history-and-new-controls-coming-soon-to-maps/?ref=werd.io">issued this announcement</a> that after a year or so it would no longer store Location History data except on users&#x2019; own devices, essentially ending Google&#x2019;s participation in geofence warrants.</blockquote><p>Being seen as a source of ubiquitous surveillance is bad for business; it stands to reason that Google would want to hold the practice.</p><p>But of course, data is a little bit more complicated than a coat or a car. Unlike a paper record &#x2014; or any other sort of property &#x2014; data is infinitely replicable. Google might hold a copy of your data, but that doesn&#x2019;t necessarily preclude anyone <em>else</em> from having a copy, too. That essential characteristic has powered the entire internet revolution: the core concept of scalability doesn&#x2019;t work without infinite replication.</p><p>This infinite replicability also has the potential to be a complication for that bailee argument. In a data universe, there may be multiple custodians for different copies of the same piece of information. It&#x2019;s not what&#x2019;s called <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rivalry_(economics)?ref=werd.io"><em>rivalrous</em></a>: while my possession of my coat or my car mean that nobody else can have them, if I give Google my data, I&#x2019;m not necessarily withholding it from anyone else. In a data world, the same coat can be stored in infinite coat checks.</p><p>Property rights evolved around rivalrous goods; for something to be considered property, it usually needs to have scarcity. The exception is <em>intellectual</em> property, which is something you create: IP covers creations that <em>can be</em> infinitely replicable. The thing is, intellectual property hinges on a copyrightable work being created; sometimes data is this (this article is data and also a copyrightable work), but sometimes it&#x2019;s just a set of facts. Facts aren&#x2019;t copyrightable; IP doesn&#x2019;t cleanly cover them. A set of facts of the form &#x201C;Ben was in this location at this time&#x201D; is therefore not covered by IP.</p><p>For us to consider data as being property, then, we probably have to consider it as something new. At the very least, we need to expand how we think about property to incorporate the concept of infinite replication.</p><h3 id="what-is-property">What is property?</h3><p>If something is your property, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bundle_of_rights?ref=werd.io">you typically have certain rights</a>:</p><ul><li>The right to use (&#x201C;enjoy&#x201D;) it</li><li>The right to exclude others from using it</li><li>The right to transfer it</li><li>The right to destroy it</li></ul><p>These all make sense in a data context too &#x2014; it just doesn&#x2019;t cover everything you can do with data. I would add:</p><ul><li>The right to copy it</li><li>The right to transform it</li><li>The right to examine it</li></ul><p>For data to be property, the owner needs to have these rights over it. Whether a user really <em>does</em> have each of these rights over the location information stored by Location History is up for debate. Do they have true title to this information, which would mean they have sole power to exercise these rights? Or have they just been granted some control over it?</p><h3 id="what-is-personal-data">What is personal data?</h3><p>It&#x2019;s worth considering who generates personal data, and how.</p><p>Take this analogy: in the famous scene in <em>Titanic</em>, Jack (Leonardo DiCaprio&#x2019;s character) draws a still life of Rose (Kate Winslet&#x2019;s character). Jack has recorded an observation of Rose. It contains Rose&#x2019;s personal information: her face, her whereabouts, what she&#x2019;s wearing. But who owns that drawing? Is it Jack&#x2019;s or Rose&#x2019;s?</p><p>Jack has made the drawing: while Rose modeled for it, it&#x2019;s his work. The drawing is intrinsically his. Rose probably has some <em>moral</em> rights over it &#x2014; for example, over her likeness &#x2014; but the piece of paper with the drawing on it is not her property.</p><p>Of course, a point of location data isn&#x2019;t a drawing. It&#x2019;s not a copyrightable work. It&#x2019;s a set of facts that list where we were at a particular time. If I sit across from you and notice that you&#x2019;re wearing a red sweater, you don&#x2019;t own that observation or have any rights over it, even if it&#x2019;s about you. I can tell anyone I want, including the police, that you were wearing it.</p><p>But there are key differences. In that scenario, I&#x2019;m independent of you; Google, on the other hand, is tracking your location through your phone, which is your property. You&#x2019;re a key actor: you&#x2019;ve set up the phone, kept it charged, bought cell service, and so on. And you&#x2019;ve chosen to use the services that capture your location. Google is acting on your behalf, recording data that you create by moving around with it in your pocket.</p><p>The originator of the action &#x2014; the <em>instigator</em> &#x2014; seems to matter. Is Google akin to Jack, observing us and drawing us in its database? Or are location records things we make ourselves by moving around with a phone in our pocket?</p><p>Is location data something Google creates by observing us, or something we create by living? Is personal data the result of something we <em>do</em> or something that&#x2019;s <em>done about us</em>?</p><p>In a world where personal data <em>is</em> property, we gain the property rights I listed above by default, and in turn, we gain much more power and control over the information that&#x2019;s stored about us. This would change our rights online, and every organization &#x2014; software companies, ad networks, publishers, governments &#x2014; that captures first-party data about a person would need to adapt. In a world where it <em>isn&#x2019;t</em>, we either make <em>some</em> gains through the lens of a reasonable expectation of privacy, or we&#x2019;re left with fewer rights. The status quo would remain largely intact.</p><p>Whether <em>Chatrie</em> finds that there was a Fourth Amendment violation is important, because privacy is important. <em>How</em> it finds it has the potential to change the internet forever.</p><p>Because it&#x2019;s not clear that the surveillance data that is stored about us is ours, and because of the serious ramifications, I would be very surprised if the Supreme Court ruled that location data stored about us was personal property.</p><p>There&#x2019;s also a danger: if location data <em>was</em> personal property, there&#x2019;s a real chance that Fourth Amendment rights would actually be <em>restricted</em> overall. If it can only apply to things that look a lot like property, that may prevent it from being applied to technology and data that diverge from that standard. To put it another way, it sounds protective, but it could ultimately narrow Fourth Amendment coverage by requiring plaintiffs to establish property interests that may not exist in modern data arrangements.</p><p>That&#x2019;s not at all to say that the Court won&#x2019;t find there is a reasonable expectation of privacy, or that location records aren&#x2019;t protected by the Fourth Amendment. If your face is caught on CCTV, nobody would argue that you own that footage, but there are reasonable protections on how you can be recorded and what can be done with it. If your phone is wiretapped, you probably don&#x2019;t own the audio, but there are reasonable protections on whether someone can record it in the first place.</p><h3 id="legislation-is-needed">Legislation is needed</h3><p>This is a thorny discussion &#x2014; in the US. Strong data protection rights are here; they&#x2019;re just not evenly distributed yet.</p><p>In most of the US, rights over data are largely still up for debate. The third-party doctrine has acted as a shield for service providers, who consequently don&#x2019;t need to build the extra features and protections that would be necessary if data was property. The <a href="https://www.justice.gov/criminal/cloud-act-resources?ref=werd.io">CLOUD Act</a> works <em>against</em> privacy rights by requiring American service providers to relinquish data to the authorities.</p><p>But privacy should be a human right. Even if the legal arrangements are under debate, the <em>moral</em> right to privacy exists and is clear.</p><p>In the EU, the <a href="https://gdpr.eu/what-is-gdpr/?ref=werd.io">General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)</a> makes your rights around data much clearer. It establishes a bundle of data rights that include:</p><ul><li>The right to understand which data is being collected about you and how it&#x2019;s processed</li><li>The right to correct inaccurate data about you</li><li>The right to delete data about you &#x2014; but only when it has outlived its usefulness for the purpose it was collected</li><li>The right to limit how data about you is processed &#x2014; in some circumstances &#x2014; and object to it being processed</li><li>The right to download your data</li><li>The right to share your downloaded data with another provider</li><li>The right to not be subject to decisions solely made using automatic systems using your data</li></ul><p>There&#x2019;s no right to prevent processing altogether, and there&#x2019;s no right to sell your data. These stop short of full property rights &#x2014; in fact, they&#x2019;re explicitly defined as rights that relate to <em>personhood</em>, not property &#x2014; but there&#x2019;s significant overlap. Most importantly, they remove ambiguity about what rights a user has over data that is stored about them. It covers both my <em>Titanic</em> and my sweater examples by directly encoding rights.</p><p>This has inspired other legislation. For example, <a href="https://oag.ca.gov/privacy/ccpa?ref=werd.io">California&#x2019;s privacy laws</a>, the California Consumer Privacy Act (CCPA) are an enormous step forward in the US &#x2014; but with significant limits. They treat data rights as consumer protection legislation, but only for data captured by certain organizations: non-profits and companies under certain revenue limits are exempt. It also has an explicit carveout for legal processes, leaving users relatively unprotected against government access. Unlike the GDPR, the CCPA doesn&#x2019;t provide <em>universal</em> rights over data.</p><p>As I mentioned, I find it unlikely that the Supreme Court will find that data is property as a finding of its <em>Chatrie</em> decision. But that doesn&#x2019;t mean data as property is a bad or undesirable outcome (except for the stakeholders who would need to comply with it). To get there, we need lawmakers to create new legislation that encodes those rights.</p><p>In his <em>Carpenter</em> dissent, Justice Gorsuch pointed out that the third-party doctrine effectively means that nobody ever has a reasonable expectation of privacy. In a world where we all carry a smartphone in our pockets that stores all kinds of information about us, it condemns us to living with ubiquitous surveillance. Property rights &#x2014; or something that approximates the bundle of rights normally associated with property &#x2014; would free us of that.</p><p>In order to prevent ongoing arguments about what rights we have over the data that is stored about us, we need clarity &#x2014; and that&#x2019;s what legislation is for. For now, all we can really do is hope that the Court decides, in some, limited situations, that we have a reasonable expectation of privacy. But we need to push for more.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Remembering Beyond Vietnam on MLK Day]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>A good friend introduced me to Martin Luther King Jr&apos;s <em>Beyond Vietnam</em> speech some time ago. It was not well-received by the mainstream press at the time (more about that in a moment) but I think it&apos;s prescient and, unfortunately, timely.</p><p>At the Riverside Church in</p>]]></description><link>https://werd.io/remembering-beyond-vietnam-on-mlk-day/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">696e3563a619080001059447</guid><category><![CDATA[Democracy]]></category><category><![CDATA[Asides]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Ben Werdmuller]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 13:58:13 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A good friend introduced me to Martin Luther King Jr&apos;s <em>Beyond Vietnam</em> speech some time ago. It was not well-received by the mainstream press at the time (more about that in a moment) but I think it&apos;s prescient and, unfortunately, timely.</p><p>At the Riverside Church in New York City, he delivered <a href="https://www.americanrhetoric.com/speeches/mlkatimetobreaksilence.htm?ref=werd.io" rel="noreferrer">a blistering response</a> to America&apos;s war in Vietnam that went beyond the war itself to discuss the values of the nation and its impact at home and abroad:</p><blockquote>We must rapidly begin the shift from a thing-oriented society to a person-oriented society. When machines and computers, profit motives and property rights, are considered more important than people, the giant triplets of racism, extreme materialism, and militarism are incapable of being conquered.<br><br>[...] A true revolution of values will soon look uneasily on the glaring contrast of poverty and wealth. With righteous indignation, it will look across the seas and see individual capitalists of the West investing huge sums of money in Asia, Africa, and South America, only to take the profits out with no concern for the social betterment of the countries, and say, &quot;This is not just.&quot; It will look at our alliance with the landed gentry of South America and say, &quot;This is not just.&quot; The Western arrogance of feeling that it has everything to teach others and nothing to learn from them is not just.</blockquote><p>It is <a href="https://www.americanrhetoric.com/speeches/mlkatimetobreaksilence.htm?ref=werd.io" rel="noreferrer">a brilliant speech</a>.</p><p>And at the time, it was condemned. <a href="https://kinginstitute.stanford.edu/encyclopedia/beyond-vietnam?ref=werd.io" rel="noreferrer">As The Martin Luther King, Jr. Research and Education Institute at Stanford University notes</a>:</p><blockquote>To King, the Vietnam War was only the most pressing symptom of American colonialism worldwide. King claimed that America made&#xA0;&#x201C;peaceful revolution impossible by refusing to give up the privileges and the pleasures that come from the immense profits of overseas investments&#x201D;. King urged instead&#xA0;&#x201C;a radical revolution of values&#x201D;&#xA0;emphasizing love and justice rather than economic nationalism.<br><br>The immediate response to King&#x2019;s speech was largely negative. Both the&#xA0;<em>Washington Post</em>&#xA0;and&#xA0;<em>New York Times</em>&#xA0;published editorials criticizing the speech, with the&#xA0;<em>Post&#xA0;</em>noting that King&#x2019;s speech had&#xA0;&#x201C;diminished his usefulness to his cause, to his country, and to his people&#x201D;&#xA0;through a simplistic and flawed view of the situation (&#x201C;A Tragedy,&#x201D;&#xA0;6 April 1967). Similarly, both the&#xA0;<a href="https://kinginstitute.stanford.edu/national-association-advancement-colored-people-naacp?ref=werd.io"><strong>National Association for the Advancement of Colored People</strong></a>&#xA0;and Ralph&#xA0;<a href="https://kinginstitute.stanford.edu/bunche-ralph-johnson?ref=werd.io"><strong>Bunche</strong></a><a href="https://kinginstitute.stanford.edu/bunche-ralph-johnson?ref=werd.io">&#xA0;</a>accused King of linking two disparate issues, Vietnam and civil rights. Despite public criticism, King continued to attack the Vietnam War on both moral and economic grounds.</blockquote><p>Today, we tend to remember MLK in a sanitized, vague way. That&apos;s because what he was really calling for was parity in a way that is still unfortunately controversial, even today. At the time, <a href="https://www.smithsonianmag.com/history/why-martin-luther-king-had-75-percent-disapproval-rating-year-he-died-180968664/?ref=werd.io" rel="noreferrer">75% of Americans disapproved of him</a>. But these ideas are even more obviously relevant today than they were at the time. He was prescient, and we need more leaders like him.</p><p>And, of course, <a href="https://thekingcenter.org/statement-from-the-king-center-regarding-the-declassification/?ref=werd.io" rel="noreferrer">he was assassinated for it</a> &#x2013; something that we still have to truly reckon with. As his daughter, Dr Bernice A King, said:</p><blockquote>&#x201C;The reality is that it is not <em>who</em> killed Martin Luther King, Jr&#x2026;but <em>what</em> killed Martin Luther King, Jr. Because whenever we get to what killed Martin Luther King, Jr., then we will deal with the various injustices that we face as a nation and ultimately as a nation that leads this world.&#x201D;</blockquote><p><a href="https://drstaceypatton1865.substack.com/p/they-love-him-dead?ref=werd.io" rel="noreferrer">Yesterday, Dr Stacey Patton wrote</a>:</p><blockquote>Tomorrow, they will invoke Martin Luther King Jr. while doing the very things he warned against. Because America has a necrophilic relationship with Dr. King. It loves the King that forgives its sins and washes its feet.<br><br>[...] It loves him dead because dead men don&#x2019;t organize. Dead men don&#x2019;t shut down streets. Dead men don&#x2019;t boycott, don&#x2019;t strike, don&#x2019;t disrupt, and don&#x2019;t demand redistribution of wealth. Dead men don&#x2019;t call out Empire and don&#x2019;t name white supremacy. Dead men don&#x2019;t link racism to capitalism and militarism in the same damn breath.<br><br>[...] Naw, they don&#x2019;t love <em>our </em>Dr. King. They love the silence that comes after the bullet.</blockquote>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Notable links: January 16, 2026]]></title><description><![CDATA[An occupation in Minnesota and finding your way to work that doesn't harm]]></description><link>https://werd.io/notable-links-january-16-2026/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">6969b710a619080001058c58</guid><category><![CDATA[Notable links]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Ben Werdmuller]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 10:00:07 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://werd.io/content/images/2026/01/55038799910_f445cbbcdd.jpg" medium="image"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="https://werd.io/content/images/2026/01/55038799910_f445cbbcdd.jpg" alt="Notable links: January 16, 2026"><p><em>Every Friday, I share a handful of pieces that caught my eye at the intersection of technology, media, and society.</em></p><p><em>I don&apos;t have a pithy summary this week. It&apos;s been a heavy week. These links &#x2013; about documenting atrocities and finding values-aligned work &#x2013; reflect that.</em></p><p><em>Did I miss something important? </em><a href="mailto:ben@werd.io" rel="noreferrer"><em>Send me an email</em></a><em> to let me know.</em></p><hr><h3 id="remarks-on-the-federal-government%E2%80%99s-ongoing-presence-in-minnesota"><a href="https://mn.gov/governor/newsroom/press-releases/?id=719765&amp;ref=werd.io" rel="noreferrer">Remarks on the Federal Government&#x2019;s Ongoing Presence in Minnesota</a></h3><p><em><strong>Update:</strong> </em><a href="https://sethmlarson.dev/?ref=werd.io" rel="noreferrer"><em>Seth Larson</em></a><em> let me know that the Minnesota Attorney General, Keith Ellison, established </em><a href="https://www.ag.state.mn.us/Federal-Action/?ref=werd.io" rel="noreferrer"><em>a portal for sending in evidence of ICE activity</em></a><em>.</em></p><p>Minnesota is experiencing unprecedented ICE action &#x2014; which is a kind of punch-pulling euphemism for what has felt like an all-out fascist invasion that has included murder, kidnappings, toxic chlorine gas set off in city streets, and ICE officers staking out stores and businesses, sometimes arresting the staff at restaurants they&#x2019;ve just been eating at.</p><p>In the midst of this, Governor Tim Walz made an address where he accurately described it as an occupation. Remarkably, he also asked his constituents this:</p><blockquote>&#x201C;Tonight, I want to share another way you can help: Witness.<br><br>Help us establish a record of exactly what&#x2019;s happening in our communities.<br><br>You have an absolute right to peacefully film ICE agents as they conduct their activities.<br><br>So carry your phone with you at all times.<br><br>And if you see ICE in your neighborhood, take out that phone and hit record.<br><br>Help us create a database of the atrocities against Minnesotans &#x2013; not just to establish a record for posterity, but to bank evidence for future prosecution.&#x201D;</blockquote><p>We&#x2019;ve seen crowdsourced footage and citizen journalism before &#x2014; most pervasively during the Black Lives Matter protests five years ago &#x2014; but I can&#x2019;t think of a time when the Governor of a State, or anyone in a similar position, has asked citizens to record and save footage so that it can be used to prosecute the authorities for its atrocities.</p><p>If we look beyond the obvious shock that <em>this is where we are now</em>, there&#x2019;s an interesting infrastructure problem here. It&#x2019;s worth asking: if <em>you</em> were designing a system to gather footage of ICE brutality from Minnesotans, while protecting their safety and ensuring the sanctity of the dataset, how would you do it? Knowing that there will be people who want to make the database unusable, or prevent people from submitting, either directly or through intimidation?</p><p>It&#x2019;s essentially a whistleblower (or journalism tips) use case. Rinse and repeat for the whole country. Some newsrooms have built their own forms, and Letitia James released <a href="https://ag.ny.gov/federal-actions-form?ref=werd.io">a portal for submitting ICE footage in New York</a>, but there&#x2019;s a strong case to be made for a central repository for <em>all</em> ICE abuse, for which <em>sifting through</em> all that video is a problem in itself. There will be a lot of it.</p><p>And what if there doesn&#x2019;t remain a strong government entity at the State level to bring about a case?</p><p>There&#x2019;s a strong argument for sharing to a central repository that can be used and browsed by multiple entities, including governments, advocacy organizations, civil rights lawyers, and newsrooms. When this information is distributed across States, newsrooms, personal Instagram accounts, and more, it doesn&#x2019;t form a body of evidence that can help bring about more impactful cases and determine patterns of activity. So someone should consider centralizing it &#x2014; but then mirroring it, <a href="https://werd.io/the-zurich-protocol/">Zurich protocol</a> style, so that nobody can hide the evidence and cover the tracks of their abuse.</p><hr><h3 id="%E2%80%98elite%E2%80%99-the-palantir-app-ice-uses-to-find-neighborhoods-to-raid"><a href="https://www.404media.co/elite-the-palantir-app-ice-uses-to-find-neighborhoods-to-raid/?ref=werd.io" rel="noreferrer">&#x2018;ELITE&#x2019;: The Palantir App ICE Uses to Find Neighborhoods to Raid</a></h3><p>This is racial profiling on a grand scale:</p><blockquote>&#x201C;Palantir is working on a tool for Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE) that populates a map with potential deportation targets, brings up a dossier on each person, and provides a &#x201C;confidence score&#x201D; on the person&#x2019;s current address, 404 Media has learned. ICE is using it to find locations where lots of people it might detain could be based.&#x201D;</blockquote><p>It apparently looks a lot like Google Maps, but designed to show the richness of an area for &#x201C;targets&#x201D;, populated in part by density of immigrants. And then you can dig in:</p><blockquote>&#x201C;Once a person is selected on the map interface, ELITE then shows a dossier on that particular person, according to the user guide. That includes their name, a photo, their Alien Number (the unique code given by the U.S. government to each immigrant), their date of birth, and their full address.&#x201D;</blockquote><p>The Nazis could only dream of having such a capability.</p><p>Imagine working for this company, on this product. Every day, you go into work, in what I assume is a beautiful office with pine furniture and a well-stocked kitchen, and you build software that will help to deport people using what you know are extrajudicial means without due process. You probably have OKRs. There are customer calls with ICE. Every two-week sprint, you take on tasks that help make this engine better.</p><p>What do you tell yourself? What do you tell your family?</p><p>Are you on board with this agenda, or do you tell yourself you need the job to pay rent? To get healthcare?</p><p>You receive stock as part of your pay package. It&#x2019;s going up! You can use it to buy a home, or to build a comfortable retirement, or some combination of the two.</p><p>Your co-workers are values aligned and work hard. They&#x2019;re talented and smart. <em>Man,</em> you might think to yourself, <em>I love working with this team.</em></p><p>Or, you might think, <em>man, I&#x2019;ve got to find another job.</em></p><p>Either way, you&#x2019;re proud of your product work. You&#x2019;re happy to take the salary, the free lunches, the espresso. And regardless of how you feel about it, the thing you do every day is powering an armed force that is kidnapping people on the street and shooting civilians, that shot a mother in the face, that is targeting people to disappear using a beautiful, modern map interface.</p><hr><h3 id="bari-weiss-is-the-symptom"><a href="https://defector.com/bari-weiss-is-the-symptom?ref=werd.io" rel="noreferrer">Bari Weiss Is The Symptom</a></h3><p>I wish this essay wasn&#x2019;t good and necessary, but it is.</p><blockquote>&#x201C;I worry some of my colleagues in the industry are getting the Bari Weiss phenomenon exactly wrong. She isn&apos;t a saboteur brought in to destroy one of the last remaining citadels of high journalism. She is one of high journalism&apos;s purest products, a perfect symptom of its old, unresolved contradictions. Her disingenuousness about motive is the industry&apos;s in miniature.&#x201D;</blockquote><p>The author is correct: Bari Weiss is not an exception to a glorious industry, but one of many. These are people who, although they would not put it that way themselves, seek to make journalism toothless; to turn it into an instrument of power rather than something that interrogates it. They&#x2019;re the people who see themselves, more than anything else, as an <em>institution</em>, rather than the people institutions worry about when they go to sleep at night. And they are everywhere.</p><p>I&#x2019;m not a journalist, but I signed up to support them. After my hard left turn from tech, I run technology for newsrooms, which includes the technologies that publish their work and keep them safe. And here I have to clarify: I didn&#x2019;t sign up to do this for all of them. I signed up to do it for the people who want to make the world safer, fairer, more equal. There&#x2019;s a reason why my two newsrooms have been <a href="https://19thnews.org/?ref=werd.io">The 19th</a> and <a href="https://propublica.org/?ref=werd.io">ProPublica</a>. The only journalism I care about aims to hold a bright light to power and established power structures, and truly hold them to account.</p><p>The Bari Weisses believe it&#x2019;s in the national interest to support whatever war the current administration has chosen to wage. They endorse official narratives in the name of covering &#x201C;both sides&#x201D;, even when they are obvious lies. They produce journalism about trans people without consulting trans people. They avoid the appearance of activism. They believe in upholding the status quo in the name of stability. And in doing so, they enable atrocities, big and small, foreign and domestic, to the point of collaboration.</p><hr><h3 id="how-to-know-if-that-job-will-crush-your-soul"><a href="https://www.anildash.com/2026/01/12/will-that-job-crush-your-soul/?ref=werd.io" rel="noreferrer">How to know if that job will crush your soul</a></h3><p>A good list of questions that will help you determine whether a job will be values-aligned or crush your soul from <a href="https://anildash.com/?ref=werd.io">Anil Dash</a>.</p><p>They also inform how to ask questions during an interview process. For example, Anil asks:</p><blockquote>&#x201C;What&#x2019;s the lived experience of the workers there whom you trust? Do you have evidence of leaders in the organization making hard choices to do the right thing?&#x201D;</blockquote><p>If you don&#x2019;t know &#x2014; and if it&#x2019;s not a big company, you probably don&#x2019;t &#x2014; the question becomes: how will you find out? The result will be a deeper and more meaningful hiring process.</p><p>But in addition to the values questions, Anil also asks about compensation and forward trajectory. These are important too. There&#x2019;s no sense in taking a job that isn&#x2019;t going to be sustainable for you, or won&#x2019;t allow you to grow with it. In those situations, there&#x2019;s barely a relationship; you&#x2019;re ultimately just a resource.</p><hr><h3 id="the-curiosity-tour"><a href="https://pointc.co/the-curiosity-tour/?ref=werd.io" rel="noreferrer">The Curiosity Tour</a></h3><p>This resonated:</p><blockquote>&#x201C;I had always been a linchpin and had chafed under cog-like conditions. I uncovered a key insight:<br><br>The process for finding a cog job and the process for finding a linchpin job are completely different.<br><br>I had been following a cog path. Reacting to job postings that were easily classifiable on LinkedIn and had a hiring process run by middle management who had no idea what to do with a linchpin when they saw one.&#x201D;</blockquote><p>What follows is &#x2014; characteristically for <a href="https://pointc.co/?ref=werd.io">Corey</a> &#x2014; a clear-eyed, easy-to-follow framework for finding linchpin-shaped jobs.</p><p>These <em>are</em> very different kinds of jobs: they often can&#x2019;t be described cleanly, and although I&#x2019;d argue strongly that all jobs should be hired through an open process, they might not even be positions that have been defined yet. At any rate, there are only good things to be gained by meeting with leaders and learning about their needs from a position of genuine curiosity.</p><p>When I was reading this piece, I realized I&#x2019;d suggested that a friend do something similar in the publishing industry a long time ago. She wanted to break into publishing and had a core set of skills that operated at the intersection of a few things. More than anything else, she was a doer. So I suggested that she make a list of publishers she&#x2019;d like to talk to &#x2014; perhaps by looking at books that she loved and checking who ran the imprint &#x2014; and reach out to them cold to have a conversation.</p><p>It worked, and within a few months she had a linchpin job at a publishing company in London. She wound up empowering an entire range of books to be published, writing some of her own, and transforming the way the publishing company ran.</p><p>So, you know, try it. You just might find you get your dream job. One that is values-aligned to you, where you don&apos;t need to hold your nose every day when you go to work.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Remarks on the Federal Government’s Ongoing Presence in Minnesota]]></title><description><![CDATA[“It is a campaign of organized brutality against the people of Minnesota by our own federal government." So record it.]]></description><link>https://werd.io/remarks-on-the-federal-governments-ongoing-presence-in-minnesota/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">6969b6c4a619080001058c52</guid><category><![CDATA[Democracy]]></category><category><![CDATA[Notable links]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Ben Werdmuller]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 03:55:48 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>[<a href="https://mn.gov/governor/newsroom/press-releases/?id=719765&amp;ref=werd.io">Minnesota Governor Tim Walz</a>]</p><p><em><strong>Update:</strong> </em><a href="https://sethmlarson.dev/?ref=werd.io" rel="noreferrer"><em>Seth Larson</em></a><em> let me know that the Minnesota Attorney General, Keith Ellison, established </em><a href="https://www.ag.state.mn.us/Federal-Action/?ref=werd.io" rel="noreferrer"><em>a portal for sending in evidence of ICE activity</em></a><em>.</em></p><p>Minnesota is experiencing unprecedented ICE action &#x2014; which is a kind of punch-pulling euphemism for what has felt like an all-out fascist invasion that has included murder, kidnappings, toxic chlorine gas set off in city streets, and ICE officers staking out stores and businesses, sometimes arresting the staff at restaurants they&#x2019;ve just been eating at.</p><p>In the midst of this, Governor Tim Walz made an address where he accurately described it as an occupation. Remarkably, he also asked his constituents this:</p><blockquote>&#x201C;Tonight, I want to share another way you can help: Witness.<br><br>Help us establish a record of exactly what&#x2019;s happening in our communities.<br><br>You have an absolute right to peacefully film ICE agents as they conduct their activities.<br><br>So carry your phone with you at all times.<br><br>And if you see ICE in your neighborhood, take out that phone and hit record.<br><br>Help us create a database of the atrocities against Minnesotans &#x2013; not just to establish a record for posterity, but to bank evidence for future prosecution.&#x201D;</blockquote><p>We&#x2019;ve seen crowdsourced footage and citizen journalism before &#x2014; most pervasively during the Black Lives Matter protests five years ago &#x2014; but I can&#x2019;t think of a time when the Governor of a State, or anyone in a similar position, has asked citizens to record and save footage so that it can be used to prosecute the authorities for its atrocities.</p><p>If we look beyond the obvious shock that <em>this is where we are now</em>, there&#x2019;s an interesting infrastructure problem here. It&#x2019;s worth asking: if <em>you</em> were designing a system to gather footage of ICE brutality from Minnesotans, while protecting their safety and ensuring the sanctity of the dataset, how would you do it? Knowing that there will be people who want to make the database unusable, or prevent people from submitting, either directly or through intimidation?</p><p>It&#x2019;s essentially a whistleblower (or journalism tips) use case. Rinse and repeat for the whole country. Some newsrooms have built their own forms, and Letitia James released <a href="https://ag.ny.gov/federal-actions-form?ref=werd.io">a portal for submitting ICE footage in New York</a>, but there&#x2019;s a strong case to be made for a central repository for <em>all</em> ICE abuse, for which <em>sifting through</em> all that video is a problem in itself. There will be a lot of it.</p><p>And what if there doesn&#x2019;t remain a strong government entity at the State level to bring about a case?</p><p>There&#x2019;s a strong argument for sharing to a central repository that can be used and browsed by multiple entities, including governments, advocacy organizations, civil rights lawyers, and newsrooms. When this information is distributed across States, newsrooms, personal Instagram accounts, and more, it doesn&#x2019;t form a body of evidence that can help bring about more impactful cases and determine patterns of activity. So someone should consider centralizing it &#x2014; but then mirroring it, <a href="https://werd.io/the-zurich-protocol/">Zurich protocol</a> style, so that nobody can hide the evidence and cover the tracks of their abuse.</p><p>[<a href="https://mn.gov/governor/newsroom/press-releases/?id=719765&amp;ref=werd.io">Link</a>]</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Curiosity Tour]]></title><description><![CDATA["A way to approach a job hunt that uncovers extraordinary, unlisted opportunities" - using a distilled framework that makes something that might look daunting feel easy.]]></description><link>https://werd.io/the-curiosity-tour/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">69699e8ba619080001058c42</guid><category><![CDATA[Business]]></category><category><![CDATA[Notable links]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Ben Werdmuller]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 02:12:27 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>[<a href="https://pointc.co/the-curiosity-tour/?ref=werd.io">Corey Ford at Point C</a>]</p><p>This resonated:</p><blockquote>&#x201C;I had always been a linchpin and had chafed under cog-like conditions. I uncovered a key insight:<br><br>The process for finding a cog job and the process for finding a linchpin job are completely different.<br><br>I had been following a cog path. Reacting to job postings that were easily classifiable on LinkedIn and had a hiring process run by middle management who had no idea what to do with a linchpin when they saw one.&#x201D;</blockquote><p>What follows is &#x2014; characteristically for <a href="https://pointc.co/?ref=werd.io">Corey</a> &#x2014; a clear-eyed, easy-to-follow framework for finding linchpin-shaped jobs.</p><p>These <em>are</em> very different kinds of jobs: they often can&#x2019;t be described cleanly, and although I&#x2019;d argue strongly that all jobs should be hired through an open process, they might not even be positions that have been defined yet. At any rate, there are only good things to be gained by meeting with leaders and learning about their needs from a position of genuine curiosity.</p><p>When I was reading this piece, I realized I&#x2019;d suggested that a friend do something similar in the publishing industry a long time ago. She wanted to break into publishing and had a core set of skills that operated at the intersection of a few things. More than anything else, she was a doer. So I suggested that she make a list of publishers she&#x2019;d like to talk to &#x2014; perhaps by looking at books that she loved and checking who ran the imprint &#x2014; and reach out to them cold to have a conversation.</p><p>It worked, and within a few months she had a linchpin job at a publishing company in London. She wound up empowering an entire range of books to be published, writing some of her own, and transforming the way the publishing company ran.</p><p>So, you know, try it. You just might find you get your dream job.</p><p>[<a href="https://pointc.co/the-curiosity-tour/?ref=werd.io">Link</a>]</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[‘ELITE’: The Palantir App ICE Uses to Find Neighborhoods to Raid]]></title><description><![CDATA["Internal ICE material and testimony from an official obtained by 404 Media provides the clearest link yet between the technological infrastructure Palantir is building for ICE and the agency’s activities on the ground."]]></description><link>https://werd.io/elite-the-palantir-app-ice-uses-to-find-neighborhoods-to-raid/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">6968ff25a619080001058c12</guid><category><![CDATA[Democracy]]></category><category><![CDATA[Notable links]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Ben Werdmuller]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 14:52:21 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>[<a href="https://www.404media.co/elite-the-palantir-app-ice-uses-to-find-neighborhoods-to-raid/?ref=werd.io">Joseph Cox at 404 Media</a>]</p><p>This is racial profiling on a grand scale:</p><blockquote>&#x201C;Palantir is working on a tool for Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE) that populates a map with potential deportation targets, brings up a dossier on each person, and provides a &#x201C;confidence score&#x201D; on the person&#x2019;s current address, 404 Media has learned. ICE is using it to find locations where lots of people it might detain could be based.&#x201D;</blockquote><p>It apparently looks a lot like Google Maps, but designed to show the richness of an area for &#x201C;targets&#x201D;, populated in part by density of immigrants. And then you can dig in:</p><blockquote>&#x201C;Once a person is selected on the map interface, ELITE then shows a dossier on that particular person, according to the user guide. That includes their name, a photo, their Alien Number (the unique code given by the U.S. government to each immigrant), their date of birth, and their full address.&#x201D;</blockquote><p>The Nazis could only dream of having such a capability.</p><p>Imagine working for this company, on this product. Every day, you go into work, in what I assume is a beautiful office with pine furniture and a well-stocked kitchen, and you build software that will help to deport people using what you know are extrajudicial means without due process. You probably have OKRs. There are customer calls with ICE. Every two-week sprint, you take on tasks that help make this engine better.</p><p>What do you tell yourself? What do you tell your family?</p><p>Are you on board with this agenda, or do you tell yourself you need the job to pay rent? To get healthcare?</p><p>You receive stock as part of your pay package. It&#x2019;s going up! You can use it to buy a home, or to build a comfortable retirement, or some combination of the two.</p><p>Your co-workers are values aligned and work hard. They&#x2019;re talented and smart. <em>Man,</em> you might think to yourself, <em>I love working with this team.</em></p><p>Or, you might think, <em>man, I&#x2019;ve got to find another job.</em></p><p>Either way, you&#x2019;re proud of your product work. You&#x2019;re happy to take the salary, the free lunches, the espresso. And regardless of how you feel about it, the thing you do every day is powering an armed force that is kidnapping people on the street and shooting civilians, that shot a mother in the face, that is targeting people to disappear using a beautiful, modern map interface.</p><p>[<a href="https://www.404media.co/elite-the-palantir-app-ice-uses-to-find-neighborhoods-to-raid/?ref=werd.io">Link</a>]</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Zurich protocol]]></title><description><![CDATA[They came for the newsroom. It was ready.]]></description><link>https://werd.io/the-zurich-protocol/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">6966bde43b1a4f0001a2a102</guid><category><![CDATA[Future of News]]></category><category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category><category><![CDATA[Fiction]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Ben Werdmuller]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 21:58:10 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://werd.io/content/images/2026/01/ilia-bronskiy-ibLJ3GJ4UCE-unsplash.jpg" medium="image"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="https://werd.io/content/images/2026/01/ilia-bronskiy-ibLJ3GJ4UCE-unsplash.jpg" alt="The Zurich protocol"><p>There was little warning. Officers tumbled into the newsroom all at once, guns drawn, shouting into the common spaces. In the kitchen, someone was in the middle of drawing an espresso; overflowing coffee and steam began to drip onto the floor. Then, there was silence as the men took tactical positions in corridors and cubicles, opening closed doors and forcing the occupants of privacy rooms onto the main floor.</p><p>They lined up the editors first, zip tying their hands together and leading them into vans downstairs. Then they began to gather the rest of the journalists. Laptops were gathered from desks. The server room, such as it was in the wake of zero trust and enterprise cloud services, had its door kicked in, switches and rack servers ripped out of their frames. One IT support engineer objected and found a gun in his face, the safety off, its owner ready to make them into an example.</p><p>The people of color were led into one van; the white journalists into another. All were driven away.</p><p>The newsroom&#x2019;s infrastructure was decommissioned that same day. The website was taken offline. Email accounts and cloud storage were trespassed, their contents downloaded for rapid analysis by the authorities using some central AI system; maybe Palantir, maybe something else.</p><p>Ostensibly, there would be a trial. In reality, everyone knew, the point was the intimidation, the unpublishing, the detainment of the people responsible for criticism. There was no time for due process, the administration argued. Across newsrooms, universities, activist organizations, there were too many people. As the newsroom sat chained to their seats, being driven to some incarceration center somewhere, they wondered how long it would be before their families knew. How long before the remote journalists were picked up in similar ways, perhaps in front of their children, their homes trashed.</p><p>It didn&#x2019;t take long for the authorities to gain access to the devices they had taken. They forced journalists to open their phones and laptops at gunpoint; they&#x2019;d all been trained not to use biometric IDs, that nobody could force them to provide their passwords and PINs, but none of that matters when you have a weapon in your face. The hard drives, though encrypted, were unlocked and accessed, the data on them cloned.</p><p>They expected to find source information: the identities of people within the government who had leaked information about detainment sites and immigration enforcement activities.</p><p>They found nothing.</p><p>The files were all gone. The emails were all redacted. The devices were as good as empty.</p><p>And no matter what they did, no matter who they threatened, nobody could restore them. Not a single member of the newsroom gave up their private information.</p><p>They couldn&#x2019;t.</p><p>And for all they did to bring the website down, they couldn&#x2019;t stop the journalism. There was no way to take it offline. Within moments, other newsrooms seemed to have become aware of the raid, and were pointing to the articles. Interest had <em>increased</em>, not decreased.</p><p>The newsroom had planned for this.</p><p>For months, all its journalism had been mirrored elsewhere. It had always been available under a Creative Commons license for anyone to republish for free &#x2014; a model pioneered by <a href="https://propublica.org/?ref=werd.io">ProPublica</a> and then followed by <a href="https://19thnews.org/?ref=werd.io">The 19th</a>, <a href="https://grist.org/?ref=werd.io">Grist</a>, <a href="https://www.themarshallproject.org/?ref=werd.io">The Marshall Project</a> and more, which this newsroom had used for years. But in that model, another outlet needed to <em>choose</em> to republish an individual article.</p><p>In contrast, this new active mirroring left nothing to chance. An independent group in Switzerland intentionally syndicated all non-profit journalism onto its servers, located in Switzerland and subject to Swiss law, out of reach by the US administration. The pieces were also, after a time delay to account for post-publishing edits, syndicated to <a href="https://ipfs.tech/?ref=werd.io">IPFS</a>, the censorship-resistant peer-to-peer content delivery network. Together, these measures meant that it was impossible to fully redact American non-profit journalism in the public interest. The website was gone, but the articles lived on.</p><p>The group had another purpose. Beyond mirroring the newsroom&#x2019;s articles, it had access to its cloud storage, its email accounts, its databases, its infrastructure. It maintained independent offsite backups of the site and every custom application, all in Switzerland. And most importantly, it had a kill switch.</p><p>When the newsroom was raided, monitoring systems in Switzerland noticed an anomaly and automatically shut down the newsroom&#x2019;s systems within seconds. Email accounts and cloud storage were drained, information was locked down. Now, it was fully under their control: no-one in the US could compel them to restore it all.</p><p>Instead, two people in Switzerland, employed by a Swiss organization, needed to independently determine that it was safe to restore data. They sat in two separate clean, glass offices. To restore the data and systems, they would need to speak to the employees in the US, monitor the sensors and the security footage from the US offices, and make their own decision. If they did determine that it was safe, they would do so quickly, but it was their choice. They had full, independent authority to keep data from the newsroom until they could make that determination.</p><p>And in this case, they could not.</p><p>Because the newsroom used cloud services with zero trust, with data shared using the principle of least privilege, the seized laptops and servers contained very little usable information. Where they did contain local data, it was encrypted using keys that were kept in Switzerland and withheld with the rest of the cloud-hosted data. There was almost nothing that the authorities could use.</p><p>There were collaborators: people on the inside who provided information. Some did it because they truly believed in the administration&#x2019;s cause; some simply wished to ingratiate themselves to power. Even they could not provide more access to the data; they could not lead authorities to sources or compromise the investigations of other newsrooms. In the event, they were not spared. They, too, rode in the van.</p><p>Word spread quickly. Details of the intrusion were saved to an indelible ledger of newsroom raids, violence against journalists, and other threats that was peered with newsrooms worldwide. Notifications were sent to leaders at partner newsrooms within seconds.</p><p>Those partner newsrooms &#x2014; protected by similar remote kill switch with other, similar Swiss groups &#x2014; were able to access source information that had been set aside in advance so that stories in progress could continue to be reported. Some of those newsrooms were in the US; some were in other countries, so that if <em>every</em> newsroom in the US was compromised, others would still be able to pick up the stories elsewhere.</p><p>The people in the van did not disappear. Their names, identities, and job titles were all recorded and broadcast to other newsrooms. There would be pressure for their release. Some of them were dual nationals or foreign citizens, and their respective governments would add to the pressure. It wasn&#x2019;t going to be an easy road, but the truth would endure. Their sources remained safe. Their work could continue. And it would not be in vain.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Bari Weiss Is The Symptom]]></title><description><![CDATA["The truth is that prestige journalism is lousy with Bari Weisses, up and down the line. Ask any journalist trying to cover the genocide in Gaza or the social death of gender nonconformists."]]></description><link>https://werd.io/bari-weiss-is-the-symptom/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">696645683b1a4f0001a2a0f5</guid><category><![CDATA[Media]]></category><category><![CDATA[Notable links]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Ben Werdmuller]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 13:15:20 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>[<a href="https://defector.com/bari-weiss-is-the-symptom?ref=werd.io">Tommy Craggs at Defector</a>]</p><p>I wish this essay wasn&#x2019;t good and necessary, but it is.</p><blockquote>&#x201C;I worry some of my colleagues in the industry are getting the Bari Weiss phenomenon exactly wrong. She isn&apos;t a saboteur brought in to destroy one of the last remaining citadels of high journalism. She is one of high journalism&apos;s purest products, a perfect symptom of its old, unresolved contradictions. Her disingenuousness about motive is the industry&apos;s in miniature.&#x201D;</blockquote><p>The author is correct: Bari Weiss is not an exception to a glorious industry, but one of many. These are people who, although they would not put it that way themselves, seek to make journalism toothless; to turn it into an instrument of power rather than something that interrogates it. They&#x2019;re the people who see themselves, more than anything else, as an <em>institution</em>, rather than the people institutions worry about when they go to sleep at night. And they are everywhere.</p><p>I&#x2019;m not a journalist, but I signed up to support them. After my hard left turn from tech, I run technology for newsrooms, which includes the technologies that publish their work and keep them safe. And here I have to clarify: I didn&#x2019;t sign up to do this for all of them. I signed up to do it for the people who want to make the world safer, fairer, more equal. There&#x2019;s a reason why my two newsrooms have been <a href="https://19thnews.org/?ref=werd.io">The 19th</a> and <a href="https://propublica.org/?ref=werd.io">ProPublica</a>. The only journalism I care about aims to hold a bright light to power and established power structures, and truly hold them to account.</p><p>The Bari Weisses believe it&#x2019;s in the national interest to support whatever war the current administration has chosen to wage. They endorse official narratives in the name of covering &#x201C;both sides&#x201D;, even when they are obvious lies. They produce journalism about trans people without consulting trans people. They avoid the appearance of activism. They believe in upholding the status quo in the name of stability. And in doing so, they enable atrocities, big and small, foreign and domestic, to the point of collaboration.</p><p>[<a href="https://defector.com/bari-weiss-is-the-symptom?ref=werd.io">Link</a>]</p>]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>